{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Endpoint Creation Overview\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"endpoints [WCF], overview\"\nms.assetid: f4dce0fb-6f54-47e6-8054-86d7f574b91c\n---\n# Endpoint Creation Overview\nAll communication with a Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) service occurs through the *endpoints* of the service. Endpoints provide the clients access to the functionality that a WCF service offers. This section describes the structure of an endpoint and outlines how to define an endpoint in configuration and in code.  \n  \n## The Structure of an Endpoint  \n Each endpoint contains an address that indicates where to find the endpoint, a binding that specifies how a client can communicate with the endpoint, and a contract that identifies the methods available.  \n  \n-   **Address**. The address uniquely identifies the endpoint and tells potential consumers where the service is located. It is represented in the WCF object model by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.EndpointAddress> address, which contains a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) and address properties that include an identity, some Web Services Description Language (WSDL) elements, and a collection of optional headers. The optional headers provide additional detailed addressing information to identify or interact with the endpoint. For more information, see [Specifying an Endpoint Address](../../../docs/framework/wcf/specifying-an-endpoint-address.md).  \n  \n-   **Binding**. The binding specifies how to communicate with the endpoint. The binding specifies how the endpoint communicates with the world, including which transport protocol to use (for example, TCP or HTTP), which encoding to use for the messages (for example, text or binary), and which security requirements are necessary (for example, Secure Sockets Layer [SSL] or SOAP message security). For more information, see [Using Bindings to Configure Services and Clients](../../../docs/framework/wcf/using-bindings-to-configure-services-and-clients.md).  \n  \n-   **Service contract**. The service contract outlines what functionality the endpoint exposes to the client. A contract specifies the operations that a client can call, the form of the message and the type of input parameters or data required to call the operation, and the kind of processing or response message the client can expect. Three basic types of contracts correspond to basic message exchange patterns (MEPs): datagram (one-way), request/reply, and duplex (bidirectional). The service contract can also employ data and message contracts to require specific data types and message formats when being accessed. For more information about how to define a service contract, see [Designing Service Contracts](../../../docs/framework/wcf/designing-service-contracts.md). Note that a client may also be required to implement a service-defined contract, called a callback contract, to receive messages from the service in a duplex MEP. For more information, see [Duplex Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/duplex-services.md).  \n  \n The endpoint for a service can be specified either imperatively by using code or declaratively through configuration. If no endpoints are specified then the runtime provides default endpoints by adding one default endpoint for each base address for each service contract implemented by the service. Defining endpoints in code is usually not practical because the bindings and addresses for a deployed service are typically different from those used while the service is being developed. Generally, it is more practical to define service endpoints using configuration rather than code. Keeping the binding and addressing information out of the code allows them to change without having to recompile and redeploy the application.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  When adding a service endpoint that performs impersonation, you must either use one of the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost.AddServiceEndpoint%2A> methods or the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ContractDescription.GetContract%28System.Type%2CSystem.Type%29> method to properly load the contract into a new <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> object.  \n  \n## Defining Endpoints in Code  \n The following example illustrates how to specify an endpoint in code with the following:  \n  \n-   Define a contract for an `IEcho` type of service that accepts someone's name and echo with the response \"Hello \\<name>!\".  \n  \n-   Implement an `Echo` service of the type defined by the `IEcho` contract.  \n  \n-   Specify an endpoint address of `http://localhost:8000/Echo` for the service.  \n  \n-   Configure the `Echo` service using a <xref:System.ServiceModel.WSHttpBinding> binding.  \n  \n```csharp  \nNamespace Echo  \n{  \n   // Define the contract for the IEcho service   \n   [ServiceContract]  \n   public interface IEcho  \n   {  \n       [OperationContract]  \n       String Hello(string name)  \n   }  \n  \n   // Create an Echo service that implements IEcho contract  \n   class Echo : IEcho  \n   {  \n      public string Hello(string name)  \n      {  \n         return \"Hello\" + name + \"!\";  \n      }  \n      public static void Main ()  \n      {  \n          //Specify the base address for Echo service.  \n          Uri echoUri = new Uri(\"http://localhost:8000/\");  \n  \n          //Create a ServiceHost for the Echo service.  \n          ServiceHost serviceHost = new ServiceHost(typeof(Echo),echoUri);  \n  \n          // Use a predefined WSHttpBinding to configure the service.  \n          WSHttpBinding binding = new WSHttpBinding();  \n  \n          // Add the endpoint for this service to the service host.  \n          serviceHost.AddServiceEndpoint(  \n             typeof(IEcho),   \n             binding,   \n             echoUri  \n           );  \n  \n          // Open the service host to run it.  \n          serviceHost.Open();  \n     }  \n  }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n```vb  \n' Define the contract for the IEcho service  \n    <ServiceContract()> _  \n    Public Interface IEcho  \n        <OperationContract()> _  \n        Function Hello(ByVal name As String) As String  \n    End Interface  \n  \n' Create an Echo service that implements IEcho contract  \n    Public Class Echo   \n        Implements IEcho  \n        Public Function Hello(ByVal name As String) As String _  \n Implements ICalculator.Hello  \n            Dim result As String = \"Hello\" + name + \"!\"  \n            Return result  \n        End Function  \n  \n' Specify the base address for Echo service.  \nDim echoUri As Uri = New Uri(\"http://localhost:8000/\")  \n  \n' Create a ServiceHost for the Echo service.  \nDim svcHost As ServiceHost = New ServiceHost(GetType(HelloWorld), echoUri)  \n  \n' Use a predefined WSHttpBinding to configure the service.  \nDim binding As New WSHttpBinding()  \n  \n' Add the endpoint for this service to the service host.  \nserviceHost.AddServiceEndpoint(GetType(IEcho), binding, echoUri)  \n  \n' Open the service host to run it.  \nserviceHost.Open()  \n```  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  The service host is created with a base address and then the rest of the address, relative to the base address, is specified as part of an endpoint. This partitioning of the address allows multiple endpoints to be defined more conveniently for services at a host.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Properties of <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> in the service application must not be modified subsequent to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> method on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>. Some members, such as the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.Credentials%2A> property and the `AddServiceEndpoint` methods on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> and <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>, throw an exception if modified past that point. Others permit you to modify them, but the result is undefined.  \n>   \n>  Similarly, on the client the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceEndpoint> values must not be modified after the call to <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory>. The <xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory.Credentials%2A> property throws an exception if modified past that point. The other client description values can be modified without error, but the result is undefined.  \n>   \n>  Whether for the service or client, it is recommended that you modify the description prior to calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A>.  \n  \n## Defining Endpoints in Configuration  \n When creating an application, you often want to defer decisions to the administrator who is deploying the application. For example, there is often no way of knowing in advance what a service address (a URI) will be. Instead of hard-coding an address, it is preferable to allow an administrator to do so after creating a service. This flexibility is accomplished through configuration. For details, see [Configuring Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/configuring-services.md).  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Use the [ServiceModel Metadata Utility Tool (Svcutil.exe)](../../../docs/framework/wcf/servicemodel-metadata-utility-tool-svcutil-exe.md) with the `/config:`*filename*`[,`*filename*`]` switch to quickly create configuration files.  \n  \n## Using Default Endpoints  \n If no endpoints are specified in code or in configuration then the runtime provides default endpoints by adding one default endpoint for each base address for each service contract implemented by the service. The base address can be specified in code or in configuration, and the default endpoints are added when <xref:System.ServiceModel.ICommunicationObject.Open> is called on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>. This example is the same example from the previous section, but since no endpoints are specified, the default endpoints are added.  \n  \n```csharp  \nNamespace Echo  \n{  \n   // Define the contract for the IEcho service   \n   [ServiceContract]  \n   Interface IEcho  \n   {  \n       [OperationContract]  \n       String Hello(string name)  \n   }  \n  \n   // Create an Echo service that implements IEcho contract  \n   Class Echo : IEcho  \n   {  \n      Public string Hello(string name)  \n      {  \n         return \"Hello\" + name + \"!\";  \n      }  \n      static void Main ()  \n      {  \n          //Specify the base address for Echo service.  \n          Uri echoUri = new Uri(\"http://localhost:8000/\");  \n  \n          //Create a ServiceHost for the Echo service.  \n          ServiceHost serviceHost = new ServiceHost(typeof(Echo),echoUri);  \n  \n          // Open the service host to run it. Default endpoints  \n          // are added when the service is opened.  \n          serviceHost.Open();  \n     }  \n  }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n```vb  \n' Define the contract for the IEcho service  \n    <ServiceContract()> _  \n    Public Interface IEcho  \n        <OperationContract()> _  \n        Function Hello(ByVal name As String) As String  \n    End Interface  \n  \n' Create an Echo service that implements IEcho contract  \n    Public Class Echo   \n        Implements IEcho  \n        Public Function Hello(ByVal name As String) As String _  \n Implements ICalculator.Hello  \n            Dim result As String = \"Hello\" + name + \"!\"  \n            Return result  \n        End Function  \n  \n' Specify the base address for Echo service.  \nDim echoUri As Uri = New Uri(\"http://localhost:8000/\")  \n  \n' Open the service host to run it. Default endpoints  \n' are added when the service is opened.  \nserviceHost.Open()  \n```  \n  \n If endpoints are explicitly provided, the default endpoints can still be added by calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.AddDefaultEndpoints%2A> on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> before calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A>. For more information about default endpoints, see [Simplified Configuration](../../../docs/framework/wcf/simplified-configuration.md) and [Simplified Configuration for WCF Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/simplified-configuration-for-wcf-services.md).  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Implementing Service Contracts](../../../docs/framework/wcf/implementing-service-contracts.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,198],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Endpoint Creation Overview\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"endpoints [WCF], overview\"\nms.assetid: f4dce0fb-6f54-47e6-8054-86d7f574b91c","nodes":[{"content":"Endpoint Creation Overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,26],"content":"Endpoint Creation Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Endpoint Creation Overview","pos":[0,26]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[205,231],"content":"Endpoint Creation Overview","linkify":"Endpoint Creation Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Endpoint Creation Overview","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"All communication with a Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) service occurs through the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> of the service.","pos":[232,350],"source":"All communication with a Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) service occurs through the *endpoints* of the service."},{"content":"Endpoints provide the clients access to the functionality that a WCF service offers.","pos":[351,435]},{"content":"This section describes the structure of an endpoint and outlines how to define an endpoint in configuration and in code.","pos":[436,556]},{"pos":[565,593],"content":"The Structure of an Endpoint","linkify":"The Structure of an Endpoint","nodes":[{"content":"The Structure of an Endpoint","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"Each endpoint contains an address that indicates where to find the endpoint, a binding that specifies how a client can communicate with the endpoint, and a contract that identifies the methods available.","pos":[597,800]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Address<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[810,822],"source":"**Address**."},{"content":"The address uniquely identifies the endpoint and tells potential consumers where the service is located.","pos":[823,927]},{"content":"It is represented in the WCF object model by the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.EndpointAddress&gt;</ph> address, which contains a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) and address properties that include an identity, some Web Services Description Language (WSDL) elements, and a collection of optional headers.","pos":[928,1222],"source":" It is represented in the WCF object model by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.EndpointAddress> address, which contains a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) and address properties that include an identity, some Web Services Description Language (WSDL) elements, and a collection of optional headers."},{"content":"The optional headers provide additional detailed addressing information to identify or interact with the endpoint.","pos":[1223,1337]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Specifying an Endpoint Address<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/specifying-an-endpoint-address.md)</ept>.","pos":[1338,1460],"source":" For more information, see [Specifying an Endpoint Address](../../../docs/framework/wcf/specifying-an-endpoint-address.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Binding<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[1470,1482],"source":"**Binding**."},{"content":"The binding specifies how to communicate with the endpoint.","pos":[1483,1542]},{"content":"The binding specifies how the endpoint communicates with the world, including which transport protocol to use (for example, TCP or HTTP), which encoding to use for the messages (for example, text or binary), and which security requirements are necessary (for example, Secure Sockets Layer [SSL] or SOAP message security).","pos":[1543,1864]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Bindings to Configure Services and Clients<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/using-bindings-to-configure-services-and-clients.md)</ept>.","pos":[1865,2023],"source":" For more information, see [Using Bindings to Configure Services and Clients](../../../docs/framework/wcf/using-bindings-to-configure-services-and-clients.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Service contract<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2033,2054],"source":"**Service contract**."},{"content":"The service contract outlines what functionality the endpoint exposes to the client.","pos":[2055,2139]},{"content":"A contract specifies the operations that a client can call, the form of the message and the type of input parameters or data required to call the operation, and the kind of processing or response message the client can expect.","pos":[2140,2366]},{"content":"Three basic types of contracts correspond to basic message exchange patterns (MEPs): datagram (one-way), request/reply, and duplex (bidirectional).","pos":[2367,2514]},{"content":"The service contract can also employ data and message contracts to require specific data types and message formats when being accessed.","pos":[2515,2650]},{"content":"For more information about how to define a service contract, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Designing Service Contracts<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/designing-service-contracts.md)</ept>.","pos":[2651,2806],"source":" For more information about how to define a service contract, see [Designing Service Contracts](../../../docs/framework/wcf/designing-service-contracts.md)."},{"content":"Note that a client may also be required to implement a service-defined contract, called a callback contract, to receive messages from the service in a duplex MEP.","pos":[2807,2969]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Duplex Services<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/duplex-services.md)</ept>.","pos":[2970,3078],"source":" For more information, see [Duplex Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/duplex-services.md)."},{"content":"The endpoint for a service can be specified either imperatively by using code or declaratively through configuration.","pos":[3085,3202]},{"content":"If no endpoints are specified then the runtime provides default endpoints by adding one default endpoint for each base address for each service contract implemented by the service.","pos":[3203,3383]},{"content":"Defining endpoints in code is usually not practical because the bindings and addresses for a deployed service are typically different from those used while the service is being developed.","pos":[3384,3571]},{"content":"Generally, it is more practical to define service endpoints using configuration rather than code.","pos":[3572,3669]},{"content":"Keeping the binding and addressing information out of the code allows them to change without having to recompile and redeploy the application.","pos":[3670,3812]},{"pos":[3820,4213],"content":"[!NOTE]\n When adding a service endpoint that performs impersonation, you must either use one of the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost.AddServiceEndpoint%2A> methods or the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ContractDescription.GetContract%28System.Type%2CSystem.Type%29> method to properly load the contract into a new <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> object.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"When adding a service endpoint that performs impersonation, you must either use one of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost.AddServiceEndpoint%2A&gt;</ph> methods or the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ContractDescription.GetContract%28System.Type%2CSystem.Type%29&gt;</ph> method to properly load the contract into a new <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription&gt;</ph> object.","pos":[9,391],"source":"When adding a service endpoint that performs impersonation, you must either use one of the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost.AddServiceEndpoint%2A> methods or the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ContractDescription.GetContract%28System.Type%2CSystem.Type%29> method to properly load the contract into a new <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> object."}]},{"pos":[4222,4248],"content":"Defining Endpoints in Code","linkify":"Defining Endpoints in Code","nodes":[{"content":"Defining Endpoints in Code","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"The following example illustrates how to specify an endpoint in code with the following:","pos":[4252,4340]},{"pos":[4350,4471],"content":"Define a contract for an <ph id=\"ph1\">`IEcho`</ph> type of service that accepts someone's name and echo with the response \"Hello <ph id=\"ph2\">\\&lt;</ph>name&gt;!\".","source":"Define a contract for an `IEcho` type of service that accepts someone's name and echo with the response \"Hello \\<name>!\"."},{"pos":[4481,4553],"content":"Implement an <ph id=\"ph1\">`Echo`</ph> service of the type defined by the <ph id=\"ph2\">`IEcho`</ph> contract.","source":"Implement an `Echo` service of the type defined by the `IEcho` contract."},{"pos":[4563,4639],"content":"Specify an endpoint address of <ph id=\"ph1\">`http://localhost:8000/Echo`</ph> for the service.","source":"Specify an endpoint address of `http://localhost:8000/Echo` for the service."},{"pos":[4649,4735],"content":"Configure the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Echo`</ph> service using a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.WSHttpBinding&gt;</ph> binding.","source":"Configure the `Echo` service using a <xref:System.ServiceModel.WSHttpBinding> binding."},{"pos":[6984,7258],"content":"[!NOTE]\n The service host is created with a base address and then the rest of the address, relative to the base address, is specified as part of an endpoint. This partitioning of the address allows multiple endpoints to be defined more conveniently for services at a host.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The service host is created with a base address and then the rest of the address, relative to the base address, is specified as part of an endpoint. This partitioning of the address allows multiple endpoints to be defined more conveniently for services at a host.","pos":[9,272],"nodes":[{"content":"The service host is created with a base address and then the rest of the address, relative to the base address, is specified as part of an endpoint.","pos":[0,148]},{"content":"This partitioning of the address allows multiple endpoints to be defined more conveniently for services at a host.","pos":[149,263]}]}]},{"pos":[7266,7868],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Properties of <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> in the service application must not be modified subsequent to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> method on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>. Some members, such as the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.Credentials%2A> property and the `AddServiceEndpoint` methods on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> and <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>, throw an exception if modified past that point. Others permit you to modify them, but the result is undefined.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Properties of <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> in the service application must not be modified subsequent to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> method on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>. Some members, such as the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.Credentials%2A> property and the `AddServiceEndpoint` methods on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> and <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>, throw an exception if modified past that point. Others permit you to modify them, but the result is undefined.","pos":[9,600],"nodes":[{"content":"Properties of <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription&gt;</ph> in the service application must not be modified subsequent to the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A&gt;</ph> method on <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase&gt;</ph>.","pos":[0,260],"source":"Properties of <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceDescription> in the service application must not be modified subsequent to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> method on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>."},{"content":"Some members, such as the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.Credentials%2A&gt;</ph> property and the <ph id=\"ph2\">`AddServiceEndpoint`</ph> methods on <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost&gt;</ph>, throw an exception if modified past that point.","pos":[261,528],"source":" Some members, such as the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.Credentials%2A> property and the `AddServiceEndpoint` methods on <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> and <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>, throw an exception if modified past that point."},{"content":"Others permit you to modify them, but the result is undefined.","pos":[529,591]}]}]},{"content":"Similarly, on the client the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceEndpoint&gt;</ph> values must not be modified after the call to <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A&gt;</ph> on the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory&gt;</ph>.","pos":[7879,8127],"source":"Similarly, on the client the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.ServiceEndpoint> values must not be modified after the call to <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.OnOpening%2A> on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory>."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory.Credentials%2A&gt;</ph> property throws an exception if modified past that point.","pos":[8128,8246],"source":" The <xref:System.ServiceModel.ChannelFactory.Credentials%2A> property throws an exception if modified past that point."},{"content":"The other client description values can be modified without error, but the result is undefined.","pos":[8247,8342]},{"pos":[8353,8519],"content":"Whether for the service or client, it is recommended that you modify the description prior to calling <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A&gt;</ph>.","source":"Whether for the service or client, it is recommended that you modify the description prior to calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A>."},{"pos":[8528,8563],"content":"Defining Endpoints in Configuration","linkify":"Defining Endpoints in Configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Defining Endpoints in Configuration","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"When creating an application, you often want to defer decisions to the administrator who is deploying the application.","pos":[8567,8685]},{"content":"For example, there is often no way of knowing in advance what a service address (a URI) will be.","pos":[8686,8782]},{"content":"Instead of hard-coding an address, it is preferable to allow an administrator to do so after creating a service.","pos":[8783,8895]},{"content":"This flexibility is accomplished through configuration.","pos":[8896,8951]},{"content":"For details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configuring Services<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/configuring-services.md)</ept>.","pos":[8952,9045],"source":" For details, see [Configuring Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/configuring-services.md)."},{"pos":[9053,9294],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Use the [ServiceModel Metadata Utility Tool (Svcutil.exe)](../../../docs/framework/wcf/servicemodel-metadata-utility-tool-svcutil-exe.md) with the `/config:`*filename*`[,`*filename*`]` switch to quickly create configuration files.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ServiceModel Metadata Utility Tool (Svcutil.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/servicemodel-metadata-utility-tool-svcutil-exe.md)</ept> with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/config:`</ph><bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>filename<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph2\">`[,`</ph><bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>filename<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph3\">`]`</ph> switch to quickly create configuration files.","pos":[9,239],"source":"Use the [ServiceModel Metadata Utility Tool (Svcutil.exe)](../../../docs/framework/wcf/servicemodel-metadata-utility-tool-svcutil-exe.md) with the `/config:`*filename*`[,`*filename*`]` switch to quickly create configuration files."}]},{"pos":[9303,9326],"content":"Using Default Endpoints","linkify":"Using Default Endpoints","nodes":[{"content":"Using Default Endpoints","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"If no endpoints are specified in code or in configuration then the runtime provides default endpoints by adding one default endpoint for each base address for each service contract implemented by the service.","pos":[9330,9538]},{"content":"The base address can be specified in code or in configuration, and the default endpoints are added when <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ICommunicationObject.Open&gt;</ph> is called on the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost&gt;</ph>.","pos":[9539,9752],"source":" The base address can be specified in code or in configuration, and the default endpoints are added when <xref:System.ServiceModel.ICommunicationObject.Open> is called on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost>."},{"content":"This example is the same example from the previous section, but since no endpoints are specified, the default endpoints are added.","pos":[9753,9883]},{"content":"If endpoints are explicitly provided, the default endpoints can still be added by calling <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.AddDefaultEndpoints%2A&gt;</ph> on the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost&gt;</ph> before calling <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[11547,11828],"source":"If endpoints are explicitly provided, the default endpoints can still be added by calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase.AddDefaultEndpoints%2A> on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> before calling <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.CommunicationObject.Open%2A>."},{"content":"For more information about default endpoints, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Simplified Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/simplified-configuration.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Simplified Configuration for WCF Services<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/simplified-configuration-for-wcf-services.md)</ept>.","pos":[11829,12093],"source":" For more information about default endpoints, see [Simplified Configuration](../../../docs/framework/wcf/simplified-configuration.md) and [Simplified Configuration for WCF Services](../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/simplified-configuration-for-wcf-services.md)."},{"pos":[12102,12110],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[12114,12209],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Implementing Service Contracts<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/implementing-service-contracts.md)</ept>","source":"[Implementing Service Contracts](../../../docs/framework/wcf/implementing-service-contracts.md)"}]}