{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator) | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-clr\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"VB\"\n  - \"CSharp\"\n  - \"C++\"\n  - \"jsharp\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"Native Image Generator\"\n  - \"images [.NET Framework], native\"\n  - \"side-by-side execution, native images\"\n  - \"assemblies [.NET Framework], native image\"\n  - \"Ngen.exe\"\n  - \"native image generation\"\n  - \"native image cache\"\n  - \"publisher policy applied for native images\"\n  - \"invalid images\"\n  - \"BypassNGenAttribute\"\n  - \"System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute\"\nms.assetid: 44bf97aa-a9a4-4eba-9a0d-cfaa6fc53a66\ncaps.latest.revision: 57\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"\nmanager: \"wpickett\"\n---\n# Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)\nThe Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) is a tool that improves the performance of managed applications. Ngen.exe creates native images, which are files containing compiled processor-specific machine code, and installs them into the native image cache on the local computer. The runtime can use native images from the cache instead of using the just-in-time (JIT) compiler to compile the original assembly.  \n  \n Changes to Ngen.exe in the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)]:  \n  \n-   Ngen.exe now compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.  \n  \n-   Native images that are generated with Ngen.exe can no longer be loaded into applications that are running in partial trust.  \n  \n Changes to Ngen.exe in the .NET Framework version 2.0:  \n  \n-   Installing an assembly also installs its dependencies, simplifying the syntax of Ngen.exe.  \n  \n-   Native images can now be shared across application domains.  \n  \n-   A new action, `update`, re-creates images that have been invalidated.  \n  \n-   Actions can be deferred for execution by a service that uses idle time on the computer to generate and install images.  \n  \n-   Some causes of image invalidation have been eliminated.  \n  \n On Windows 8, see [Native Image Task](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb).  \n  \n For additional information on using Ngen.exe and the native image service, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Ngen.exe syntax for versions 1.0 and 1.1 of the .NET Framework can be found in [Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) Legacy Syntax](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/5a69fc7a-103f-4afc-8ab4-606adcb46324).  \n  \n This tool is automatically installed with Visual Studio. To run the tool, use the Developer Command Prompt (or the Visual Studio Command Prompt in Windows 7). For more information, see [Command Prompts](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md).  \n  \n At the command prompt, type the following:  \n  \n## Syntax  \n  \n```  \n  \nngen action [options]  \n  \n```  \n  \n```  \nngen /? | /help  \n```  \n  \n## Actions  \n The following table shows the syntax of each `action`. For descriptions of the individual parts of an `action`, see the [Arguments](#ArgumentTable), [Priority Levels](#PriorityTable), [Scenarios](#ScenarioTable), and [Config](#ConfigTable) tables. The [Options](#OptionTable) table describes the `options` and the help switches.  \n  \n|Action|Description|  \n|------------|-----------------|  \n|`install` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`] [`scenarios`] [`config`] [`/queue`[`:`{`1`&#124;`2`&#124;`3`}]]|Generate native images for an assembly and its dependencies and install the images in the native image cache.<br /><br /> If `/queue` is specified, the action is queued for the native image service. The default priority is 3. See the [Priority Levels](#PriorityTable) table.|  \n|`uninstall` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`] [`scenarios`] [`config`]|Delete the native images of an assembly and its dependencies from the native image cache.<br /><br /> To uninstall a single image and its dependencies, use the same command-line arguments that were used to install the image. **Note:**  Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], the action `uninstall` * is no longer supported.|  \n|`update` [`/queue`]|Update native images that have become invalid.<br /><br /> If `/queue` is specified, the updates are queued for the native image service. Updates are always scheduled at priority 3, so they run when the computer is idle.|  \n|`display` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`]|Display the state of the native images for an assembly and its dependencies.<br /><br /> If no argument is supplied, everything in the native image cache is displayed.|  \n|`executeQueuedItems` [`1``&#124;``2``&#124;``3`]<br /><br /> -or-<br /><br /> `eqi` [1&#124;2&#124;3]|Execute queued compilation jobs.<br /><br /> If a priority is specified, compilation jobs with greater or equal priority are executed. If no priority is specified, all queued compilation jobs are executed.|  \n|`queue` {`pause` &#124; `continue` &#124; `status`}|Pause the native image service, allow the paused service to continue, or query the status of the service.|  \n  \n<a name=\"ArgumentTable\"></a>   \n## Arguments  \n  \n|Argument|Description|  \n|--------------|-----------------|  \n|`assemblyName`|The full display name of the assembly. For example, `\"myAssembly, Version=2.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=0038abc9deabfle5\"`. **Note:**  You can supply a partial assembly name, such as `myAssembly`, for the `display` and `uninstall` actions. <br /><br /> Only one assembly can be specified per Ngen.exe command line.|  \n|`assemblyPath`|The explicit path of the assembly. You can specify a full or relative path.<br /><br /> If you specify a file name without a path, the assembly must be located in the current directory.<br /><br /> Only one assembly can be specified per Ngen.exe command line.|  \n  \n<a name=\"PriorityTable\"></a>   \n## Priority Levels  \n  \n|Priority|Description|  \n|--------------|-----------------|  \n|`1`|Native images are generated and installed immediately, without waiting for idle time.|  \n|`2`|Native images are generated and installed without waiting for idle time, but after all priority 1 actions (and their dependencies) have completed.|  \n|`3`|Native images are installed when the native image service detects that the computer is idle. See [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).|  \n  \n<a name=\"ScenarioTable\"></a>   \n## Scenarios  \n  \n|Scenario|Description|  \n|--------------|-----------------|  \n|`/Debug`|Generate native images that can be used under a debugger.|  \n|`/Profile`|Generate native images that can be used under a profiler.|  \n|`/NoDependencies`|Generate the minimum number of native images required by the specified scenario options.|  \n  \n<a name=\"ConfigTable\"></a>   \n## Config  \n  \n|Configuration|Description|  \n|-------------------|-----------------|  \n|`/ExeConfig:` `exePath`|Use the configuration of the specified executable assembly.<br /><br /> Ngen.exe needs to make the same decisions as the loader when binding to dependencies. When a shared component is loaded at run time, using the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A> method, the application's configuration file determines the dependencies that are loaded for the shared component — for example, the version of a dependency that is loaded. The `/ExeConfig` switch gives Ngen.exe guidance on which dependencies would be loaded at run time.|  \n|`/AppBase:` `directoryPath`|When locating dependencies, use the specified directory as the application base.|  \n  \n<a name=\"OptionTable\"></a>   \n## Options  \n  \n|Option|Description|  \n|------------|-----------------|  \n|`/nologo`|Suppress the Microsoft startup banner display.|  \n|`/silent`|Suppress the display of success messages.|  \n|`/verbose`|Display detailed information for debugging. **Note:**  Due to operating system limitations, this option does not display as much additional information on Windows 98 and Windows Millennium Edition.|  \n|`/help`, `/?`|Display command syntax and options for the current release.|  \n  \n## Remarks  \n To run Ngen.exe, you must have administrative privileges.  \n  \n> [!CAUTION]\n>  Do not run Ngen.exe on assemblies that are not fully trusted. Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], Ngen.exe compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.  \n  \n Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_short](../../../includes/net-v40-short-md.md)], the native images that are generated with Ngen.exe can no longer be loaded into applications that are running in partial trust. Instead, the just-in-time (JIT) compiler is invoked.  \n  \n Ngen.exe generates native images for the assembly specified by the `assemblyname` argument to the `install` action and all its dependencies. Dependencies are determined from references in the assembly manifest. The only scenario in which you need to install a dependency separately is when the application loads it using reflection, for example by calling the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method.  \n  \n> [!IMPORTANT]\n>  Do not use the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.LoadFrom%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method with native images. An image loaded with this method cannot be used by other assemblies in the execution context.  \n  \n Ngen.exe maintains a count on dependencies. For example, suppose `MyAssembly.exe` and `YourAssembly.exe` are both installed in the native image cache, and both have references to `OurDependency.dll`. If `MyAssembly.exe` is uninstalled, `OurDependency.dll` is not uninstalled. It is only removed when `YourAssembly.exe` is also uninstalled.  \n  \n If you are generating a native image for an assembly in the global assembly cache, specify its display name. See <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.FullName%2A?displayProperty=fullName>.  \n  \n The native images that Ngen.exe generates can be shared across application domains. This means you can use Ngen.exe in application scenarios that require assemblies to be shared across application domains. To specify domain neutrality:  \n  \n-   Apply the <xref:System.LoaderOptimizationAttribute> attribute to your application.  \n  \n-   Set the <xref:System.AppDomainSetup.LoaderOptimization%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property when you create setup information for a new application domain.  \n  \n Always use domain-neutral code when loading the same assembly into multiple application domains. If a native image is loaded into a nonshared application domain after having been loaded into a shared domain, it cannot be used.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Domain-neutral code cannot be unloaded, and performance may be slightly slower, particularly when accessing static members.  \n  \n In this Remarks section:  \n  \n-   [Generating images for different scenarios](#Scenarios)  \n  \n-   [Determining when to Use native images](#WhenToUse)  \n  \n    -   [Improved memory use](#Memory)  \n  \n    -   [Faster application startup](#Startup)  \n  \n    -   [Summary of usage considerations](#UsageSummary)  \n  \n-   [Importance of assembly base addresses](#BaseAddresses)  \n  \n-   [Hard binding](#HardBinding)  \n  \n    -   [Specifying a binding hint for a dependency](#DependencyHint)  \n  \n    -   [Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly](#AssemblyHint)  \n  \n-   [Deferred processing](#Deferred)  \n  \n-   [Native images and JIT compilation](#JITCompilation)  \n  \n    -   [Invalid images](#InvalidImages)  \n  \n-   [Troubleshooting](#Troubleshooting)  \n  \n    -   [Assembly Binding Log Viewer](#Fusion)  \n  \n    -   [The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant](#MDA)  \n  \n    -   [Opting out of native image generation](#OptOut)  \n  \n<a name=\"Scenarios\"></a>   \n## Generating images for     different scenarios  \n After you have generated a native image for an assembly, the runtime automatically attempts to locate and use this native   image each time it runs the assembly. Multiple images can be generated, depending on usage scenarios.  \n  \n For example, if you run an assembly in a debugging or profiling scenario, the runtime looks for a native image that was generated with the `/Debug` or `/Profile` options. If it is unable to find a matching native image, the runtime reverts to standard JIT compilation. The only way to debug native images is to create a native image with the `/Debug`option.  \n  \n The `uninstall` action also recognize scenarios, so you can uninstall all scenarios or only selected scenarios.  \n  \n<a name=\"WhenToUse\"></a>   \n## Determining when to Use native images  \n Native images can provide performance improvements in two areas: improved memory use and reduced startup time.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Performance of native images depends on a number of factors that make analysis difficult, such as code and data access patterns, how many calls are made across module boundaries, and how many dependencies have already been loaded by other applications. The only way to determine whether native images benefit your application is by careful performance measurements in your key deployment scenarios.  \n  \n<a name=\"Memory\"></a>   \n### Improved memory use  \n Native images can significantly improve memory use when code is shared between processes. Native images are Windows PE files, so a single copy of a .dll file can be shared by multiple processes; by contrast, native code produced by the JIT compiler is stored in private memory and cannot be shared.  \n  \n Applications that are run under terminal services can also benefit from shared code pages.  \n  \n In addition, not loading the JIT compiler saves a fixed amount of memory for each application instance.  \n  \n<a name=\"Startup\"></a>   \n### Faster application startup  \n Precompiling assemblies with Ngen.exe can improve the startup time for some applications. In general, gains can be made when applications share component assemblies because after the first application has been started the shared components are already loaded for subsequent applications. Cold startup, in which all the assemblies in an application must be loaded from the hard disk, does not benefit as much from native images because the hard disk access time predominates.  \n  \n Hard binding can affect startup time, because all images that are hard bound to the main application assembly must be loaded at the same time.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Before the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_long](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-long-md.md)], you should put shared, strong-named components in the global assembly cache, because the loader performs extra validation on strong-named assemblies that are not in the global assembly cache, effectively eliminating any improvement in startup time gained by using native images. Optimizations that were introduced in the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_short](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-short-md.md)] removed the extra validation.  \n  \n<a name=\"UsageSummary\"></a>   \n### Summary of usage considerations  \n The following general considerations and application considerations may assist you in deciding whether to undertake the effort of evaluating native images for your application:  \n  \n-   Native images load faster than MSIL because they eliminate the need for many startup activities, such as JIT compilation and type-safety verification.  \n  \n-   Native images require a smaller initial working set because there is no need for the JIT compiler.  \n  \n-   Native images enable code sharing between processes.  \n  \n-   Native images require more hard disk space than MSIL assemblies and may require considerable time to generate.  \n  \n-   Native images must be maintained.  \n  \n    -   Images need to be regenerated when the original assembly or one of its dependencies is serviced.  \n  \n    -   A single assembly may need multiple native images for use in different applications or different scenarios. For example, the configuration information in two applications might result in different binding decisions for the same dependent assembly.  \n  \n    -   Native images must be generated by an administrator; that is, from a Windows account in the Administrators group.  \n  \n In addition to these general considerations, the nature of your application must be considered when determining whether native images might provide a performance benefit:  \n  \n-   If your application runs in an environment that uses many shared components, native images allow the components to be shared by multiple processes.  \n  \n-   If your application uses multiple application domains, native images allow code pages to be shared across domains.  \n  \n    > [!NOTE]\n    >  In the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, native images cannot be shared across application domains. This is not the case in version 2.0 or later.  \n  \n-   If your application will be run under Terminal Server, native images allow sharing of code pages.  \n  \n-   Large applications generally benefit from compilation to native images. Small applications generally do not benefit.  \n  \n-   For long-running applications, run-time JIT compilation performs slightly better than native images. (Hard binding can mitigate this performance difference to some degree.)  \n  \n<a name=\"BaseAddresses\"></a>   \n## Importance of assembly base addresses  \n Because native images are Windows PE files, they are subject to the same rebasing issues as other executable files. The performance cost of relocation is even more pronounced if hard binding is employed.  \n  \n To set the base address for a native image, use the appropriate option of your compiler to set the base address for the assembly. Ngen.exe uses this base address for the native image.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Native images are larger than the managed assemblies from which they were created. Base addresses must be calculated to allow for these larger sizes.  \n  \n You can use a tool such as dumpbin.exe to view the preferred base address of a native image.  \n  \n<a name=\"HardBinding\"></a>   \n## Hard binding  \n Hard binding increases throughput and reduces working set size for native images. The disadvantage of hard binding is that all the images that are hard bound to an assembly must be loaded when the assembly is loaded. This can significantly increase startup time for a large application.  \n  \n Hard binding is appropriate for dependencies that are loaded in all your application's performance-critical scenarios. As with any aspect of native image use, careful performance measurements are the only way to determine whether hard binding improves your application's performance.  \n  \n The <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute> and <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> attributes allow you to provide hard binding hints to Ngen.exe.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  These attributes are hints to Ngen.exe, not commands. Using them does not guarantee hard binding. The meaning of these attributes may change in future releases.  \n  \n<a name=\"DependencyHint\"></a>   \n### Specifying a binding hint for a dependency  \n Apply the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute> to an assembly to indicate the likelihood that a specified dependency will be loaded. <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> indicates that hard binding is appropriate, <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint> indicates that the default for the dependency should be used, and <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint> indicates that hard binding is not appropriate.  \n  \n The following code shows the attributes for an assembly that has two dependencies. The first dependency (Assembly1) is an appropriate candidate for hard binding, and the second (Assembly2) is not.  \n  \n```vb  \nImports System.Runtime.CompilerServices  \n<Assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly1\", LoadHint.Always)>  \n<Assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly2\", LoadHint.Sometimes)>  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \nusing System.Runtime.CompilerServices;  \n[assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly1\", LoadHint.Always)]  \n[assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly2\", LoadHint.Sometimes)]  \n```  \n  \n```cpp#  \nusing namespace System::Runtime::CompilerServices;  \n[assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly1\", LoadHint.Always)];  \n[assembly:DependencyAttribute(\"Assembly2\", LoadHint.Sometimes)];  \n```  \n  \n The assembly name does not include the file name extension. Display names can be used.  \n  \n<a name=\"AssemblyHint\"></a>   \n### Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly  \n Default binding hints are only needed for assemblies that will be used immediately and frequently by any application that has a dependency on them. Apply the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> with <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> to such assemblies to specify that hard binding should be used.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  There is no reason to apply <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> to .dll assemblies that do not fall into this category, because applying the attribute with any value other than <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> has the same effect as not applying the attribute at all.  \n  \n Microsoft uses the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> to specify that hard binding is the default for a very small number of assemblies in the .NET Framework, such as mscorlib.dll.  \n  \n<a name=\"Deferred\"></a>   \n## Deferred processing  \n Generation of native images for a very large application can take considerable time. Similarly, changes to a shared component or changes to computer settings might require many native images to be updated. The `install` and `update` actions have a `/queue` option that queues the operation for deferred execution by the native image service. In addition, Ngen.exe has `queue` and `executeQueuedItems` actions that provide some control over the service. For more information, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).  \n  \n<a name=\"JITCompilation\"></a>   \n## Native images and JIT compilation  \n If Ngen.exe encounters any methods in an assembly that it cannot generate, it excludes them from the native image. When the runtime executes this assembly, it reverts to JIT compilation for the methods that were not included in the native image.  \n  \n In addition, native images are not used if the assembly has been upgraded, or if the image has been invalidated for any reason.  \n  \n<a name=\"InvalidImages\"></a>   \n### Invalid images  \n When you use Ngen.exe to create a native image of an assembly, the output depends upon the command-line options that you specify and certain settings on your computer. These settings include the following:  \n  \n-   The version of the .NET Framework.  \n  \n-   The version of the operating system, if the change is from the Windows 9x family to the Windows NT family.  \n  \n-   The exact identity of the assembly (recompilation changes identity).  \n  \n-   The exact identity of all assemblies that the assembly references (recompilation changes identity).  \n  \n-   Security factors.  \n  \n Ngen.exe records this information when it generates a native image. When you execute an assembly, the runtime looks for the native image generated with options and settings that match the computer's current environment. The runtime reverts to JIT compilation of an assembly if it cannot find a matching native image. The following changes to a computer's settings and environment cause native images to become invalid:  \n  \n-   The version of the .NET Framework.  \n  \n     If you apply an update to the .NET Framework, all native images that you have created using Ngen.exe become invalid. For this reason, all updates of the .NET Framework execute the `Ngen Update` command, to ensure that all native images are regenerated. The .NET Framework automatically creates new native images for the .NET Framework libraries that it installs.  \n  \n-   The version of the operating system, if the change is from the Windows 9x family to the Windows NT family.  \n  \n     For example, if the version of the operating system running on a computer changes from Windows 98 to Windows XP, all native images stored in the native image cache become invalid. However, if the operating system changes from Windows 2000 to Windows XP, the images are not invalidated.  \n  \n-   The exact identity of the assembly.  \n  \n     If you recompile an assembly, the assembly's corresponding native image becomes invalid.  \n  \n-   The exact identity of any assemblies the assembly references.  \n  \n     If you update a managed assembly, all native images that directly or indirectly depend on that assembly become invalid and need to be regenerated. This includes both ordinary references and hard-bound dependencies. Whenever a software update is applied, the installation program should execute an `Ngen Update` command to ensure that all dependent native images are regenerated.  \n  \n-   Security factors.  \n  \n     Changing machine security policy to restrict permissions previously granted to an assembly can cause a previously compiled native image for that assembly to become invalid.  \n  \n     For detailed information about how the common language runtime administers code access security and how to use permissions, see [Code Access Security](../../../docs/framework/misc/code-access-security.md).  \n  \n<a name=\"Troubleshooting\"></a>   \n## Troubleshooting  \n The following troubleshooting topics allow you to see which native images are being used and which cannot be used by your application, to determine when the JIT compiler starts to compile a method, and shows how to opt out of native image compilation of specified methods.  \n  \n<a name=\"Fusion\"></a>   \n### Assembly Binding Log Viewer  \n To confirm that native images are being used by your application, you can use the [Fuslogvw.exe (Assembly Binding Log Viewer)](../../../docs/framework/tools/fuslogvw-exe-assembly-binding-log-viewer.md). Select **Native Images** in the **Log Categories** box on the binding log viewer window. Fuslogvw.exe provides information about why a native image was rejected.  \n  \n<a name=\"MDA\"></a>   \n### The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant  \n You can use the [jitCompilationStart](../../../docs/framework/debug-trace-profile/jitcompilationstart-mda.md) managed debugging assistant (MDA) to determine when the JIT compiler starts to compile a function.  \n  \n<a name=\"OptOut\"></a>   \n### Opting out of native image generation  \n In some cases, NGen.exe may have difficulty generating a native image for a specific method, or you may prefer that the method be JIT compiled rather then compiled to a native image. In this case, you can use the `System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute` attribute to prevent NGen.exe from generating a native image for a particular method. The attribute must be applied individually to each method whose code you do not want to include in the native image. NGen.exe recognizes the attribute and does not generate code in the native image for the corresponding method.  \n  \n Note, however, that `BypassNGenAttribute` is not defined as a type in the .NET Framework Class library. In order to consume the attribute in your code, you must first define it as follows:  \n  \n [!code-csharp[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#1)]  \n  \n You can then apply the attribute on a per-method basis. The following example instructs the Native Image Generator that it should not generate a native image for the `ExampleClass.ToJITCompile` method.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#2)]  \n  \n## Examples  \n The following command generates a native image for `ClientApp.exe`, located in the current directory, and installs the image in the native image cache. If a configuration file exists for the assembly, Ngen.exe uses it. In addition, native images are generated for any .dll files that `ClientApp.exe` references.  \n  \n```  \nngen install ClientApp.exe  \n```  \n  \n An image installed with Ngen.exe is also called a root. A root can be an application or a shared component.  \n  \n The following command generates a native image for `MyAssembly.exe` with the specified path.  \n  \n```  \nngen install c:\\myfiles\\MyAssembly.exe  \n```  \n  \n When locating assemblies and their dependencies, Ngen.exe uses the same probing logic used by the common language runtime. By default, the directory that contains `ClientApp.exe` is used as the application base directory, and all assembly probing begins in this directory. You can override this behavior by using the `/AppBase` option.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  This is a change from Ngen.exe behavior in the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, where the application base is set to the current directory.  \n  \n An assembly can have a dependency without a reference, for example if it loads a .dll file by using the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method. You can create a native image for such a .dll file by using configuration information for the application assembly, with the `/ExeConfig` option. The following command generates a native image for `MyLib.dll,` using the configuration information from `MyApp.exe`.  \n  \n```  \nngen install c:\\myfiles\\MyLib.dll /ExeConfig:c:\\myapps\\MyApp.exe  \n```  \n  \n Assemblies installed in this way are not removed when the application is removed.  \n  \n To uninstall a dependency, use the same command-line options that were used to install it. The following command uninstalls the `MyLib.dll` from the previous example.  \n  \n```  \nngen uninstall c:\\myfiles\\MyLib.dll /ExeConfig:c:\\myapps\\MyApp.exe  \n```  \n  \n To create a native image for an assembly in the global assembly cache, use the display name of the assembly. For example:  \n  \n```  \nngen install \"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral,   \n  PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\"  \n```  \n  \n NGen.exe generates a separate set of images for each scenario you install. For example, the following commands install a complete set of native images for normal operation, another complete set for debugging, and a third for profiling:  \n  \n```  \nngen install MyApp.exe  \nngen install MyApp.exe /debug  \nngen install MyApp.exe /profile  \n```  \n  \n### Displaying the Native Image Cache  \n Once native images are installed in the cache, they can be displayed using Ngen.exe. The following command displays all native images in the native image cache.  \n  \n```  \nngen display  \n```  \n  \n The `display` action lists all the root assemblies first, followed by a list of all the native images on the computer.  \n  \n Use the simple name of an assembly to display information only for that assembly. The following command displays all native images in the native image cache that match the partial name `MyAssembly`, their dependencies, and all roots that have a dependency on `MyAssembly`:  \n  \n```  \nngen display MyAssembly  \n```  \n  \n Knowing what roots depend on a shared component assembly is useful in gauging the impact of an `update` action after the shared component is upgraded.  \n  \n If you specify an assembly's file extension, you must either specify the path or execute Ngen.exe from the directory containing the assembly:  \n  \n```  \nngen display c:\\myApps\\MyAssembly.exe  \n```  \n  \n The following command displays all native images in the native image cache with the name `MyAssembly` and the version 1.0.0.0.  \n  \n```  \nngen display \"myAssembly, version=1.0.0.0\"  \n```  \n  \n### Updating Images  \n Images are typically updated after a shared component has been upgraded. To update all native images that have changed, or whose dependencies have changed, use the `update` action with no arguments.  \n  \n```  \nngen update  \n```  \n  \n Updating all images can be a lengthy process. You can queue the updates for execution by the native image service by using the `/queue` option. For more information on the `/queue` option and installation priorities, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).  \n  \n```  \nngen update /queue  \n```  \n  \n### Uninstalling Images  \n Ngen.exe maintains a list of dependencies, so that shared components are removed only when all assemblies that depend on them have been removed. In addition, a shared component is not removed if it has been installed as a root.  \n  \n The following command uninstalls all scenarios for the root `ClientApp.exe`:  \n  \n```  \nngen uninstall ClientApp  \n```  \n  \n The `uninstall` action can be used to remove specific scenarios. The following command uninstalls all debug scenarios for `ClientApp.exe`:  \n  \n```  \nngen uninstall ClientApp /debug  \n```  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Uninstalling `/debug` scenarios does not uninstall a scenario that includes both `/profile` and `/debug.`  \n  \n The following command uninstalls all scenarios for a specific version of `ClientApp.exe`:  \n  \n```  \nngen uninstall \"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0\"  \n```  \n  \n The following commands uninstall all scenarios for `\"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\",` or just the debug scenario for that assembly:  \n  \n```  \nngen uninstall \"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral,   \n  PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\"  \nngen uninstall \"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral,   \n  PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\" /debug  \n```  \n  \n As with the `install` action, supplying an extension requires either executing Ngen.exe from the directory containing the assembly or specifying a full path.  \n  \n For examples relating to the native image service, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).  \n  \n## Native Image Task  \n The native image task is a Windows task that generates and maintains native images. The native image task generates and reclaims native images automatically for supported scenarios. (See [Creating Native Images](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/2bc8b678-dd8d-4742-ad82-319e9bf52418).) It also enables installers to use [Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)](../../../docs/framework/tools/ngen-exe-native-image-generator.md) to create and update native images at a deferred time.  \n  \n The native image task is registered once for each CPU architecture supported on a computer, to allow compilation for applications that target each architecture:  \n  \n|Task name|32-bit computer|64-bit computer|  \n|---------------|----------------------|----------------------|  \n|NET Framework NGEN v4.0.30319|Yes|Yes|  \n|NET Framework NGEN v4.0.30319 64|No|Yes|  \n  \n The native image task is is available in the .NET Framework 4.5 and later versions, when running on Windows 8 or later. On earlier versions of Windows, the .NET Framework uses the [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309).  \n  \n### Task Lifetime  \n In general, the Windows Task Scheduler starts the native image task every night when the computer is idle. The task checks for any deferred work that is queued by application installers, any deferred native image update requests, and any automatic image creation. The task completes outstanding work items and then shuts down. If the computer stops being idle while the task is running, the task stops.  \n  \n You can also start the native image task manually through the Task Scheduler UI or through manual calls to NGen.exe. If the task is started through either of these methods, it will continue running when the computer is no longer idle. Images created manually by using NGen.exe are prioritized to enable predictable behavior for application installers.  \n  \n## Native Image Service  \n The native image service is a Windows service that generates and maintains native images. The native image service allows the developer to defer the installation and update of native images to periods when the computer is idle.  \n  \n Normally, the native image service is initiated by the installation program (installer) for an application or update. For priority 3 actions, the service executes during idle time on the computer. The service saves its state and is capable of continuing through multiple reboots if necessary. Multiple image compilations can be queued.  \n  \n The service also interacts with the manual Ngen.exe command. Manual commands take precedence over background activity.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  On Windows Vista, the name displayed for the native image service is \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X86\" or \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X64\". On all earlier versions of Microsoft Windows, the name is \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X86\" or \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X64\".  \n  \n### Launching Deferred Operations  \n Before beginning an installation or upgrade, pausing the service is recommended. This ensures that the service does not execute while the installer is copying files or putting assemblies in the global assembly cache. The following Ngen.exe command line pauses the service:  \n  \n```  \nngen queue pause  \n```  \n  \n When all deferred operations have been queued, the following command allows the service to resume:  \n  \n```  \nngen queue continue  \n```  \n  \n To defer native image generation when installing a new application or when updating a shared component, use the `/queue` option with the `install` or `update` actions. The following Ngen.exe command lines install a native image for a shared component and perform an update of all roots that may have been affected:  \n  \n```  \nngen install MyComponent /queue  \nngen update /queue  \n```  \n  \n The `update` action regenerates all native images that have been invalidated, not just those that use `MyComponent`.  \n  \n If your application consists of many roots, you can control the priority of the deferred actions. The following commands queue the installation of three roots. `Assembly1` is installed first, without waiting for idle time. `Assembly2` is also installed without waiting for idle time, but after all priority 1 actions have completed. `Assembly3` is installed when the service detects that the computer is idle.  \n  \n```  \nngen install Assembly1 /queue:1  \nngen install Assembly2 /queue:2  \nngen install Assembly3 /queue:3  \n```  \n  \n You can force queued actions to occur synchronously by using the `executeQueuedItems` action. If you supply the optional priority, this action affects only the queued actions that have equal or lower priority. The default priority is 3, so the following Ngen.exe command processes all queued actions immediately, and does not return until they are finished:  \n  \n```  \nngen executeQueuedItems  \n```  \n  \n Synchronous commands are executed by Ngen.exe and do not use the native image service. You can execute actions using Ngen.exe while the native image service is running.  \n  \n### Service Shutdown  \n After being initiated by the execution of an Ngen.exe command that includes the `/queue` option, the service runs in the background until all actions have been completed. The service saves its state so that it can continue through multiple reboots if necessary. When the service detects that there are no more actions queued, it resets its status so that it will not restart the next time the computer is booted, and then it shuts itself down.  \n  \n### Service Interaction with Clients  \n In the .NET Framework version 2.0, the only interaction with the native image service is through the command-line tool Ngen.exe. Use the command-line tool in installation scripts to queue actions for the native image service and to interact with the service.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)   \n [Native Image Task](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb)   \n [Tools](../../../docs/framework/tools/index.md)   \n [Managed Execution Process](../../../docs/standard/managed-execution-process.md)   \n [How the Runtime Locates Assemblies](../../../docs/framework/deployment/how-the-runtime-locates-assemblies.md)   \n [Command Prompts](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md)","nodes":[{"pos":[4,804],"nodes":[{"content":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator) | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"pos":[0,50],"content":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator) | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"content":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator) | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,50]}]}],"pos":[6,59],"yaml":true}],"content":"title: \"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator) | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-clr\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"VB\"\n  - \"CSharp\"\n  - \"C++\"\n  - \"jsharp\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"Native Image Generator\"\n  - \"images [.NET Framework], native\"\n  - \"side-by-side execution, native images\"\n  - \"assemblies [.NET Framework], native image\"\n  - \"Ngen.exe\"\n  - \"native image generation\"\n  - \"native image cache\"\n  - \"publisher policy applied for native images\"\n  - \"invalid images\"\n  - \"BypassNGenAttribute\"\n  - \"System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute\"\nms.assetid: 44bf97aa-a9a4-4eba-9a0d-cfaa6fc53a66\ncaps.latest.revision: 57\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"\nmanager: \"wpickett\"","yamlblock":true},{"pos":[811,844],"content":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)","linkify":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)","nodes":[{"content":"Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"The Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) is a tool that improves the performance of managed applications.","pos":[845,947]},{"content":"Ngen.exe creates native images, which are files containing compiled processor-specific machine code, and installs them into the native image cache on the local computer.","pos":[948,1117]},{"content":"The runtime can use native images from the cache instead of using the just-in-time (JIT) compiler to compile the original assembly.","pos":[1118,1249]},{"pos":[1256,1346],"content":"Changes to Ngen.exe in the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)]</ph>:","source":"Changes to Ngen.exe in the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)]:"},{"content":"Ngen.exe now compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.","pos":[1356,1467]},{"content":"Native images that are generated with Ngen.exe can no longer be loaded into applications that are running in partial trust.","pos":[1477,1600]},{"content":"Changes to Ngen.exe in the .NET Framework version 2.0:","pos":[1607,1661]},{"content":"Installing an assembly also installs its dependencies, simplifying the syntax of Ngen.exe.","pos":[1671,1761]},{"content":"Native images can now be shared across application domains.","pos":[1771,1830]},{"pos":[1840,1909],"content":"A new action, <ph id=\"ph1\">`update`</ph>, re-creates images that have been invalidated.","source":"A new action, `update`, re-creates images that have been invalidated."},{"content":"Actions can be deferred for execution by a service that uses idle time on the computer to generate and install images.","pos":[1919,2037]},{"content":"Some causes of image invalidation have been eliminated.","pos":[2047,2102]},{"pos":[2109,2217],"content":"On Windows 8, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Task<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb)</ept>.","source":"On Windows 8, see [Native Image Task](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb)."},{"pos":[2224,2396],"content":"For additional information on using Ngen.exe and the native image service, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","source":"For additional information on using Ngen.exe and the native image service, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[2404,2614],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Ngen.exe syntax for versions 1.0 and 1.1 of the .NET Framework can be found in [Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) Legacy Syntax](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/5a69fc7a-103f-4afc-8ab4-606adcb46324).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Ngen.exe syntax for versions 1.0 and 1.1 of the .NET Framework can be found in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) Legacy Syntax<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/5a69fc7a-103f-4afc-8ab4-606adcb46324)</ept>.","pos":[9,208],"source":"Ngen.exe syntax for versions 1.0 and 1.1 of the .NET Framework can be found in [Native Image Generator (Ngen.exe) Legacy Syntax](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/5a69fc7a-103f-4afc-8ab4-606adcb46324)."}]},{"content":"This tool is automatically installed with Visual Studio.","pos":[2621,2677]},{"content":"To run the tool, use the Developer Command Prompt (or the Visual Studio Command Prompt in Windows 7).","pos":[2678,2779]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Command Prompts<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md)</ept>.","pos":[2780,2890],"source":" For more information, see [Command Prompts](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md)."},{"content":"At the command prompt, type the following:","pos":[2897,2939]},{"pos":[2948,2954],"content":"Syntax","linkify":"Syntax","nodes":[{"content":"Syntax","pos":[0,6]}]},{"pos":[3041,3048],"content":"Actions","linkify":"Actions","nodes":[{"content":"Actions","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"The following table shows the syntax of each <ph id=\"ph1\">`action`</ph>.","pos":[3052,3106],"source":"The following table shows the syntax of each `action`."},{"content":"For descriptions of the individual parts of an <ph id=\"ph1\">`action`</ph>, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Arguments<ept id=\"p1\">](#ArgumentTable)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Priority Levels<ept id=\"p2\">](#PriorityTable)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Scenarios<ept id=\"p3\">](#ScenarioTable)</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Config<ept id=\"p4\">](#ConfigTable)</ept> tables.","pos":[3107,3299],"source":" For descriptions of the individual parts of an `action`, see the [Arguments](#ArgumentTable), [Priority Levels](#PriorityTable), [Scenarios](#ScenarioTable), and [Config](#ConfigTable) tables."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Options<ept id=\"p1\">](#OptionTable)</ept> table describes the <ph id=\"ph1\">`options`</ph> and the help switches.","pos":[3300,3380],"source":" The [Options](#OptionTable) table describes the `options` and the help switches."},{"content":"Action","pos":[3387,3393]},{"content":"Description","pos":[3394,3405]},{"pos":[3445,3557],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`install`</ph> [<ph id=\"ph2\">`assemblyName`</ph> &amp;#124; <ph id=\"ph3\">`assemblyPath`</ph>] [<ph id=\"ph4\">`scenarios`</ph>] [<ph id=\"ph5\">`config`</ph>] [<ph id=\"ph6\">`/queue`</ph>[<ph id=\"ph7\">`:`</ph>{<ph id=\"ph8\">`1`</ph>&amp;#124;<ph id=\"ph9\">`2`</ph>&amp;#124;<ph id=\"ph10\">`3`</ph>}]]","source":"`install` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`] [`scenarios`] [`config`] [`/queue`[`:`{`1`&#124;`2`&#124;`3`}]]"},{"content":"Generate native images for an assembly and its dependencies and install the images in the native image cache.","pos":[3558,3667]},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> is specified, the action is queued for the native image service.","pos":[3680,3756],"source":"If `/queue` is specified, the action is queued for the native image service."},{"content":"The default priority is 3.","pos":[3757,3783]},{"content":"See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Priority Levels<ept id=\"p1\">](#PriorityTable)</ept> table.","pos":[3784,3832],"source":" See the [Priority Levels](#PriorityTable) table."},{"pos":[3837,3912],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`uninstall`</ph> [<ph id=\"ph2\">`assemblyName`</ph> &amp;#124; <ph id=\"ph3\">`assemblyPath`</ph>] [<ph id=\"ph4\">`scenarios`</ph>] [<ph id=\"ph5\">`config`</ph>]","source":"`uninstall` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`] [`scenarios`] [`config`]"},{"content":"Delete the native images of an assembly and its dependencies from the native image cache.","pos":[3913,4002]},{"content":"To uninstall a single image and its dependencies, use the same command-line arguments that were used to install the image.","pos":[4015,4137]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Starting with the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)]</ph>, the action <ph id=\"ph2\">`uninstall`</ph> * is no longer supported.","pos":[4138,4279],"source":"**Note:**  Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], the action `uninstall` * is no longer supported."},{"pos":[4284,4303],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`update`</ph> [<ph id=\"ph2\">`/queue`</ph>]","source":"`update` [`/queue`]"},{"content":"Update native images that have become invalid.","pos":[4304,4350]},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> is specified, the updates are queued for the native image service.","pos":[4363,4441],"source":"If `/queue` is specified, the updates are queued for the native image service."},{"content":"Updates are always scheduled at priority 3, so they run when the computer is idle.","pos":[4442,4524]},{"pos":[4529,4577],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`display`</ph> [<ph id=\"ph2\">`assemblyName`</ph> &amp;#124; <ph id=\"ph3\">`assemblyPath`</ph>]","source":"`display` [`assemblyName` &#124; `assemblyPath`]"},{"content":"Display the state of the native images for an assembly and its dependencies.","pos":[4578,4654]},{"content":"If no argument is supplied, everything in the native image cache is displayed.","pos":[4667,4745]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`executeQueuedItems`</ph> [<ph id=\"ph2\">`1``&amp;#124;``2``&amp;#124;``3`</ph>]","pos":[4750,4798],"source":"`executeQueuedItems` [`1``&#124;``2``&#124;``3`]"},{"content":"-or-","pos":[4811,4815]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`eqi`</ph> [1&amp;#124;2&amp;#124;3]","pos":[4828,4851],"source":"`eqi` [1&#124;2&#124;3]"},{"content":"Execute queued compilation jobs.","pos":[4852,4884]},{"content":"If a priority is specified, compilation jobs with greater or equal priority are executed.","pos":[4897,4986]},{"content":"If no priority is specified, all queued compilation jobs are executed.","pos":[4987,5057]},{"pos":[5062,5113],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`queue`</ph> {<ph id=\"ph2\">`pause`</ph> &amp;#124; <ph id=\"ph3\">`continue`</ph> &amp;#124; <ph id=\"ph4\">`status`</ph>}","source":"`queue` {`pause` &#124; `continue` &#124; `status`}"},{"content":"Pause the native image service, allow the paused service to continue, or query the status of the service.","pos":[5114,5219]},{"pos":[5261,5270],"content":"Arguments","linkify":"Arguments","nodes":[{"content":"Arguments","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"Argument","pos":[5277,5285]},{"content":"Description","pos":[5286,5297]},{"content":"The full display name of the assembly.","pos":[5354,5392]},{"content":"For example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`\"myAssembly, Version=2.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=0038abc9deabfle5\"`</ph>.","pos":[5393,5488],"source":" For example, `\"myAssembly, Version=2.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=0038abc9deabfle5\"`."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  You can supply a partial assembly name, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`myAssembly`</ph>, for the <ph id=\"ph2\">`display`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">`uninstall`</ph> actions.","pos":[5489,5604],"source":"**Note:**  You can supply a partial assembly name, such as `myAssembly`, for the `display` and `uninstall` actions."},{"content":"Only one assembly can be specified per Ngen.exe command line.","pos":[5618,5679]},{"content":"The explicit path of the assembly.","pos":[5699,5733]},{"content":"You can specify a full or relative path.","pos":[5734,5774]},{"content":"If you specify a file name without a path, the assembly must be located in the current directory.","pos":[5787,5884]},{"content":"Only one assembly can be specified per Ngen.exe command line.","pos":[5897,5958]},{"pos":[6000,6015],"content":"Priority Levels","linkify":"Priority Levels","nodes":[{"content":"Priority Levels","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"Priority","pos":[6022,6030]},{"content":"Description","pos":[6031,6042]},{"content":"Native images are generated and installed immediately, without waiting for idle time.","pos":[6088,6173]},{"content":"Native images are generated and installed without waiting for idle time, but after all priority 1 actions (and their dependencies) have completed.","pos":[6182,6328]},{"content":"Native images are installed when the native image service detects that the computer is idle.","pos":[6337,6429]},{"content":"See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","pos":[6430,6527],"source":" See [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[6569,6578],"content":"Scenarios","linkify":"Scenarios","nodes":[{"content":"Scenarios","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"Scenario","pos":[6585,6593]},{"content":"Description","pos":[6594,6605]},{"content":"Generate native images that can be used under a debugger.","pos":[6656,6713]},{"content":"Generate native images that can be used under a profiler.","pos":[6729,6786]},{"content":"Generate the minimum number of native images required by the specified scenario options.","pos":[6809,6897]},{"pos":[6937,6943],"content":"Config","linkify":"Config","nodes":[{"content":"Config","pos":[0,6]}]},{"content":"Configuration","pos":[6950,6963]},{"content":"Description","pos":[6964,6975]},{"pos":[7022,7045],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`/ExeConfig:`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`exePath`</ph>","source":"`/ExeConfig:` `exePath`"},{"content":"Use the configuration of the specified executable assembly.","pos":[7046,7105]},{"content":"Ngen.exe needs to make the same decisions as the loader when binding to dependencies.","pos":[7118,7203]},{"content":"When a shared component is loaded at run time, using the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A&gt;</ph> method, the application's configuration file determines the dependencies that are loaded for the shared component — for example, the version of a dependency that is loaded.","pos":[7204,7475],"source":" When a shared component is loaded at run time, using the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A> method, the application's configuration file determines the dependencies that are loaded for the shared component — for example, the version of a dependency that is loaded."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`/ExeConfig`</ph> switch gives Ngen.exe guidance on which dependencies would be loaded at run time.","pos":[7476,7574],"source":" The `/ExeConfig` switch gives Ngen.exe guidance on which dependencies would be loaded at run time."},{"pos":[7579,7606],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`/AppBase:`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`directoryPath`</ph>","source":"`/AppBase:` `directoryPath`"},{"content":"When locating dependencies, use the specified directory as the application base.","pos":[7607,7687]},{"pos":[7727,7734],"content":"Options","linkify":"Options","nodes":[{"content":"Options","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"Option","pos":[7741,7747]},{"content":"Description","pos":[7748,7759]},{"content":"Suppress the Microsoft startup banner display.","pos":[7809,7855]},{"content":"Suppress the display of success messages.","pos":[7870,7911]},{"content":"Display detailed information for debugging.","pos":[7927,7970]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  Due to operating system limitations, this option does not display as much additional information on Windows 98 and Windows Millennium Edition.","pos":[7971,8124],"source":"**Note:**  Due to operating system limitations, this option does not display as much additional information on Windows 98 and Windows Millennium Edition."},{"pos":[8129,8142],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`/help`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`/?`</ph>","source":"`/help`, `/?`"},{"content":"Display command syntax and options for the current release.","pos":[8143,8202]},{"pos":[8212,8219],"content":"Remarks","linkify":"Remarks","nodes":[{"content":"Remarks","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"To run Ngen.exe, you must have administrative privileges.","pos":[8223,8280]},{"pos":[8288,8553],"content":"[!CAUTION]\n Do not run Ngen.exe on assemblies that are not fully trusted. Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], Ngen.exe compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not run Ngen.exe on assemblies that are not fully trusted. Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], Ngen.exe compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.","pos":[12,263],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not run Ngen.exe on assemblies that are not fully trusted.","pos":[0,61]},{"content":"Starting with the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)]</ph>, Ngen.exe compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated.","pos":[62,251],"source":" Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_long](../../../includes/net-v40-long-md.md)], Ngen.exe compiles assemblies with full trust, and code access security (CAS) policy is no longer evaluated."}]}]},{"content":"Starting with the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v40_short](../../../includes/net-v40-short-md.md)]</ph>, the native images that are generated with Ngen.exe can no longer be loaded into applications that are running in partial trust.","pos":[8560,8771],"source":"Starting with the [!INCLUDE[net_v40_short](../../../includes/net-v40-short-md.md)], the native images that are generated with Ngen.exe can no longer be loaded into applications that are running in partial trust."},{"content":"Instead, the just-in-time (JIT) compiler is invoked.","pos":[8772,8824]},{"content":"Ngen.exe generates native images for the assembly specified by the <ph id=\"ph1\">`assemblyname`</ph> argument to the <ph id=\"ph2\">`install`</ph> action and all its dependencies.","pos":[8831,8971],"source":"Ngen.exe generates native images for the assembly specified by the `assemblyname` argument to the `install` action and all its dependencies."},{"content":"Dependencies are determined from references in the assembly manifest.","pos":[8972,9041]},{"content":"The only scenario in which you need to install a dependency separately is when the application loads it using reflection, for example by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[9042,9265],"source":" The only scenario in which you need to install a dependency separately is when the application loads it using reflection, for example by calling the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method."},{"pos":[9273,9495],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\n Do not use the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.LoadFrom%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method with native images. An image loaded with this method cannot be used by other assemblies in the execution context.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not use the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.LoadFrom%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method with native images. An image loaded with this method cannot be used by other assemblies in the execution context.","pos":[14,220],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.LoadFrom%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method with native images.","pos":[0,112],"source":"Do not use the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.LoadFrom%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method with native images."},{"content":"An image loaded with this method cannot be used by other assemblies in the execution context.","pos":[113,206]}]}]},{"content":"Ngen.exe maintains a count on dependencies.","pos":[9502,9545]},{"content":"For example, suppose <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyAssembly.exe`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`YourAssembly.exe`</ph> are both installed in the native image cache, and both have references to <ph id=\"ph3\">`OurDependency.dll`</ph>.","pos":[9546,9701],"source":" For example, suppose `MyAssembly.exe` and `YourAssembly.exe` are both installed in the native image cache, and both have references to `OurDependency.dll`."},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyAssembly.exe`</ph> is uninstalled, <ph id=\"ph2\">`OurDependency.dll`</ph> is not uninstalled.","pos":[9702,9777],"source":" If `MyAssembly.exe` is uninstalled, `OurDependency.dll` is not uninstalled."},{"content":"It is only removed when <ph id=\"ph1\">`YourAssembly.exe`</ph> is also uninstalled.","pos":[9778,9841],"source":" It is only removed when `YourAssembly.exe` is also uninstalled."},{"content":"If you are generating a native image for an assembly in the global assembly cache, specify its display name.","pos":[9848,9956]},{"content":"See <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.FullName%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>.","pos":[9957,10032],"source":" See <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.FullName%2A?displayProperty=fullName>."},{"content":"The native images that Ngen.exe generates can be shared across application domains.","pos":[10039,10122]},{"content":"This means you can use Ngen.exe in application scenarios that require assemblies to be shared across application domains.","pos":[10123,10244]},{"content":"To specify domain neutrality:","pos":[10245,10274]},{"content":"Apply the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.LoaderOptimizationAttribute&gt;</ph> attribute to your application.","pos":[10284,10366],"source":"Apply the <xref:System.LoaderOptimizationAttribute> attribute to your application."},{"content":"Set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.AppDomainSetup.LoaderOptimization%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property when you create setup information for a new application domain.","pos":[10376,10532],"source":"Set the <xref:System.AppDomainSetup.LoaderOptimization%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property when you create setup information for a new application domain."},{"content":"Always use domain-neutral code when loading the same assembly into multiple application domains.","pos":[10539,10635]},{"content":"If a native image is loaded into a nonshared application domain after having been loaded into a shared domain, it cannot be used.","pos":[10636,10765]},{"pos":[10773,10907],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Domain-neutral code cannot be unloaded, and performance may be slightly slower, particularly when accessing static members.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Domain-neutral code cannot be unloaded, and performance may be slightly slower, particularly when accessing static members.","pos":[9,132]}]},{"content":"In this Remarks section:","pos":[10914,10938]},{"pos":[10948,11003],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generating images for different scenarios<ept id=\"p1\">](#Scenarios)</ept>","source":"[Generating images for different scenarios](#Scenarios)"},{"pos":[11013,11064],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Determining when to Use native images<ept id=\"p1\">](#WhenToUse)</ept>","source":"[Determining when to Use native images](#WhenToUse)"},{"pos":[11078,11108],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Improved memory use<ept id=\"p1\">](#Memory)</ept>","source":"[Improved memory use](#Memory)"},{"pos":[11122,11160],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Faster application startup<ept id=\"p1\">](#Startup)</ept>","source":"[Faster application startup](#Startup)"},{"pos":[11174,11222],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Summary of usage considerations<ept id=\"p1\">](#UsageSummary)</ept>","source":"[Summary of usage considerations](#UsageSummary)"},{"pos":[11232,11287],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Importance of assembly base addresses<ept id=\"p1\">](#BaseAddresses)</ept>","source":"[Importance of assembly base addresses](#BaseAddresses)"},{"pos":[11297,11325],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hard binding<ept id=\"p1\">](#HardBinding)</ept>","source":"[Hard binding](#HardBinding)"},{"pos":[11339,11400],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Specifying a binding hint for a dependency<ept id=\"p1\">](#DependencyHint)</ept>","source":"[Specifying a binding hint for a dependency](#DependencyHint)"},{"pos":[11414,11480],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly<ept id=\"p1\">](#AssemblyHint)</ept>","source":"[Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly](#AssemblyHint)"},{"pos":[11490,11522],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deferred processing<ept id=\"p1\">](#Deferred)</ept>","source":"[Deferred processing](#Deferred)"},{"pos":[11532,11584],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native images and JIT compilation<ept id=\"p1\">](#JITCompilation)</ept>","source":"[Native images and JIT compilation](#JITCompilation)"},{"pos":[11598,11630],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Invalid images<ept id=\"p1\">](#InvalidImages)</ept>","source":"[Invalid images](#InvalidImages)"},{"pos":[11640,11675],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Troubleshooting<ept id=\"p1\">](#Troubleshooting)</ept>","source":"[Troubleshooting](#Troubleshooting)"},{"pos":[11689,11727],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Binding Log Viewer<ept id=\"p1\">](#Fusion)</ept>","source":"[Assembly Binding Log Viewer](#Fusion)"},{"pos":[11741,11800],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant<ept id=\"p1\">](#MDA)</ept>","source":"[The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant](#MDA)"},{"pos":[11814,11862],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Opting out of native image generation<ept id=\"p1\">](#OptOut)</ept>","source":"[Opting out of native image generation](#OptOut)"},{"pos":[11899,11944],"content":"Generating images for     different scenarios","linkify":"Generating images for     different scenarios","nodes":[{"content":"Generating images for     different scenarios","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"After you have generated a native image for an assembly, the runtime automatically attempts to locate and use this native   image each time it runs the assembly.","pos":[11948,12109]},{"content":"Multiple images can be generated, depending on usage scenarios.","pos":[12110,12173]},{"content":"For example, if you run an assembly in a debugging or profiling scenario, the runtime looks for a native image that was generated with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/Debug`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`/Profile`</ph> options.","pos":[12180,12350],"source":"For example, if you run an assembly in a debugging or profiling scenario, the runtime looks for a native image that was generated with the `/Debug` or `/Profile` options."},{"content":"If it is unable to find a matching native image, the runtime reverts to standard JIT compilation.","pos":[12351,12448]},{"content":"The only way to debug native images is to create a native image with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/Debug`</ph>option.","pos":[12449,12537],"source":" The only way to debug native images is to create a native image with the `/Debug`option."},{"pos":[12544,12655],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`uninstall`</ph> action also recognize scenarios, so you can uninstall all scenarios or only selected scenarios.","source":"The `uninstall` action also recognize scenarios, so you can uninstall all scenarios or only selected scenarios."},{"pos":[12692,12729],"content":"Determining when to Use native images","linkify":"Determining when to Use native images","nodes":[{"content":"Determining when to Use native images","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Native images can provide performance improvements in two areas: improved memory use and reduced startup time.","pos":[12733,12843]},{"pos":[12851,13260],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Performance of native images depends on a number of factors that make analysis difficult, such as code and data access patterns, how many calls are made across module boundaries, and how many dependencies have already been loaded by other applications. The only way to determine whether native images benefit your application is by careful performance measurements in your key deployment scenarios.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Performance of native images depends on a number of factors that make analysis difficult, such as code and data access patterns, how many calls are made across module boundaries, and how many dependencies have already been loaded by other applications. The only way to determine whether native images benefit your application is by careful performance measurements in your key deployment scenarios.","pos":[9,407],"nodes":[{"content":"Performance of native images depends on a number of factors that make analysis difficult, such as code and data access patterns, how many calls are made across module boundaries, and how many dependencies have already been loaded by other applications.","pos":[0,252]},{"content":"The only way to determine whether native images benefit your application is by careful performance measurements in your key deployment scenarios.","pos":[253,398]}]}]},{"pos":[13295,13314],"content":"Improved memory use","linkify":"Improved memory use","nodes":[{"content":"Improved memory use","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Native images can significantly improve memory use when code is shared between processes.","pos":[13318,13407]},{"content":"Native images are Windows PE files, so a single copy of a .dll file can be shared by multiple processes; by contrast, native code produced by the JIT compiler is stored in private memory and cannot be shared.","pos":[13408,13616]},{"content":"Applications that are run under terminal services can also benefit from shared code pages.","pos":[13623,13713]},{"content":"In addition, not loading the JIT compiler saves a fixed amount of memory for each application instance.","pos":[13720,13823]},{"pos":[13859,13885],"content":"Faster application startup","linkify":"Faster application startup","nodes":[{"content":"Faster application startup","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"Precompiling assemblies with Ngen.exe can improve the startup time for some applications.","pos":[13889,13978]},{"content":"In general, gains can be made when applications share component assemblies because after the first application has been started the shared components are already loaded for subsequent applications.","pos":[13979,14176]},{"content":"Cold startup, in which all the assemblies in an application must be loaded from the hard disk, does not benefit as much from native images because the hard disk access time predominates.","pos":[14177,14363]},{"content":"Hard binding can affect startup time, because all images that are hard bound to the main application assembly must be loaded at the same time.","pos":[14370,14512]},{"pos":[14520,15033],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Before the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_long](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-long-md.md)], you should put shared, strong-named components in the global assembly cache, because the loader performs extra validation on strong-named assemblies that are not in the global assembly cache, effectively eliminating any improvement in startup time gained by using native images. Optimizations that were introduced in the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_short](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-short-md.md)] removed the extra validation.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Before the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_long](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-long-md.md)], you should put shared, strong-named components in the global assembly cache, because the loader performs extra validation on strong-named assemblies that are not in the global assembly cache, effectively eliminating any improvement in startup time gained by using native images. Optimizations that were introduced in the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_short](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-short-md.md)] removed the extra validation.","pos":[9,511],"nodes":[{"content":"Before the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_long](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-long-md.md)]</ph>, you should put shared, strong-named components in the global assembly cache, because the loader performs extra validation on strong-named assemblies that are not in the global assembly cache, effectively eliminating any improvement in startup time gained by using native images.","pos":[0,359],"source":"Before the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_long](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-long-md.md)], you should put shared, strong-named components in the global assembly cache, because the loader performs extra validation on strong-named assemblies that are not in the global assembly cache, effectively eliminating any improvement in startup time gained by using native images."},{"content":"Optimizations that were introduced in the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_short](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-short-md.md)]</ph> removed the extra validation.","pos":[360,502],"source":" Optimizations that were introduced in the [!INCLUDE[net_v35SP1_short](../../../includes/net-v35sp1-short-md.md)] removed the extra validation."}]}]},{"pos":[15074,15105],"content":"Summary of usage considerations","linkify":"Summary of usage considerations","nodes":[{"content":"Summary of usage considerations","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"The following general considerations and application considerations may assist you in deciding whether to undertake the effort of evaluating native images for your application:","pos":[15109,15285]},{"content":"Native images load faster than MSIL because they eliminate the need for many startup activities, such as JIT compilation and type-safety verification.","pos":[15295,15445]},{"content":"Native images require a smaller initial working set because there is no need for the JIT compiler.","pos":[15455,15553]},{"content":"Native images enable code sharing between processes.","pos":[15563,15615]},{"content":"Native images require more hard disk space than MSIL assemblies and may require considerable time to generate.","pos":[15625,15735]},{"content":"Native images must be maintained.","pos":[15745,15778]},{"content":"Images need to be regenerated when the original assembly or one of its dependencies is serviced.","pos":[15792,15888]},{"content":"A single assembly may need multiple native images for use in different applications or different scenarios.","pos":[15902,16009]},{"content":"For example, the configuration information in two applications might result in different binding decisions for the same dependent assembly.","pos":[16010,16149]},{"content":"Native images must be generated by an administrator; that is, from a Windows account in the Administrators group.","pos":[16163,16276]},{"content":"In addition to these general considerations, the nature of your application must be considered when determining whether native images might provide a performance benefit:","pos":[16283,16453]},{"content":"If your application runs in an environment that uses many shared components, native images allow the components to be shared by multiple processes.","pos":[16463,16610]},{"content":"If your application uses multiple application domains, native images allow code pages to be shared across domains.","pos":[16620,16734]},{"pos":[16746,16909],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIn the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, native images cannot be shared across application domains. This is not the case in version 2.0 or later.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"In the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, native images cannot be shared across application domains. This is not the case in version 2.0 or later.","pos":[8,156],"nodes":[{"content":"In the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, native images cannot be shared across application domains.","pos":[0,102]},{"content":"This is not the case in version 2.0 or later.","pos":[103,148]}]}]},{"content":"If your application will be run under Terminal Server, native images allow sharing of code pages.","pos":[16919,17016]},{"content":"Large applications generally benefit from compilation to native images.","pos":[17026,17097]},{"content":"Small applications generally do not benefit.","pos":[17098,17142]},{"content":"For long-running applications, run-time JIT compilation performs slightly better than native images.","pos":[17152,17252]},{"content":"(Hard binding can mitigate this performance difference to some degree.)","pos":[17253,17324]},{"pos":[17365,17402],"content":"Importance of assembly base addresses","linkify":"Importance of assembly base addresses","nodes":[{"content":"Importance of assembly base addresses","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Because native images are Windows PE files, they are subject to the same rebasing issues as other executable files.","pos":[17406,17521]},{"content":"The performance cost of relocation is even more pronounced if hard binding is employed.","pos":[17522,17609]},{"content":"To set the base address for a native image, use the appropriate option of your compiler to set the base address for the assembly.","pos":[17616,17745]},{"content":"Ngen.exe uses this base address for the native image.","pos":[17746,17799]},{"pos":[17807,17967],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Native images are larger than the managed assemblies from which they were created. Base addresses must be calculated to allow for these larger sizes.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Native images are larger than the managed assemblies from which they were created. Base addresses must be calculated to allow for these larger sizes.","pos":[9,158],"nodes":[{"content":"Native images are larger than the managed assemblies from which they were created.","pos":[0,82]},{"content":"Base addresses must be calculated to allow for these larger sizes.","pos":[83,149]}]}]},{"content":"You can use a tool such as dumpbin.exe to view the preferred base address of a native image.","pos":[17974,18066]},{"pos":[18105,18117],"content":"Hard binding","linkify":"Hard binding","nodes":[{"content":"Hard binding","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"Hard binding increases throughput and reduces working set size for native images.","pos":[18121,18202]},{"content":"The disadvantage of hard binding is that all the images that are hard bound to an assembly must be loaded when the assembly is loaded.","pos":[18203,18337]},{"content":"This can significantly increase startup time for a large application.","pos":[18338,18407]},{"content":"Hard binding is appropriate for dependencies that are loaded in all your application's performance-critical scenarios.","pos":[18414,18532]},{"content":"As with any aspect of native image use, careful performance measurements are the only way to determine whether hard binding improves your application's performance.","pos":[18533,18697]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> attributes allow you to provide hard binding hints to Ngen.exe.","pos":[18704,18900],"source":"The <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute> and <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> attributes allow you to provide hard binding hints to Ngen.exe."},{"pos":[18908,19079],"content":"[!NOTE]\n These attributes are hints to Ngen.exe, not commands. Using them does not guarantee hard binding. The meaning of these attributes may change in future releases.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"These attributes are hints to Ngen.exe, not commands. Using them does not guarantee hard binding. The meaning of these attributes may change in future releases.","pos":[9,169],"nodes":[{"content":"These attributes are hints to Ngen.exe, not commands.","pos":[0,53]},{"content":"Using them does not guarantee hard binding.","pos":[54,97]},{"content":"The meaning of these attributes may change in future releases.","pos":[98,160]}]}]},{"pos":[19122,19164],"content":"Specifying a binding hint for a dependency","linkify":"Specifying a binding hint for a dependency","nodes":[{"content":"Specifying a binding hint for a dependency","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Apply the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> to an assembly to indicate the likelihood that a specified dependency will be loaded.","pos":[19168,19322],"source":"Apply the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DependencyAttribute> to an assembly to indicate the likelihood that a specified dependency will be loaded."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> indicates that hard binding is appropriate, <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint&gt;</ph> indicates that the default for the dependency should be used, and <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint&gt;</ph> indicates that hard binding is not appropriate.","pos":[19323,19649],"source":" <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> indicates that hard binding is appropriate, <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint> indicates that the default for the dependency should be used, and <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint> indicates that hard binding is not appropriate."},{"content":"The following code shows the attributes for an assembly that has two dependencies.","pos":[19656,19738]},{"content":"The first dependency (Assembly1) is an appropriate candidate for hard binding, and the second (Assembly2) is not.","pos":[19739,19852]},{"content":"The assembly name does not include the file name extension.","pos":[20441,20500]},{"content":"Display names can be used.","pos":[20501,20527]},{"pos":[20568,20617],"content":"Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly","linkify":"Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly","nodes":[{"content":"Specifying a default binding hint for an assembly","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"Default binding hints are only needed for assemblies that will be used immediately and frequently by any application that has a dependency on them.","pos":[20621,20768]},{"content":"Apply the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> with <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> to such assemblies to specify that hard binding should be used.","pos":[20769,20986],"source":" Apply the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> with <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> to such assemblies to specify that hard binding should be used."},{"pos":[20994,21342],"content":"[!NOTE]\n There is no reason to apply <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> to .dll assemblies that do not fall into this category, because applying the attribute with any value other than <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> has the same effect as not applying the attribute at all.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"There is no reason to apply <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> to .dll assemblies that do not fall into this category, because applying the attribute with any value other than <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> has the same effect as not applying the attribute at all.","pos":[9,346],"source":"There is no reason to apply <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> to .dll assemblies that do not fall into this category, because applying the attribute with any value other than <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.LoadHint?displayProperty=fullName> has the same effect as not applying the attribute at all."}]},{"content":"Microsoft uses the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute&gt;</ph> to specify that hard binding is the default for a very small number of assemblies in the .NET Framework, such as mscorlib.dll.","pos":[21349,21560],"source":"Microsoft uses the <xref:System.Runtime.CompilerServices.DefaultDependencyAttribute> to specify that hard binding is the default for a very small number of assemblies in the .NET Framework, such as mscorlib.dll."},{"pos":[21596,21615],"content":"Deferred processing","linkify":"Deferred processing","nodes":[{"content":"Deferred processing","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Generation of native images for a very large application can take considerable time.","pos":[21619,21703]},{"content":"Similarly, changes to a shared component or changes to computer settings might require many native images to be updated.","pos":[21704,21824]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`install`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`update`</ph> actions have a <ph id=\"ph3\">`/queue`</ph> option that queues the operation for deferred execution by the native image service.","pos":[21825,21960],"source":" The `install` and `update` actions have a `/queue` option that queues the operation for deferred execution by the native image service."},{"content":"In addition, Ngen.exe has <ph id=\"ph1\">`queue`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`executeQueuedItems`</ph> actions that provide some control over the service.","pos":[21961,22071],"source":" In addition, Ngen.exe has `queue` and `executeQueuedItems` actions that provide some control over the service."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","pos":[22072,22191],"source":" For more information, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[22233,22266],"content":"Native images and JIT compilation","linkify":"Native images and JIT compilation","nodes":[{"content":"Native images and JIT compilation","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"If Ngen.exe encounters any methods in an assembly that it cannot generate, it excludes them from the native image.","pos":[22270,22384]},{"content":"When the runtime executes this assembly, it reverts to JIT compilation for the methods that were not included in the native image.","pos":[22385,22515]},{"content":"In addition, native images are not used if the assembly has been upgraded, or if the image has been invalidated for any reason.","pos":[22522,22649]},{"pos":[22691,22705],"content":"Invalid images","linkify":"Invalid images","nodes":[{"content":"Invalid images","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"When you use Ngen.exe to create a native image of an assembly, the output depends upon the command-line options that you specify and certain settings on your computer.","pos":[22709,22876]},{"content":"These settings include the following:","pos":[22877,22914]},{"content":"The version of the .NET Framework.","pos":[22924,22958]},{"content":"The version of the operating system, if the change is from the Windows 9x family to the Windows NT family.","pos":[22968,23074]},{"content":"The exact identity of the assembly (recompilation changes identity).","pos":[23084,23152]},{"content":"The exact identity of all assemblies that the assembly references (recompilation changes identity).","pos":[23162,23261]},{"content":"Security factors.","pos":[23271,23288]},{"content":"Ngen.exe records this information when it generates a native image.","pos":[23295,23362]},{"content":"When you execute an assembly, the runtime looks for the native image generated with options and settings that match the computer's current environment.","pos":[23363,23514]},{"content":"The runtime reverts to JIT compilation of an assembly if it cannot find a matching native image.","pos":[23515,23611]},{"content":"The following changes to a computer's settings and environment cause native images to become invalid:","pos":[23612,23713]},{"content":"The version of the .NET Framework.","pos":[23723,23757]},{"content":"If you apply an update to the .NET Framework, all native images that you have created using Ngen.exe become invalid.","pos":[23768,23884]},{"content":"For this reason, all updates of the .NET Framework execute the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Ngen Update`</ph> command, to ensure that all native images are regenerated.","pos":[23885,24020],"source":" For this reason, all updates of the .NET Framework execute the `Ngen Update` command, to ensure that all native images are regenerated."},{"content":"The .NET Framework automatically creates new native images for the .NET Framework libraries that it installs.","pos":[24021,24130]},{"content":"The version of the operating system, if the change is from the Windows 9x family to the Windows NT family.","pos":[24140,24246]},{"content":"For example, if the version of the operating system running on a computer changes from Windows 98 to Windows XP, all native images stored in the native image cache become invalid.","pos":[24257,24436]},{"content":"However, if the operating system changes from Windows 2000 to Windows XP, the images are not invalidated.","pos":[24437,24542]},{"content":"The exact identity of the assembly.","pos":[24552,24587]},{"content":"If you recompile an assembly, the assembly's corresponding native image becomes invalid.","pos":[24598,24686]},{"content":"The exact identity of any assemblies the assembly references.","pos":[24696,24757]},{"content":"If you update a managed assembly, all native images that directly or indirectly depend on that assembly become invalid and need to be regenerated.","pos":[24768,24914]},{"content":"This includes both ordinary references and hard-bound dependencies.","pos":[24915,24982]},{"content":"Whenever a software update is applied, the installation program should execute an <ph id=\"ph1\">`Ngen Update`</ph> command to ensure that all dependent native images are regenerated.","pos":[24983,25146],"source":" Whenever a software update is applied, the installation program should execute an `Ngen Update` command to ensure that all dependent native images are regenerated."},{"content":"Security factors.","pos":[25156,25173]},{"content":"Changing machine security policy to restrict permissions previously granted to an assembly can cause a previously compiled native image for that assembly to become invalid.","pos":[25184,25356]},{"pos":[25367,25572],"content":"For detailed information about how the common language runtime administers code access security and how to use permissions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Code Access Security<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/misc/code-access-security.md)</ept>.","source":"For detailed information about how the common language runtime administers code access security and how to use permissions, see [Code Access Security](../../../docs/framework/misc/code-access-security.md)."},{"pos":[25615,25630],"content":"Troubleshooting","linkify":"Troubleshooting","nodes":[{"content":"Troubleshooting","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"The following troubleshooting topics allow you to see which native images are being used and which cannot be used by your application, to determine when the JIT compiler starts to compile a method, and shows how to opt out of native image compilation of specified methods.","pos":[25634,25906]},{"pos":[25941,25968],"content":"Assembly Binding Log Viewer","linkify":"Assembly Binding Log Viewer","nodes":[{"content":"Assembly Binding Log Viewer","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"To confirm that native images are being used by your application, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Fuslogvw.exe (Assembly Binding Log Viewer)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/fuslogvw-exe-assembly-binding-log-viewer.md)</ept>.","pos":[25972,26174],"source":"To confirm that native images are being used by your application, you can use the [Fuslogvw.exe (Assembly Binding Log Viewer)](../../../docs/framework/tools/fuslogvw-exe-assembly-binding-log-viewer.md)."},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Native Images<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Log Categories<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> box on the binding log viewer window.","pos":[26175,26263],"source":" Select **Native Images** in the **Log Categories** box on the binding log viewer window."},{"content":"Fuslogvw.exe provides information about why a native image was rejected.","pos":[26264,26336]},{"pos":[26368,26419],"content":"The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant","linkify":"The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant","nodes":[{"content":"The JITCompilationStart managed debugging assistant","pos":[0,51]}]},{"pos":[26423,26631],"content":"You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>jitCompilationStart<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/debug-trace-profile/jitcompilationstart-mda.md)</ept> managed debugging assistant (MDA) to determine when the JIT compiler starts to compile a function.","source":"You can use the [jitCompilationStart](../../../docs/framework/debug-trace-profile/jitcompilationstart-mda.md) managed debugging assistant (MDA) to determine when the JIT compiler starts to compile a function."},{"pos":[26666,26703],"content":"Opting out of native image generation","linkify":"Opting out of native image generation","nodes":[{"content":"Opting out of native image generation","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"In some cases, NGen.exe may have difficulty generating a native image for a specific method, or you may prefer that the method be JIT compiled rather then compiled to a native image.","pos":[26707,26889]},{"content":"In this case, you can use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute`</ph> attribute to prevent NGen.exe from generating a native image for a particular method.","pos":[26890,27042],"source":" In this case, you can use the `System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute` attribute to prevent NGen.exe from generating a native image for a particular method."},{"content":"The attribute must be applied individually to each method whose code you do not want to include in the native image.","pos":[27043,27159]},{"content":"NGen.exe recognizes the attribute and does not generate code in the native image for the corresponding method.","pos":[27160,27270]},{"content":"Note, however, that <ph id=\"ph1\">`BypassNGenAttribute`</ph> is not defined as a type in the .NET Framework Class library.","pos":[27277,27380],"source":"Note, however, that `BypassNGenAttribute` is not defined as a type in the .NET Framework Class library."},{"content":"In order to consume the attribute in your code, you must first define it as follows:","pos":[27381,27465]},{"pos":[27472,27795],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#1)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#1)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#1)]"},{"content":"You can then apply the attribute on a per-method basis.","pos":[27802,27857]},{"content":"The following example instructs the Native Image Generator that it should not generate a native image for the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ExampleClass.ToJITCompile`</ph> method.","pos":[27858,28003],"source":" The following example instructs the Native Image Generator that it should not generate a native image for the `ExampleClass.ToJITCompile` method."},{"pos":[28010,28333],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#2)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#2)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/cs/Optout1.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR_System/System.Runtime.BypassNGenAttribute/vb/Optout1.vb#2)]"},{"pos":[28342,28350],"content":"Examples","linkify":"Examples","nodes":[{"content":"Examples","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The following command generates a native image for <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph>, located in the current directory, and installs the image in the native image cache.","pos":[28354,28505],"source":"The following command generates a native image for `ClientApp.exe`, located in the current directory, and installs the image in the native image cache."},{"content":"If a configuration file exists for the assembly, Ngen.exe uses it.","pos":[28506,28572]},{"content":"In addition, native images are generated for any .dll files that <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph> references.","pos":[28573,28665],"source":" In addition, native images are generated for any .dll files that `ClientApp.exe` references."},{"content":"An image installed with Ngen.exe is also called a root.","pos":[28716,28771]},{"content":"A root can be an application or a shared component.","pos":[28772,28823]},{"pos":[28830,28922],"content":"The following command generates a native image for <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyAssembly.exe`</ph> with the specified path.","source":"The following command generates a native image for `MyAssembly.exe` with the specified path."},{"content":"When locating assemblies and their dependencies, Ngen.exe uses the same probing logic used by the common language runtime.","pos":[28985,29107]},{"content":"By default, the directory that contains <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph> is used as the application base directory, and all assembly probing begins in this directory.","pos":[29108,29257],"source":" By default, the directory that contains `ClientApp.exe` is used as the application base directory, and all assembly probing begins in this directory."},{"content":"You can override this behavior by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/AppBase`</ph> option.","pos":[29258,29320],"source":" You can override this behavior by using the `/AppBase` option."},{"pos":[29328,29482],"content":"[!NOTE]\n This is a change from Ngen.exe behavior in the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, where the application base is set to the current directory.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This is a change from Ngen.exe behavior in the .NET Framework versions 1.0 and 1.1, where the application base is set to the current directory.","pos":[9,152]}]},{"content":"An assembly can have a dependency without a reference, for example if it loads a .dll file by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[29489,29667],"source":"An assembly can have a dependency without a reference, for example if it loads a .dll file by using the <xref:System.Reflection.Assembly.Load%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method."},{"content":"You can create a native image for such a .dll file by using configuration information for the application assembly, with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/ExeConfig`</ph> option.","pos":[29668,29813],"source":" You can create a native image for such a .dll file by using configuration information for the application assembly, with the `/ExeConfig` option."},{"content":"The following command generates a native image for <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyLib.dll,`</ph> using the configuration information from <ph id=\"ph2\">`MyApp.exe`</ph>.","pos":[29814,29931],"source":" The following command generates a native image for `MyLib.dll,` using the configuration information from `MyApp.exe`."},{"content":"Assemblies installed in this way are not removed when the application is removed.","pos":[30020,30101]},{"content":"To uninstall a dependency, use the same command-line options that were used to install it.","pos":[30108,30198]},{"content":"The following command uninstalls the <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyLib.dll`</ph> from the previous example.","pos":[30199,30274],"source":" The following command uninstalls the `MyLib.dll` from the previous example."},{"content":"To create a native image for an assembly in the global assembly cache, use the display name of the assembly.","pos":[30365,30473]},{"content":"For example:","pos":[30474,30486]},{"content":"NGen.exe generates a separate set of images for each scenario you install.","pos":[30635,30709]},{"content":"For example, the following commands install a complete set of native images for normal operation, another complete set for debugging, and a third for profiling:","pos":[30710,30870]},{"pos":[30986,31019],"content":"Displaying the Native Image Cache","linkify":"Displaying the Native Image Cache","nodes":[{"content":"Displaying the Native Image Cache","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"Once native images are installed in the cache, they can be displayed using Ngen.exe.","pos":[31023,31107]},{"content":"The following command displays all native images in the native image cache.","pos":[31108,31183]},{"pos":[31220,31338],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`display`</ph> action lists all the root assemblies first, followed by a list of all the native images on the computer.","source":"The `display` action lists all the root assemblies first, followed by a list of all the native images on the computer."},{"content":"Use the simple name of an assembly to display information only for that assembly.","pos":[31345,31426]},{"content":"The following command displays all native images in the native image cache that match the partial name <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyAssembly`</ph>, their dependencies, and all roots that have a dependency on <ph id=\"ph2\">`MyAssembly`</ph>:","pos":[31427,31617],"source":" The following command displays all native images in the native image cache that match the partial name `MyAssembly`, their dependencies, and all roots that have a dependency on `MyAssembly`:"},{"pos":[31665,31815],"content":"Knowing what roots depend on a shared component assembly is useful in gauging the impact of an <ph id=\"ph1\">`update`</ph> action after the shared component is upgraded.","source":"Knowing what roots depend on a shared component assembly is useful in gauging the impact of an `update` action after the shared component is upgraded."},{"content":"If you specify an assembly's file extension, you must either specify the path or execute Ngen.exe from the directory containing the assembly:","pos":[31822,31963]},{"pos":[32025,32151],"content":"The following command displays all native images in the native image cache with the name <ph id=\"ph1\">`MyAssembly`</ph> and the version 1.0.0.0.","source":"The following command displays all native images in the native image cache with the name `MyAssembly` and the version 1.0.0.0."},{"pos":[32221,32236],"content":"Updating Images","linkify":"Updating Images","nodes":[{"content":"Updating Images","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"Images are typically updated after a shared component has been upgraded.","pos":[32240,32312]},{"content":"To update all native images that have changed, or whose dependencies have changed, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`update`</ph> action with no arguments.","pos":[32313,32438],"source":" To update all native images that have changed, or whose dependencies have changed, use the `update` action with no arguments."},{"content":"Updating all images can be a lengthy process.","pos":[32474,32519]},{"content":"You can queue the updates for execution by the native image service by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> option.","pos":[32520,32617],"source":" You can queue the updates for execution by the native image service by using the `/queue` option."},{"content":"For more information on the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> option and installation priorities, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","pos":[32618,32788],"source":" For more information on the `/queue` option and installation priorities, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[32834,32853],"content":"Uninstalling Images","linkify":"Uninstalling Images","nodes":[{"content":"Uninstalling Images","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Ngen.exe maintains a list of dependencies, so that shared components are removed only when all assemblies that depend on them have been removed.","pos":[32857,33001]},{"content":"In addition, a shared component is not removed if it has been installed as a root.","pos":[33002,33084]},{"pos":[33091,33167],"content":"The following command uninstalls all scenarios for the root <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph>:","source":"The following command uninstalls all scenarios for the root `ClientApp.exe`:"},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`uninstall`</ph> action can be used to remove specific scenarios.","pos":[33216,33280],"source":"The `uninstall` action can be used to remove specific scenarios."},{"content":"The following command uninstalls all debug scenarios for <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph>:","pos":[33281,33354],"source":" The following command uninstalls all debug scenarios for `ClientApp.exe`:"},{"pos":[33411,33527],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Uninstalling `/debug` scenarios does not uninstall a scenario that includes both `/profile` and `/debug.`","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Uninstalling <ph id=\"ph1\">`/debug`</ph> scenarios does not uninstall a scenario that includes both <ph id=\"ph2\">`/profile`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">`/debug.`</ph>","pos":[9,114],"source":"Uninstalling `/debug` scenarios does not uninstall a scenario that includes both `/profile` and `/debug.`"}]},{"pos":[33534,33623],"content":"The following command uninstalls all scenarios for a specific version of <ph id=\"ph1\">`ClientApp.exe`</ph>:","source":"The following command uninstalls all scenarios for a specific version of `ClientApp.exe`:"},{"pos":[33691,33897],"content":"The following commands uninstall all scenarios for <ph id=\"ph1\">`\"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\",`</ph> or just the debug scenario for that assembly:","source":"The following commands uninstall all scenarios for `\"ClientApp, Version=1.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=3c7ba247adcd2081, processorArchitecture=MSIL\",` or just the debug scenario for that assembly:"},{"pos":[34184,34341],"content":"As with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`install`</ph> action, supplying an extension requires either executing Ngen.exe from the directory containing the assembly or specifying a full path.","source":"As with the `install` action, supplying an extension requires either executing Ngen.exe from the directory containing the assembly or specifying a full path."},{"pos":[34348,34496],"content":"For examples relating to the native image service, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","source":"For examples relating to the native image service, see [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[34505,34522],"content":"Native Image Task","linkify":"Native Image Task","nodes":[{"content":"Native Image Task","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"The native image task is a Windows task that generates and maintains native images.","pos":[34526,34609]},{"content":"The native image task generates and reclaims native images automatically for supported scenarios.","pos":[34610,34707]},{"content":"(See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Native Images<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/2bc8b678-dd8d-4742-ad82-319e9bf52418)</ept>.) It also enables installers to use <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/ngen-exe-native-image-generator.md)</ept> to create and update native images at a deferred time.","pos":[34708,35000],"source":" (See [Creating Native Images](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/2bc8b678-dd8d-4742-ad82-319e9bf52418).) It also enables installers to use [Ngen.exe (Native Image Generator)](../../../docs/framework/tools/ngen-exe-native-image-generator.md) to create and update native images at a deferred time."},{"content":"The native image task is registered once for each CPU architecture supported on a computer, to allow compilation for applications that target each architecture:","pos":[35007,35167]},{"content":"Task name","pos":[35174,35183]},{"content":"32-bit computer","pos":[35184,35199]},{"content":"64-bit computer","pos":[35200,35215]},{"content":"NET Framework NGEN v4.0.30319","pos":[35286,35315]},{"content":"Yes","pos":[35316,35319]},{"content":"Yes","pos":[35320,35323]},{"content":"NET Framework NGEN v4.0.30319 64","pos":[35328,35360]},{"content":"No","pos":[35361,35363]},{"content":"Yes","pos":[35364,35367]},{"content":"The native image task is is available in the .NET Framework 4.5 and later versions, when running on Windows 8 or later.","pos":[35375,35494]},{"content":"On earlier versions of Windows, the .NET Framework uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept>.","pos":[35495,35648],"source":" On earlier versions of Windows, the .NET Framework uses the [Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)."},{"pos":[35658,35671],"content":"Task Lifetime","linkify":"Task Lifetime","nodes":[{"content":"Task Lifetime","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"In general, the Windows Task Scheduler starts the native image task every night when the computer is idle.","pos":[35675,35781]},{"content":"The task checks for any deferred work that is queued by application installers, any deferred native image update requests, and any automatic image creation.","pos":[35782,35938]},{"content":"The task completes outstanding work items and then shuts down.","pos":[35939,36001]},{"content":"If the computer stops being idle while the task is running, the task stops.","pos":[36002,36077]},{"content":"You can also start the native image task manually through the Task Scheduler UI or through manual calls to NGen.exe.","pos":[36084,36200]},{"content":"If the task is started through either of these methods, it will continue running when the computer is no longer idle.","pos":[36201,36318]},{"content":"Images created manually by using NGen.exe are prioritized to enable predictable behavior for application installers.","pos":[36319,36435]},{"pos":[36444,36464],"content":"Native Image Service","linkify":"Native Image Service","nodes":[{"content":"Native Image Service","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"The native image service is a Windows service that generates and maintains native images.","pos":[36468,36557]},{"content":"The native image service allows the developer to defer the installation and update of native images to periods when the computer is idle.","pos":[36558,36695]},{"content":"Normally, the native image service is initiated by the installation program (installer) for an application or update.","pos":[36702,36819]},{"content":"For priority 3 actions, the service executes during idle time on the computer.","pos":[36820,36898]},{"content":"The service saves its state and is capable of continuing through multiple reboots if necessary.","pos":[36899,36994]},{"content":"Multiple image compilations can be queued.","pos":[36995,37037]},{"content":"The service also interacts with the manual Ngen.exe command.","pos":[37044,37104]},{"content":"Manual commands take precedence over background activity.","pos":[37105,37162]},{"pos":[37170,37509],"content":"[!NOTE]\n On Windows Vista, the name displayed for the native image service is \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X86\" or \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X64\". On all earlier versions of Microsoft Windows, the name is \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X86\" or \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X64\".","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"On Windows Vista, the name displayed for the native image service is \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X86\" or \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X64\". On all earlier versions of Microsoft Windows, the name is \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X86\" or \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X64\".","pos":[9,337],"nodes":[{"content":"On Windows Vista, the name displayed for the native image service is \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X86\" or \"Microsoft.NET Framework NGEN v2.0.50727_X64\".","pos":[0,164]},{"content":"On all earlier versions of Microsoft Windows, the name is \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X86\" or \".NET Runtime Optimization Service v2.0.50727_X64\".","pos":[165,328]}]}]},{"pos":[37519,37548],"content":"Launching Deferred Operations","linkify":"Launching Deferred Operations","nodes":[{"content":"Launching Deferred Operations","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"Before beginning an installation or upgrade, pausing the service is recommended.","pos":[37552,37632]},{"content":"This ensures that the service does not execute while the installer is copying files or putting assemblies in the global assembly cache.","pos":[37633,37768]},{"content":"The following Ngen.exe command line pauses the service:","pos":[37769,37824]},{"content":"When all deferred operations have been queued, the following command allows the service to resume:","pos":[37865,37963]},{"content":"To defer native image generation when installing a new application or when updating a shared component, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> option with the <ph id=\"ph2\">`install`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph3\">`update`</ph> actions.","pos":[38007,38174],"source":"To defer native image generation when installing a new application or when updating a shared component, use the `/queue` option with the `install` or `update` actions."},{"content":"The following Ngen.exe command lines install a native image for a shared component and perform an update of all roots that may have been affected:","pos":[38175,38321]},{"pos":[38398,38514],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`update`</ph> action regenerates all native images that have been invalidated, not just those that use <ph id=\"ph2\">`MyComponent`</ph>.","source":"The `update` action regenerates all native images that have been invalidated, not just those that use `MyComponent`."},{"content":"If your application consists of many roots, you can control the priority of the deferred actions.","pos":[38521,38618]},{"content":"The following commands queue the installation of three roots.","pos":[38619,38680]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`Assembly1`</ph> is installed first, without waiting for idle time.","pos":[38681,38743],"source":"`Assembly1` is installed first, without waiting for idle time."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`Assembly2`</ph> is also installed without waiting for idle time, but after all priority 1 actions have completed.","pos":[38744,38853],"source":"`Assembly2` is also installed without waiting for idle time, but after all priority 1 actions have completed."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`Assembly3`</ph> is installed when the service detects that the computer is idle.","pos":[38854,38930],"source":"`Assembly3` is installed when the service detects that the computer is idle."},{"content":"You can force queued actions to occur synchronously by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`executeQueuedItems`</ph> action.","pos":[39054,39147],"source":"You can force queued actions to occur synchronously by using the `executeQueuedItems` action."},{"content":"If you supply the optional priority, this action affects only the queued actions that have equal or lower priority.","pos":[39148,39263]},{"content":"The default priority is 3, so the following Ngen.exe command processes all queued actions immediately, and does not return until they are finished:","pos":[39264,39411]},{"content":"Synchronous commands are executed by Ngen.exe and do not use the native image service.","pos":[39459,39545]},{"content":"You can execute actions using Ngen.exe while the native image service is running.","pos":[39546,39627]},{"pos":[39637,39653],"content":"Service Shutdown","linkify":"Service Shutdown","nodes":[{"content":"Service Shutdown","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"After being initiated by the execution of an Ngen.exe command that includes the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/queue`</ph> option, the service runs in the background until all actions have been completed.","pos":[39657,39827],"source":"After being initiated by the execution of an Ngen.exe command that includes the `/queue` option, the service runs in the background until all actions have been completed."},{"content":"The service saves its state so that it can continue through multiple reboots if necessary.","pos":[39828,39918]},{"content":"When the service detects that there are no more actions queued, it resets its status so that it will not restart the next time the computer is booted, and then it shuts itself down.","pos":[39919,40100]},{"pos":[40110,40142],"content":"Service Interaction with Clients","linkify":"Service Interaction with Clients","nodes":[{"content":"Service Interaction with Clients","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"In the .NET Framework version 2.0, the only interaction with the native image service is through the command-line tool Ngen.exe.","pos":[40146,40274]},{"content":"Use the command-line tool in installation scripts to queue actions for the native image service and to interact with the service.","pos":[40275,40404]},{"pos":[40413,40421],"content":"See Also","linkify":"See Also","nodes":[{"content":"See Also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Service<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[40425,40518],"source":"[Native Image Service](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/b15e0e32-59cb-4ae4-967c-6c9527781309) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Native Image Task<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[40522,40612],"source":"[Native Image Task](http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/9b1f7590-4e0d-4737-90ef-eaf696932afb) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Tools<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/index.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[40616,40664],"source":"[Tools](../../../docs/framework/tools/index.md) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managed Execution Process<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/managed-execution-process.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[40668,40749],"source":"[Managed Execution Process](../../../docs/standard/managed-execution-process.md) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How the Runtime Locates Assemblies<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/deployment/how-the-runtime-locates-assemblies.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[40753,40864],"source":"[How the Runtime Locates Assemblies](../../../docs/framework/deployment/how-the-runtime-locates-assemblies.md) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Command Prompts<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md)</ept>","pos":[40868,40951],"source":"[Command Prompts](../../../docs/framework/tools/developer-command-prompt-for-vs.md)"}]}