{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Instancing Initialization | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-clr\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nms.assetid: 154d049f-2140-4696-b494-c7e53f6775ef\ncaps.latest.revision: 31\nauthor: \"Erikre\"\nms.author: \"erikre\"\nmanager: \"erikre\"\n---\n# Instancing Initialization\nThis sample extends the [Pooling](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/pooling.md) sample by defining an interface, `IObjectControl`, which customizes the initialization of an object by activating and deactivating it. The client invokes methods that return the object to the pool and that do not return the object to the pool.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.  \n  \n## Extensibility Points  \n The first step in creating a [!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)] extension is to decide the extensibility point to use. In [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)], the term *EndpointDispatcher* refers to a run-time component responsible for converting incoming messages into method invocations on the user’s service and for converting return values from that method to an outgoing message. A [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] service creates an EndpointDispatcher for each endpoint.  \n  \n The EndpointDispatcher offers endpoint scope (for all messages received or sent by the service) extensibility using the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher> class. This class allows you to customize various properties that control the behavior of the EndpointDispatcher. This sample focuses on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A> property that points to the object that provides the instances of the service class.  \n  \n## IInstanceProvider  \n In [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)], the EndpointDispatcher creates instances of a service class by using an instance provider that implements the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> interface. This interface has only two methods:  \n  \n-   <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A>: When a message arrives, the Dispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method to create an instance of the service class to process the message. The frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property. For example if the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property is set to <xref:System.ServiceModel.InstanceContextMode?displayProperty=fullName>, a new instance of service class is created to process each message that arrives, so <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> is called whenever a message arrives.  \n  \n-   <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A>: When the service instance finishes processing the message, the EndpointDispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A> method. As in the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method, the frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property.  \n  \n## The Object Pool  \n The `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` class contains the implementation for the object pool. This class implements the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> interface to interact with the service model layer. When the EndpointDispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method, instead of creating a new instance, the custom implementation looks for an existing object in an in-memory pool. If one is available, it is returned. Otherwise, `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` checks whether the `ActiveObjectsCount` property (number of objects returned from the pool) has reached the maximum pool size. If not, a new instance is created and returned to the caller and `ActiveObjectsCount` is subsequently incremented. Otherwise an object creation request is queued for a configured period of time. The implementation for `GetObjectFromThePool` is shown in the following sample code.  \n  \n```  \n  \nprivate object GetObjectFromThePool()  \n{  \n    bool didNotTimeout =   \n       availableCount.WaitOne(creationTimeout, true);  \n    if(didNotTimeout)  \n    {  \n         object obj = null;  \n         lock (poolLock)  \n        {  \n             if (pool.Count != 0)  \n             {  \n                   obj = pool.Pop();  \n                   activeObjectsCount++;  \n             }  \n             else if (pool.Count == 0)  \n             {  \n                   if (activeObjectsCount < maxPoolSize)  \n                   {  \n                        obj = CreateNewPoolObject();  \n                        activeObjectsCount++;  \n  \n                        #if (DEBUG)  \n                        WritePoolMessage(  \n                             ResourceHelper.GetString(\"MsgNewObject\"));  \n                       #endif  \n                   }                          \n            }  \n           idleTimer.Stop();  \n      }  \n     // Call the Activate method if possible.  \n    if (obj is IObjectControl)  \n   {  \n         ((IObjectControl)obj).Activate();  \n   }  \n   return obj;  \n}  \nthrow new TimeoutException(  \nResourceHelper.GetString(\"ExObjectCreationTimeout\"));  \n}  \n```  \n  \n The custom `ReleaseInstance` implementation adds the released instance back to the pool and decrements the `ActiveObjectsCount` value. The EndpointDispatcher can call these methods from different threads, and therefore synchronized access to the class level members in the `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` class is required.  \n  \n```  \npublic void ReleaseInstance(InstanceContext instanceContext, object instance)  \n{  \n    lock (poolLock)  \n    {  \n        // Check whether the object can be pooled.   \n        // Call the Deactivate method if possible.  \n        if (instance is IObjectControl)  \n        {  \n            IObjectControl objectControl = (IObjectControl)instance;  \n            objectControl.Deactivate();  \n  \n            if (objectControl.CanBePooled)  \n            {  \n                pool.Push(instance);  \n  \n                #if(DEBUG)  \n                WritePoolMessage(  \n                    ResourceHelper.GetString(\"MsgObjectPooled\"));  \n                #endif                          \n            }  \n            else  \n            {  \n                #if(DEBUG)  \n                WritePoolMessage(  \n                    ResourceHelper.GetString(\"MsgObjectWasNotPooled\"));  \n                #endif  \n            }  \n        }  \n        else  \n        {  \n            pool.Push(instance);  \n  \n            #if(DEBUG)  \n            WritePoolMessage(  \n                ResourceHelper.GetString(\"MsgObjectPooled\"));  \n            #endif   \n        }  \n  \n        activeObjectsCount--;  \n  \n        if (activeObjectsCount == 0)  \n        {  \n            idleTimer.Start();                       \n        }  \n    }  \n  \n    availableCount.Release(1);  \n}  \n  \n```  \n  \n The `ReleaseInstance` method provides a *clean up initialization* feature. Normally the pool maintains a minimum number of objects for the lifetime of the pool. However, there can be periods of excessive usage that require creating additional objects in the pool to reach the maximum limit specified in the configuration. Eventually when the pool becomes less active those surplus objects can become an extra overhead. Therefore when the `activeObjectsCount` reaches zero an idle timer is started that triggers and performs a clean-up cycle.  \n  \n```  \nif (activeObjectsCount == 0)  \n{  \n    idleTimer.Start();   \n}  \n  \n```  \n  \n ServiceModel layer extensions are hooked up using the following behaviors:  \n  \n-   Service Behaviors: These allow for the customization of the entire service runtime.  \n  \n-   Endpoint Behaviors: These allow for the customization of a particular service endpoint, including the EndpointDispatcher.  \n  \n-   Contract Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientRuntime> or <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime> classes on the client or the service respectively.  \n  \n-   Operation Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientOperation> or <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchOperation> classes on the client or the service respectively.  \n  \n For the purpose of an object pooling extension, either an endpoint behavior or a service behavior can be created. In this example, we use a service behavior, which applies object pooling ability to every endpoint of the service. Service behaviors are created by implementing the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> interface. There are several ways to make the ServiceModel aware of the custom behaviors:  \n  \n-   Using a custom attribute.  \n  \n-   Imperatively adding it to the service description’s behaviors collection.  \n  \n-   Extending the configuration file.  \n  \n This sample uses a custom attribute. When the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> is constructed, it examines the attributes used in the service’s type definition and adds the available behaviors to the service description’s behaviors collection.  \n  \n The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> interface has three methods: <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A>`,` <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A>`,` and <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A>. These methods are called by [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] when the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> is being initialized. <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called first; it allows the service to be inspected for inconsistencies. <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called next; this method is only required in very advanced scenarios. <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called last and is responsible for configuring the runtime. The following parameters are passed into <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName>:  \n  \n-   `Description`: This parameter provides the service description for the entire service. This can be used to inspect description data about the service’s endpoints, contracts, bindings, and other data associated with the service.  \n  \n-   `ServiceHostBase`: This parameter provides the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> that is currently being initialized.  \n  \n In the custom <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> implementation, a new instance of `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` is instantiated and assigned to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A> property in each <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher> that is attached to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>.  \n  \n```  \npublic void ApplyDispatchBehavior(ServiceDescription description, ServiceHostBase serviceHostBase)  \n{  \n    if (enabled)  \n    {  \n        // Create an instance of the ObjectPoolInstanceProvider.  \n        instanceProvider = new ObjectPoolInstanceProvider(description.ServiceType,  \n        maxPoolSize, minPoolSize, creationTimeout);  \n  \n        // Assign our instance provider to Dispatch behavior in each   \n        // endpoint.  \n        foreach (ChannelDispatcherBase cdb in serviceHostBase.ChannelDispatchers)  \n        {  \n             ChannelDispatcher cd = cdb as ChannelDispatcher;  \n             if (cd != null)  \n             {  \n                 foreach (EndpointDispatcher ed in cd.Endpoints)  \n                 {  \n                        ed.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider = instanceProvider;  \n                 }  \n             }  \n         }  \n     }  \n}   \n```  \n  \n In addition to an <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> implementation the `ObjectPoolingAttribute` class has several members to customize the object pool using the attribute arguments. These members include `MaxSize`, `MinSize`, `Enabled` and `CreationTimeout`, to match the object pooling feature set provided by .NET Enterprise Services.  \n  \n The object pooling behavior can now be added to a [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] service by annotating the service implementation with the newly created custom `ObjectPooling` attribute.  \n  \n```  \n[ObjectPooling(MaxSize=1024, MinSize=10, CreationTimeout=30000]      \npublic class PoolService : IPoolService  \n{  \n  // …  \n}  \n```  \n  \n## Hooking Activation and Deactivation  \n The primary objective of object pooling is to optimize short-lived objects with relatively expensive creation and initialization. Therefore it can give a dramatic performance boost to an application if properly used. Because the object is returned from the pool, the constructor is called only once. However, some applications require some level of control so that they can initialize and clean-up the resources used during a single context. For example, an object being used for a set of calculations can reset its private fields before processing the next calculation. Enterprise Services enabled this kind of context-specific initialization by letting the object developer override `Activate` and `Deactivate` methods from the <xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent> base class.  \n  \n The object pool calls the `Activate` method just before returning the object from the pool. `Deactivate` is called when the object returns back to the pool. The <xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent> base class also has a `boolean` property called `CanBePooled`, which can be used to notify the pool whether the object can be pooled further.  \n  \n To mimic this functionality, the sample declares a public interface (`IObjectControl`) that has the aforementioned members. This interface is then implemented by service classes intended to provide context specific initialization. The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> implementation must be modified to meet these requirements. Now, each time you get an object by calling the `GetInstance` method, you must check whether the object implements `IObjectControl.` If it does, you must call the `Activate` method appropriately.  \n  \n```  \nif (obj is IObjectControl)  \n{  \n    ((IObjectControl)obj).Activate();  \n}  \n  \n```  \n  \n When returning an object to the pool, a check is required for the `CanBePooled` property before adding the object back to the pool.  \n  \n```  \nif (instance is IObjectControl)  \n{  \n    IObjectControl objectControl = (IObjectControl)instance;  \n    objectControl.Deactivate();  \n    if (objectControl.CanBePooled)  \n    {  \n       pool.Push(instance);  \n    }  \n}  \n  \n```  \n  \n Because the service developer can decide whether an object can be pooled, the object count in the pool at a given time can go below the minimum size. Therefore you must check whether the object count has gone below the minimum level and perform the necessary initialization in the clean-up procedure.  \n  \n```  \n// Remove the surplus objects.  \nif (pool.Count > minPoolSize)  \n{  \n  // Clean the surplus objects.  \n}                      \nelse if (pool.Count < minPoolSize)  \n{  \n  // Reinitialize the missing objects.  \n  while(pool.Count != minPoolSize)  \n  {  \n    pool.Push(CreateNewPoolObject());  \n  }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n When you run the sample, the operation requests and responses are displayed in both the service and client console windows. Press Enter in each console window to shut down the service and client.  \n  \n#### To set up, build, and run the sample  \n  \n1.  Ensure that you have performed the [One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md).  \n  \n2.  To build the solution, follow the instructions in [Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md).  \n  \n3.  To run the sample in a single- or cross-machine configuration, follow the instructions in [Running the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/running-the-samples.md).  \n  \n> [!IMPORTANT]\n>  The samples may already be installed on your machine. Check for the following (default) directory before continuing.  \n>   \n>  `<InstallDrive>:\\WF_WCF_Samples`  \n>   \n>  If this directory does not exist, go to [Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) and Windows Workflow Foundation (WF) Samples for .NET Framework 4](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=150780) to download all [!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)] and [!INCLUDE[wf1](../../../../includes/wf1-md.md)] samples. This sample is located in the following directory.  \n>   \n>  `<InstallDrive>:\\WF_WCF_Samples\\WCF\\Extensibility\\Instancing\\Initialization`  \n  \n## See Also","nodes":[{"pos":[12,54],"content":"Instancing Initialization | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Instancing Initialization | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,42]}]},{"pos":[353,378],"content":"Instancing Initialization","linkify":"Instancing Initialization","nodes":[{"content":"Instancing Initialization","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This sample extends the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Pooling<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/pooling.md)</ept> sample by defining an interface, <ph id=\"ph1\">`IObjectControl`</ph>, which customizes the initialization of an object by activating and deactivating it.","pos":[379,598],"source":"This sample extends the [Pooling](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/pooling.md) sample by defining an interface, `IObjectControl`, which customizes the initialization of an object by activating and deactivating it."},{"content":"The client invokes methods that return the object to the pool and that do not return the object to the pool.","pos":[599,707]},{"pos":[715,822],"content":"[!NOTE]\n The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.","pos":[9,105]}]},{"pos":[831,851],"content":"Extensibility Points","linkify":"Extensibility Points","nodes":[{"content":"Extensibility Points","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"The first step in creating a <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)]</ph> extension is to decide the extensibility point to use.","pos":[855,994],"source":"The first step in creating a [!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)] extension is to decide the extensibility point to use."},{"content":"In <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)]</ph>, the term <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>EndpointDispatcher<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> refers to a run-time component responsible for converting incoming messages into method invocations on the user’s service and for converting return values from that method to an outgoing message.","pos":[995,1280],"source":" In [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)], the term *EndpointDispatcher* refers to a run-time component responsible for converting incoming messages into method invocations on the user’s service and for converting return values from that method to an outgoing message."},{"content":"A <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)]</ph> service creates an EndpointDispatcher for each endpoint.","pos":[1281,1395],"source":" A [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] service creates an EndpointDispatcher for each endpoint."},{"content":"The EndpointDispatcher offers endpoint scope (for all messages received or sent by the service) extensibility using the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[1402,1585],"source":"The EndpointDispatcher offers endpoint scope (for all messages received or sent by the service) extensibility using the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher> class."},{"content":"This class allows you to customize various properties that control the behavior of the EndpointDispatcher.","pos":[1586,1692]},{"content":"This sample focuses on the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A&gt;</ph> property that points to the object that provides the instances of the service class.","pos":[1693,1878],"source":" This sample focuses on the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A> property that points to the object that provides the instances of the service class."},{"pos":[1887,1904],"content":"IInstanceProvider","linkify":"IInstanceProvider","nodes":[{"content":"IInstanceProvider","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"In <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)]</ph>, the EndpointDispatcher creates instances of a service class by using an instance provider that implements the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider&gt;</ph> interface.","pos":[1908,2144],"source":"In [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)], the EndpointDispatcher creates instances of a service class by using an instance provider that implements the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> interface."},{"content":"This interface has only two methods:","pos":[2145,2181]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A&gt;</ph>: When a message arrives, the Dispatcher calls the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A&gt;</ph> method to create an instance of the service class to process the message.","pos":[2191,2456],"source":"<xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A>: When a message arrives, the Dispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method to create an instance of the service class to process the message."},{"content":"The frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[2457,2604],"source":" The frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property."},{"content":"For example if the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.InstanceContextMode?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>, a new instance of service class is created to process each message that arrives, so <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A&gt;</ph> is called whenever a message arrives.","pos":[2605,2983],"source":" For example if the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property is set to <xref:System.ServiceModel.InstanceContextMode?displayProperty=fullName>, a new instance of service class is created to process each message that arrives, so <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> is called whenever a message arrives."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A&gt;</ph>: When the service instance finishes processing the message, the EndpointDispatcher calls the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[2993,3243],"source":"<xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A>: When the service instance finishes processing the message, the EndpointDispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.ReleaseInstance%2A> method."},{"content":"As in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A&gt;</ph> method, the frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[3244,3480],"source":" As in the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method, the frequency of the calls to this method is determined by the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceBehaviorAttribute.InstanceContextMode%2A> property."},{"pos":[3489,3504],"content":"The Object Pool","linkify":"The Object Pool","nodes":[{"content":"The Object Pool","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ObjectPoolInstanceProvider`</ph> class contains the implementation for the object pool.","pos":[3508,3595],"source":"The `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` class contains the implementation for the object pool."},{"content":"This class implements the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider&gt;</ph> interface to interact with the service model layer.","pos":[3596,3729],"source":" This class implements the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> interface to interact with the service model layer."},{"content":"When the EndpointDispatcher calls the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A&gt;</ph> method, instead of creating a new instance, the custom implementation looks for an existing object in an in-memory pool.","pos":[3730,3959],"source":" When the EndpointDispatcher calls the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider.GetInstance%2A> method, instead of creating a new instance, the custom implementation looks for an existing object in an in-memory pool."},{"content":"If one is available, it is returned.","pos":[3960,3996]},{"content":"Otherwise, <ph id=\"ph1\">`ObjectPoolInstanceProvider`</ph> checks whether the <ph id=\"ph2\">`ActiveObjectsCount`</ph> property (number of objects returned from the pool) has reached the maximum pool size.","pos":[3997,4163],"source":" Otherwise, `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` checks whether the `ActiveObjectsCount` property (number of objects returned from the pool) has reached the maximum pool size."},{"content":"If not, a new instance is created and returned to the caller and <ph id=\"ph1\">`ActiveObjectsCount`</ph> is subsequently incremented.","pos":[4164,4278],"source":" If not, a new instance is created and returned to the caller and `ActiveObjectsCount` is subsequently incremented."},{"content":"Otherwise an object creation request is queued for a configured period of time.","pos":[4279,4358]},{"content":"The implementation for <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetObjectFromThePool`</ph> is shown in the following sample code.","pos":[4359,4443],"source":" The implementation for `GetObjectFromThePool` is shown in the following sample code."},{"content":"The custom <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReleaseInstance`</ph> implementation adds the released instance back to the pool and decrements the <ph id=\"ph2\">`ActiveObjectsCount`</ph> value.","pos":[5638,5772],"source":"The custom `ReleaseInstance` implementation adds the released instance back to the pool and decrements the `ActiveObjectsCount` value."},{"content":"The EndpointDispatcher can call these methods from different threads, and therefore synchronized access to the class level members in the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ObjectPoolInstanceProvider`</ph> class is required.","pos":[5773,5958],"source":" The EndpointDispatcher can call these methods from different threads, and therefore synchronized access to the class level members in the `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` class is required."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReleaseInstance`</ph> method provides a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>clean up initialization<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> feature.","pos":[7325,7399],"source":"The `ReleaseInstance` method provides a *clean up initialization* feature."},{"content":"Normally the pool maintains a minimum number of objects for the lifetime of the pool.","pos":[7400,7485]},{"content":"However, there can be periods of excessive usage that require creating additional objects in the pool to reach the maximum limit specified in the configuration.","pos":[7486,7646]},{"content":"Eventually when the pool becomes less active those surplus objects can become an extra overhead.","pos":[7647,7743]},{"content":"Therefore when the <ph id=\"ph1\">`activeObjectsCount`</ph> reaches zero an idle timer is started that triggers and performs a clean-up cycle.","pos":[7744,7866],"source":" Therefore when the `activeObjectsCount` reaches zero an idle timer is started that triggers and performs a clean-up cycle."},{"content":"ServiceModel layer extensions are hooked up using the following behaviors:","pos":[7956,8030]},{"content":"Service Behaviors: These allow for the customization of the entire service runtime.","pos":[8040,8123]},{"content":"Endpoint Behaviors: These allow for the customization of a particular service endpoint, including the EndpointDispatcher.","pos":[8133,8254]},{"content":"Contract Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientRuntime&gt;</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime&gt;</ph> classes on the client or the service respectively.","pos":[8264,8487],"source":"Contract Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientRuntime> or <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime> classes on the client or the service respectively."},{"content":"Operation Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientOperation&gt;</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchOperation&gt;</ph> classes on the client or the service respectively.","pos":[8497,8725],"source":"Operation Behaviors: These allow for the customization of either <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.ClientOperation> or <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchOperation> classes on the client or the service respectively."},{"content":"For the purpose of an object pooling extension, either an endpoint behavior or a service behavior can be created.","pos":[8732,8845]},{"content":"In this example, we use a service behavior, which applies object pooling ability to every endpoint of the service.","pos":[8846,8960]},{"content":"Service behaviors are created by implementing the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior&gt;</ph> interface.","pos":[8961,9077],"source":" Service behaviors are created by implementing the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> interface."},{"content":"There are several ways to make the ServiceModel aware of the custom behaviors:","pos":[9078,9156]},{"content":"Using a custom attribute.","pos":[9166,9191]},{"content":"Imperatively adding it to the service description’s behaviors collection.","pos":[9201,9274]},{"content":"Extending the configuration file.","pos":[9284,9317]},{"content":"This sample uses a custom attribute.","pos":[9324,9360]},{"content":"When the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost&gt;</ph> is constructed, it examines the attributes used in the service’s type definition and adds the available behaviors to the service description’s behaviors collection.","pos":[9361,9573],"source":" When the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> is constructed, it examines the attributes used in the service’s type definition and adds the available behaviors to the service description’s behaviors collection."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior&gt;</ph> interface has three methods: <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph3\">`,`</ph> <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph5\">`,`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph6\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[9580,9908],"source":"The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> interface has three methods: <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A>`,` <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A>`,` and <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A>."},{"content":"These methods are called by <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)]</ph> when the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost&gt;</ph> is being initialized.","pos":[9909,10062],"source":" These methods are called by [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] when the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHost> is being initialized."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> is called first; it allows the service to be inspected for inconsistencies.","pos":[10063,10231],"source":"<xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.Validate%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called first; it allows the service to be inspected for inconsistencies."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> is called next; this method is only required in very advanced scenarios.","pos":[10232,10409],"source":"<xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.AddBindingParameters%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called next; this method is only required in very advanced scenarios."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> is called last and is responsible for configuring the runtime.","pos":[10410,10578],"source":"<xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName> is called last and is responsible for configuring the runtime."},{"content":"The following parameters are passed into <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>:","pos":[10579,10726],"source":" The following parameters are passed into <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior.ApplyDispatchBehavior%2A?displayProperty=fullName>:"},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`Description`</ph>: This parameter provides the service description for the entire service.","pos":[10736,10822],"source":"`Description`: This parameter provides the service description for the entire service."},{"content":"This can be used to inspect description data about the service’s endpoints, contracts, bindings, and other data associated with the service.","pos":[10823,10963]},{"pos":[10973,11099],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`ServiceHostBase`</ph>: This parameter provides the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase&gt;</ph> that is currently being initialized.","source":"`ServiceHostBase`: This parameter provides the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase> that is currently being initialized."},{"pos":[11106,11490],"content":"In the custom <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior&gt;</ph> implementation, a new instance of <ph id=\"ph2\">`ObjectPoolInstanceProvider`</ph> is instantiated and assigned to the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A&gt;</ph> property in each <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher&gt;</ph> that is attached to the <ph id=\"ph5\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase&gt;</ph>.","source":"In the custom <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> implementation, a new instance of `ObjectPoolInstanceProvider` is instantiated and assigned to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.DispatchRuntime.InstanceProvider%2A> property in each <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.EndpointDispatcher> that is attached to the <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase>."},{"content":"In addition to an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior&gt;</ph> implementation the <ph id=\"ph2\">`ObjectPoolingAttribute`</ph> class has several members to customize the object pool using the attribute arguments.","pos":[12391,12594],"source":"In addition to an <xref:System.ServiceModel.Description.IServiceBehavior> implementation the `ObjectPoolingAttribute` class has several members to customize the object pool using the attribute arguments."},{"content":"These members include <ph id=\"ph1\">`MaxSize`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`MinSize`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph3\">`Enabled`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph4\">`CreationTimeout`</ph>, to match the object pooling feature set provided by .NET Enterprise Services.","pos":[12595,12749],"source":" These members include `MaxSize`, `MinSize`, `Enabled` and `CreationTimeout`, to match the object pooling feature set provided by .NET Enterprise Services."},{"pos":[12756,12967],"content":"The object pooling behavior can now be added to a <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)]</ph> service by annotating the service implementation with the newly created custom <ph id=\"ph2\">`ObjectPooling`</ph> attribute.","source":"The object pooling behavior can now be added to a [!INCLUDE[indigo2](../../../../includes/indigo2-md.md)] service by annotating the service implementation with the newly created custom `ObjectPooling` attribute."},{"pos":[13120,13155],"content":"Hooking Activation and Deactivation","linkify":"Hooking Activation and Deactivation","nodes":[{"content":"Hooking Activation and Deactivation","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"The primary objective of object pooling is to optimize short-lived objects with relatively expensive creation and initialization.","pos":[13159,13288]},{"content":"Therefore it can give a dramatic performance boost to an application if properly used.","pos":[13289,13375]},{"content":"Because the object is returned from the pool, the constructor is called only once.","pos":[13376,13458]},{"content":"However, some applications require some level of control so that they can initialize and clean-up the resources used during a single context.","pos":[13459,13600]},{"content":"For example, an object being used for a set of calculations can reset its private fields before processing the next calculation.","pos":[13601,13729]},{"content":"Enterprise Services enabled this kind of context-specific initialization by letting the object developer override <ph id=\"ph1\">`Activate`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`Deactivate`</ph> methods from the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent&gt;</ph> base class.","pos":[13730,13951],"source":" Enterprise Services enabled this kind of context-specific initialization by letting the object developer override `Activate` and `Deactivate` methods from the <xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent> base class."},{"content":"The object pool calls the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Activate`</ph> method just before returning the object from the pool.","pos":[13958,14049],"source":"The object pool calls the `Activate` method just before returning the object from the pool."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`Deactivate`</ph> is called when the object returns back to the pool.","pos":[14050,14114],"source":"`Deactivate` is called when the object returns back to the pool."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent&gt;</ph> base class also has a <ph id=\"ph2\">`boolean`</ph> property called <ph id=\"ph3\">`CanBePooled`</ph>, which can be used to notify the pool whether the object can be pooled further.","pos":[14115,14311],"source":" The <xref:System.EnterpriseServices.ServicedComponent> base class also has a `boolean` property called `CanBePooled`, which can be used to notify the pool whether the object can be pooled further."},{"content":"To mimic this functionality, the sample declares a public interface (<ph id=\"ph1\">`IObjectControl`</ph>) that has the aforementioned members.","pos":[14318,14441],"source":"To mimic this functionality, the sample declares a public interface (`IObjectControl`) that has the aforementioned members."},{"content":"This interface is then implemented by service classes intended to provide context specific initialization.","pos":[14442,14548]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider&gt;</ph> implementation must be modified to meet these requirements.","pos":[14549,14668],"source":" The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Dispatcher.IInstanceProvider> implementation must be modified to meet these requirements."},{"content":"Now, each time you get an object by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetInstance`</ph> method, you must check whether the object implements <ph id=\"ph2\">`IObjectControl.`</ph> If it does, you must call the <ph id=\"ph3\">`Activate`</ph> method appropriately.","pos":[14669,14864],"source":" Now, each time you get an object by calling the `GetInstance` method, you must check whether the object implements `IObjectControl.` If it does, you must call the `Activate` method appropriately."},{"pos":[14966,15097],"content":"When returning an object to the pool, a check is required for the <ph id=\"ph1\">`CanBePooled`</ph> property before adding the object back to the pool.","source":"When returning an object to the pool, a check is required for the `CanBePooled` property before adding the object back to the pool."},{"content":"Because the service developer can decide whether an object can be pooled, the object count in the pool at a given time can go below the minimum size.","pos":[15344,15493]},{"content":"Therefore you must check whether the object count has gone below the minimum level and perform the necessary initialization in the clean-up procedure.","pos":[15494,15644]},{"content":"When you run the sample, the operation requests and responses are displayed in both the service and client console windows.","pos":[15968,16091]},{"content":"Press Enter in each console window to shut down the service and client.","pos":[16092,16163]},{"pos":[16174,16210],"content":"To set up, build, and run the sample","linkify":"To set up, build, and run the sample","nodes":[{"content":"To set up, build, and run the sample","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[16220,16419],"content":"Ensure that you have performed the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md)</ept>.","source":"Ensure that you have performed the [One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md)."},{"pos":[16429,16599],"content":"To build the solution, follow the instructions in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md)</ept>.","source":"To build the solution, follow the instructions in [Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md)."},{"pos":[16609,16817],"content":"To run the sample in a single- or cross-machine configuration, follow the instructions in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Running the Windows Communication Foundation Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/running-the-samples.md)</ept>.","source":"To run the sample in a single- or cross-machine configuration, follow the instructions in [Running the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/running-the-samples.md)."},{"pos":[16825,16957],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\n The samples may already be installed on your machine. Check for the following (default) directory before continuing.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":" The samples may already be installed on your machine. Check for the following (default) directory before continuing.","pos":[13,130],"nodes":[{"content":"The samples may already be installed on your machine.","pos":[1,54]},{"content":"Check for the following (default) directory before continuing.","pos":[55,117]}]}]},{"content":"If this directory does not exist, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) and Windows Workflow Foundation (WF) Samples for .NET Framework 4<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=150780)</ept> to download all <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)]</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[wf1](../../../../includes/wf1-md.md)]</ph> samples.","pos":[17011,17337],"source":"If this directory does not exist, go to [Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) and Windows Workflow Foundation (WF) Samples for .NET Framework 4](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=150780) to download all [!INCLUDE[indigo1](../../../../includes/indigo1-md.md)] and [!INCLUDE[wf1](../../../../includes/wf1-md.md)] samples."},{"content":"This sample is located in the following directory.","pos":[17338,17388]},{"pos":[17484,17492],"content":"See Also","linkify":"See Also","nodes":[{"content":"See Also","pos":[0,8]}]}]}