{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords:\n  - \"Windows Workflow Foundation [WF], glossary\"\n  - \"WF [WF], glossary\"\nms.assetid: ab682b2f-3779-45ca-b831-b7c03d7dbb3a\n---\n\n# Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5\n\nThe following terms are used in the Windows Workflow Foundation documentation.\n\n## Terms\n\n|Term|Definition|\n|----------|----------------|\n|activity|A unit of program behavior in Windows Workflow Foundation. Single activities can be composed together into more complex activities.|\n|activity action|A data structure used to expose callbacks for workflow and activity execution.|\n|argument|Defines the data flow into and out of an activity. Each argument has a specified direction: in, out, or in/out. These represent the input, output, and input/output parameters of the activity.|\n|bookmark|The point at which an activity can pause and wait to be resumed.|\n|compensation|A group of actions designed to undo or mitigate the effect of previously completed work.|\n|correlation|The mechanism for routing messages to a workflow or service instance.|\n|expression|A construct that takes in one or more arguments, performs an operation on the arguments and returns a single value. Expressions can be used anywhere an activity can be used.|\n|flowchart|A well-known modeling paradigm that represents program components as symbols linked together with directional arrows.  In the .NET Framework 4, workflows can be modeled as flowcharts using the Flowchart activity.|\n|long-running process|A unit of program execution that does not return immediately and may span system restarts.|\n|persistence|Saving the state of a workflow or service to a durable medium, so that it can be unloaded from memory or recovered after a system failure.|\n|state machine|A well-known modeling paradigm that represents program components as individual states linked together with event-driven state transitions.  Workflows can be modeled as state machines using the StateMachine activity.|\n|substance|Represents a group of related bookmarks under a common identifier and allows the runtime to make decisions about whether a particular bookmark resumption is valid or may become valid.|\n|type converter|A CLR type can be associated with one or more System.ComponentModel.TypeConverter derived types that enable converting instances of the CLR type to and from instances of other types. A type converter is associated with a CLR type using the System.ComponentModel.TypeConverterAttribute attribute.  A TypeConverterAttribute can be specified directly on the CLR type or on a property. A type converter specified on a property always takes precedence over a type converter specified on the CLR type of the property.|\n|variable|Represents the storage of some data that must be saved and accessed later.|\n|workflow|A single activity or tree of activities invoked by a host process.|\n|XAML|eXtensible Application Markup Language|\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,237],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords:\n  - \"Windows Workflow Foundation [WF], glossary\"\n  - \"WF [WF], glossary\"\nms.assetid: ab682b2f-3779-45ca-b831-b7c03d7dbb3a","nodes":[{"content":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","nodes":[{"pos":[0,59],"content":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","nodes":[{"content":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","pos":[0,59]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[245,304],"content":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","linkify":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","nodes":[{"content":"Windows Workflow Foundation Glossary for .NET Framework 4.5","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"The following terms are used in the Windows Workflow Foundation documentation.","pos":[306,384]},{"pos":[389,394],"content":"Terms","linkify":"Terms","nodes":[{"content":"Terms","pos":[0,5]}]},{"content":"Term","pos":[397,401]},{"content":"Definition","pos":[402,412]},{"content":"activity","pos":[445,453]},{"content":"A unit of program behavior in Windows Workflow Foundation.","pos":[454,512]},{"content":"Single activities can be composed together into more complex activities.","pos":[513,585]},{"content":"activity action","pos":[588,603]},{"content":"A data structure used to expose callbacks for workflow and activity execution.","pos":[604,682]},{"content":"argument","pos":[685,693]},{"content":"Defines the data flow into and out of an activity.","pos":[694,744]},{"content":"Each argument has a specified direction: in, out, or in/out. These represent the input, output, and input/output parameters of the activity.","pos":[745,885]},{"content":"bookmark","pos":[888,896]},{"content":"The point at which an activity can pause and wait to be resumed.","pos":[897,961]},{"content":"compensation","pos":[964,976]},{"content":"A group of actions designed to undo or mitigate the effect of previously completed work.","pos":[977,1065]},{"content":"correlation","pos":[1068,1079]},{"content":"The mechanism for routing messages to a workflow or service instance.","pos":[1080,1149]},{"content":"expression","pos":[1152,1162]},{"content":"A construct that takes in one or more arguments, performs an operation on the arguments and returns a single value.","pos":[1163,1278]},{"content":"Expressions can be used anywhere an activity can be used.","pos":[1279,1336]},{"content":"flowchart","pos":[1339,1348]},{"content":"A well-known modeling paradigm that represents program components as symbols linked together with directional arrows.","pos":[1349,1466]},{"content":"In the .NET Framework 4, workflows can be modeled as flowcharts using the Flowchart activity.","pos":[1468,1561]},{"content":"long-running process","pos":[1564,1584]},{"content":"A unit of program execution that does not return immediately and may span system restarts.","pos":[1585,1675]},{"content":"persistence","pos":[1678,1689]},{"content":"Saving the state of a workflow or service to a durable medium, so that it can be unloaded from memory or recovered after a system failure.","pos":[1690,1828]},{"content":"state machine","pos":[1831,1844]},{"content":"A well-known modeling paradigm that represents program components as individual states linked together with event-driven state transitions.","pos":[1845,1984]},{"content":"Workflows can be modeled as state machines using the StateMachine activity.","pos":[1986,2061]},{"content":"substance","pos":[2064,2073]},{"content":"Represents a group of related bookmarks under a common identifier and allows the runtime to make decisions about whether a particular bookmark resumption is valid or may become valid.","pos":[2074,2257]},{"content":"type converter","pos":[2260,2274]},{"content":"A CLR type can be associated with one or more System.ComponentModel.TypeConverter derived types that enable converting instances of the CLR type to and from instances of other types.","pos":[2275,2457]},{"content":"A type converter is associated with a CLR type using the System.ComponentModel.TypeConverterAttribute attribute.","pos":[2458,2570]},{"content":"A TypeConverterAttribute can be specified directly on the CLR type or on a property.","pos":[2572,2656]},{"content":"A type converter specified on a property always takes precedence over a type converter specified on the CLR type of the property.","pos":[2657,2786]},{"content":"variable","pos":[2789,2797]},{"content":"Represents the storage of some data that must be saved and accessed later.","pos":[2798,2872]},{"content":"workflow","pos":[2875,2883]},{"content":"A single activity or tree of activities invoked by a host process.","pos":[2884,2950]},{"content":"XAML","pos":[2953,2957]},{"content":"eXtensible Application Markup Language","pos":[2958,2996]}]}