{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: dotnet-standard\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \".NET Framework regular expressions, best practices\"\n  - \"regular expressions, best practices\"\nms.assetid: 618e5afb-3a97-440d-831a-70e4c526a51c\ncaps.latest.revision: 15\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"\nmanager: \"wpickett\"\n---\n# Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET\n<a name=\"top\"></a> The regular expression engine in .NET is a powerful, full-featured tool that processes text based on pattern matches rather than on comparing and matching literal text. In most cases, it performs pattern matching rapidly and efficiently. However, in some cases, the regular expression engine can appear to be very slow. In extreme cases, it can even appear to stop responding as it processes a relatively small input over the course of hours or even days.  \n  \n This topic outlines some of the best practices that developers can adopt to ensure that their regular expressions achieve optimal performance. It contains the following sections:  \n  \n-   [Consider the Input Source](#InputSource)  \n  \n-   [Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately](#ObjectInstantiation)  \n  \n-   [Take Charge of Backtracking](#Backtracking)  \n  \n-   [Use Time-out Values](#Timeouts)  \n  \n-   [Capture Only When Necessary](#Capture)  \n  \n-   [Related Topics](#RelatedTopics)  \n  \n<a name=\"InputSource\"></a>   \n## Consider the Input Source  \n In general, regular expressions can accept two types of input: constrained or unconstrained. Constrained input is text that originates from a known or reliable source and follows a predefined format. Unconstrained input is text that originates from an unreliable source, such as a web user, and may not follow a predefined or expected format.  \n  \n Regular expression patterns are typically written to match valid input. That is, developers examine the text that they want to match and then write a regular expression pattern that matches it. Developers then determine whether this pattern requires correction or further elaboration by testing it with multiple valid input items. When the pattern matches all presumed valid inputs, it is declared to be production-ready and can be included in a released application. This makes a regular expression pattern suitable for matching constrained input. However, it does not make it suitable for matching unconstrained input.  \n  \n To match unconstrained input, a regular expression must be able to efficiently handle three kinds of text:  \n  \n-   Text that matches the regular expression pattern.  \n  \n-   Text that does not match the regular expression pattern.  \n  \n-   Text that nearly matches the regular expression pattern.  \n  \n The last text type is especially problematic for a regular expression that has been written to handle constrained input. If that regular expression also relies on extensive [backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md), the regular expression engine can spend an inordinate amount of time (in some cases, many hours or days) processing seemingly innocuous text.  \n  \n> [!WARNING]\n>  The following example uses a regular expression that is prone to excessive backtracking and that is likely to reject valid email addresses. You should not use it in an email validation routine. If you would like a regular expression that validates email addresses, see [How to: Verify that Strings Are in Valid Email Format](../../../docs/standard/base-types/how-to-verify-that-strings-are-in-valid-email-format.md).  \n  \n For example, consider a very commonly used but extremely problematic regular expression for validating the alias of an email address. The regular expression `^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*$` is written to process what is considered to be a valid email address, which consists of an alphanumeric character, followed by zero or more characters that can be alphanumeric, periods, or hyphens. The regular expression must end with an alphanumeric character. However, as the following example shows, although this regular expression handles valid input easily, its performance is very inefficient when it is processing nearly valid input.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/design2.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/design2.vb#1)]  \n  \n As the output from the example shows, the regular expression engine processes the valid email alias in about the same time interval regardless of its length. On the other hand, when the nearly valid email address has more than five characters, processing time approximately doubles for each additional character in the string. This means that a nearly valid 28-character string would take over an hour to process, and a nearly valid 33-character string would take nearly a day to process.  \n  \n Because this regular expression was developed solely by considering the format of input to be matched, it fails to take account of input that does not match the pattern. This, in turn, can allow unconstrained input that nearly matches the regular expression pattern to significantly degrade performance.  \n  \n To solve this problem, you can do the following:  \n  \n-   When developing a pattern, you should consider how backtracking might affect the performance of the regular expression engine, particularly if your regular expression is designed to process unconstrained input. For more information, see the [Take Charge of Backtracking](#Backtracking) section.  \n  \n-   Thoroughly test your regular expression using invalid and near-valid input as well as valid input. To generate input for a particular regular expression randomly, you can use [Rex](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=210756), which is a regular expression exploration tool from Microsoft Research.  \n  \n [Back to top](#top)  \n  \n<a name=\"ObjectInstantiation\"></a>   \n## Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately  \n At the heart of .NET’s regular expression object model is the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex?displayProperty=fullName> class, which represents the regular expression engine. Often, the single greatest factor that affects regular expression performance is the way in which the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> engine is used. Defining a regular expression involves tightly coupling the regular expression engine with a regular expression pattern. That coupling process, whether it involves instantiating a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object by passing its constructor a regular expression pattern or calling a static method by passing it the regular expression pattern along with the string to be analyzed, is by necessity an expensive one.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  For a more detailed discussion of the performance implications of using interpreted and compiled regular expressions, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211566) in the BCL Team blog.  \n  \n You can couple the regular expression engine with a particular regular expression pattern and then use the engine to match text in several ways:  \n  \n-   You can call a static pattern-matching method, such as <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName>. This does not require instantiation of a regular expression object.  \n  \n-   You can instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of an interpreted regular expression. This is the default method for binding the regular expression engine to a regular expression pattern. It results when a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is instantiated without an `options` argument that includes the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag.  \n  \n-   You can instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of a compiled regular expression. Regular expression objects represent compiled patterns when a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is instantiated with an `options` argument that includes the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag.  \n  \n-   You can create a special-purpose <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object that is tightly coupled with a particular regular expression pattern, compile it, and save it to a standalone assembly. You do this by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method.  \n  \n The particular way in which you call regular expression matching methods can have a significant impact on your application. The following sections discuss when to use static method calls, interpreted regular expressions, and compiled regular expressions to improve your application's performance.  \n  \n> [!IMPORTANT]\n>  The form of the method call (static, interpreted, compiled) affects performance if the same regular expression is used repeatedly in method calls, or if an application makes extensive use of regular expression objects.  \n  \n### Static Regular Expressions  \n Static regular expression methods are recommended as an alternative to repeatedly instantiating a regular expression object with the same regular expression. Unlike regular expression patterns used by regular expression objects, either the operation codes or the compiled Microsoft intermediate language (MSIL) from patterns used in instance method calls is cached internally by the regular expression engine.  \n  \n For example, an event handler frequently calls another method to validate user input. This is reflected in the following code, in which a <xref:System.Windows.Forms.Button> control's <xref:System.Windows.Forms.Control.Click> event is used to call a method named `IsValidCurrency`, which checks whether the user has entered a currency symbol followed by at least one decimal digit.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#2)]  \n  \n A very inefficient implementation of the `IsValidCurrency` method is shown in the following example. Note that each method call reinstantiates a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object with the same pattern. This, in turn, means that the regular expression pattern must be recompiled each time the method is called.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#3)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#3)]  \n  \n You should replace this inefficient code with a call to the static <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName> method. This eliminates the need to instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object each time you want to call a pattern-matching method, and enables the regular expression engine to retrieve a compiled version of the regular expression from its cache.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static2.cs#4)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static2.vb#4)]  \n  \n By default, the last 15 most recently used static regular expression patterns are cached. For applications that require a larger number of cached static regular expressions, the size of the cache can be adjusted by setting the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CacheSize%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property.  \n  \n The regular expression `\\p{Sc}+\\s*\\d+` that is used in this example verifies that the input string consists of a currency symbol and at least one decimal digit. The pattern is defined as shown in the following table.  \n  \n|Pattern|Description|  \n|-------------|-----------------|  \n|`\\p{Sc}+`|Match one or more characters in the Unicode Symbol, Currency category.|  \n|`\\s*`|Match zero or more white-space characters.|  \n|`\\d+`|Match one or more decimal digits.|  \n  \n<a name=\"Interpreted\"></a>   \n### Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions  \n Regular expression patterns that are not bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option are interpreted. When a regular expression object is instantiated, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to a set of operation codes. When an instance method is called, the operation codes are converted to MSIL and executed by the JIT compiler. Similarly, when a static regular expression method is called and the regular expression cannot be found in the cache, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to a set of operation codes and stores them in the cache. It then converts these operation codes to MSIL so that the JIT compiler can execute them. Interpreted regular expressions reduce startup time at the cost of slower execution time. Because of this, they are best used when the regular expression is used in a small number of method calls, or if the exact number of calls to regular expression methods is unknown but is expected to be small. As the number of method calls increases, the performance gain from reduced startup time is outstripped by the slower execution speed.  \n  \n Regular expression patterns that are bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option are compiled. This means that, when a regular expression object is instantiated, or when a static regular expression method is called and the regular expression cannot be found in the cache, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to an intermediary set of operation codes, which it then converts to MSIL. When a method is called, the JIT compiler executes the MSIL. In contrast to interpreted regular expressions, compiled regular expressions increase startup time but execute individual pattern-matching methods faster. As a result, the performance benefit that results from compiling the regular expression increases in proportion to the number of regular expression methods called.  \n  \n To summarize, we recommend that you use interpreted regular expressions when you call regular expression methods with a specific regular expression relatively infrequently. You should use compiled regular expressions when you call regular expression methods with a specific regular expression relatively frequently. The exact threshold at which the slower execution speeds of interpreted regular expressions outweigh gains from their reduced startup time, or the threshold at which the slower startup times of compiled regular expressions outweigh gains from their faster execution speeds, is difficult to determine. It depends on a variety of factors, including the complexity of the regular expression and the specific data that it processes. To determine whether interpreted or compiled regular expressions offer the best performance for your particular application scenario, you can use the <xref:System.Diagnostics.Stopwatch> class to compare their execution times.  \n  \n The following example compares the performance of compiled and interpreted regular expressions when reading the first ten sentences and when reading all the sentences in the text of Theodore Dreiser's *The Financier*. As the output from the example shows, when only ten calls are made to regular expression matching methods, an interpreted regular expression offers better performance than a compiled regular expression. However, a compiled regular expression offers better performance when a large number of calls (in this case, over 13,000) are made.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compare1.cs#5)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compare1.vb#5)]  \n  \n The regular expression pattern used in the example, `\\b(\\w+((\\r?\\n)|,?\\s))*\\w+[.?:;!]`, is defined as shown in the following table.  \n  \n|Pattern|Description|  \n|-------------|-----------------|  \n|`\\b`|Begin the match at a word boundary.|  \n|`\\w+`|Match one or more word characters.|  \n|`(\\r?\\n)&#124;,?\\s)`|Match either zero or one carriage return followed by a newline character, or zero or one comma followed by a white-space character.|  \n|`(\\w+((\\r?\\n)&#124;,?\\s))*`|Match zero or more occurrences of one or more word characters that are followed either by zero or one carriage return and a newline character, or by zero or one comma followed by a white-space character.|  \n|`\\w+`|Match one or more word characters.|  \n|`[.?:;!]`|Match a period, question mark, colon, semicolon, or exclamation point.|  \n  \n### Regular Expressions: Compiled to an Assembly  \n .NET also enables you to create an assembly that contains compiled regular expressions. This moves the performance hit of regular expression compilation from run time to design time. However, it also involves some additional work: You must define the regular expressions in advance and compile them to an assembly. The compiler can then reference this assembly when compiling source code that uses the assembly’s regular expressions. Each compiled regular expression in the assembly is represented by a class that derives from <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex>.  \n  \n To compile regular expressions to an assembly, you call the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%28System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo%5B%5D%2CSystem.Reflection.AssemblyName%29?displayProperty=fullName> method and pass it an array of <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo> objects that represent the regular expressions to be compiled, and an <xref:System.Reflection.AssemblyName> object that contains information about the assembly to be created.  \n  \n We recommend that you compile regular expressions to an assembly in the following situations:  \n  \n-   If you are a component developer who wants to create a library of reusable regular expressions.  \n  \n-   If you expect your regular expression's pattern-matching methods to be called an indeterminate number of times -- anywhere from once or twice to thousands or tens of thousands of times. Unlike compiled or interpreted regular expressions, regular expressions that are compiled to separate assemblies offer performance that is consistent regardless of the number of method calls.  \n  \n If you are using compiled regular expressions to optimize performance, you should not use reflection to create the assembly, load the regular expression engine, and execute its pattern-matching methods. This requires that you avoid building regular expression patterns dynamically, and that you specify any pattern-matching options (such as case-insensitive pattern matching) at the time the assembly is created. It also requires that you separate the code that creates the assembly from the code that uses the regular expression.  \n  \n The following example shows how to create an assembly that contains a compiled regular expression. It creates an assembly named `RegexLib.dll` with a single regular expression class, `SentencePattern`, that contains the sentence-matching regular expression pattern used in the [Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions](#Interpreted) section.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile1.cs#6)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile1.vb#6)]  \n  \n When the example is compiled to an executable and run, it creates an assembly named `RegexLib.dll`. The regular expression is represented by a class named `Utilities.RegularExpressions.SentencePattern` that is derived from <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex>. The following example then uses the compiled regular expression to extract the sentences from the text of Theodore Dreiser's *The Financier*.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile2.cs#7)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile2.vb#7)]  \n  \n [Back to top](#top)  \n  \n<a name=\"Backtracking\"></a>   \n## Take Charge of Backtracking  \n Ordinarily, the regular expression engine uses linear progression to move through an input string and compare it to a regular expression pattern. However, when indeterminate quantifiers such as `*`, `+`, and `?` are used in a regular expression pattern, the regular expression engine may give up a portion of successful partial matches and return to a previously saved state in order to search for a successful match for the entire pattern. This process is known as backtracking.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  For more information on backtracking, see [Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md) and [Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md). For a detailed discussion of backtracking, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211567) in the BCL Team blog.  \n  \n Support for backtracking gives regular expressions power and flexibility. It also places the responsibility for controlling the operation of the regular expression engine in the hands of regular expression developers. Because developers are often not aware of this responsibility, their misuse of backtracking or reliance on excessive backtracking often plays the most significant role in degrading regular expression performance. In a worst-case scenario, execution time can double for each additional character in the input string. In fact, by using backtracking excessively, it is easy to create the programmatic equivalent of an endless loop if input nearly matches the regular expression pattern; the regular expression engine may take hours or even days to process a relatively short input string.  \n  \n Often, applications pay a performance penalty for using backtracking despite the fact that backtracking is not essential for a match. For example, the regular expression `\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b` matches all words that begin with an uppercase character, as the following table shows.  \n  \n|Pattern|Description|  \n|-|-|  \n|`\\b`|Begin the match at a word boundary.|  \n|`\\p{Lu}`|Match an uppercase character.|  \n|`\\w*`|Match zero or more word characters.|  \n|`\\b`|End the match at a word boundary.|  \n  \n Because a word boundary is not the same as, or a subset of, a word character, there is no possibility that the regular expression engine will cross a word boundary when matching word characters. This means that for this regular expression, backtracking can never contribute to the overall success of any match -- it can only degrade performance, because the regular expression engine is forced to save its state for each successful preliminary match of a word character.  \n  \n If you determine that backtracking is not necessary, you can disable it by using the `(?>``subexpression``)` language element. The following example parses an input string by using two regular expressions. The first, `\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b`, relies on backtracking. The second, `\\b\\p{Lu}(?>\\w*)\\b`, disables backtracking. As the output from the example shows, they both produce the same result.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack2.cs#10)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack2.vb#10)]  \n  \n In many cases, backtracking is essential for matching a regular expression pattern to input text. However, excessive backtracking can severely degrade performance and create the impression that an application has stopped responding. In particular, this happens when quantifiers are nested and the text that matches the outer subexpression is a subset of the text that matches the inner subexpression.  \n  \n> [!WARNING]\n>  In addition to avoiding excessive backtracking, you should use the timeout feature to ensure that excessive backtracking does not severely degrade regular expression performance. For more information, see the [Use Timeout Values](#Timeouts) section.  \n  \n For example, the regular expression pattern `^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*\\$$` is intended to match a part number that consists of at least one alphanumeric character. Any additional characters can consist of an alphanumeric character, a hyphen, an underscore, or a period, though the last character must be alphanumeric. A dollar sign terminates the part number. In some cases, this regular expression pattern can exhibit extremely poor performance because quantifiers are nested, and because the subexpression `[0-9A-Z]` is a subset of the subexpression `[-.\\w]*`.  \n  \n In these cases, you can optimize regular expression performance by removing the nested quantifiers and replacing the outer subexpression with a zero-width lookahead or lookbehind assertion. Lookahead and lookbehind assertions are anchors; they do not move the pointer in the input string, but instead look ahead or behind to check whether a specified condition is met. For example, the part number regular expression can be rewritten as `^[0-9A-Z][-.\\w]*(?<=[0-9A-Z])\\$$`. This regular expression pattern is defined as shown in the following table.  \n  \n|Pattern|Description|  \n|-------------|-----------------|  \n|`^`|Begin the match at the beginning of the input string.|  \n|`[0-9A-Z]`|Match an alphanumeric character. The part number must consist of at least this character.|  \n|`[-.\\w]*`|Match zero or more occurrences of any word character, hyphen, or period.|  \n|`\\$`|Match a dollar sign.|  \n|`(?<=[0-9A-Z])`|Look ahead of the ending dollar sign to ensure that the previous character is alphanumeric.|  \n|`$`|End the match at the end of the input string.|  \n  \n The following example illustrates the use of this regular expression to match an array containing possible part numbers.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack4.cs#11)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack4.vb#11)]  \n  \n The regular expression language in .NET includes the following language elements that you can use to eliminate nested quantifiers. For more information, see [Grouping Constructs](../../../docs/standard/base-types/grouping-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md).  \n  \n|Language element|Description|  \n|----------------------|-----------------|  \n|`(?=` `subexpression` `)`|Zero-width positive lookahead. Look ahead of the current position to determine whether `subexpression` matches the input string.|  \n|`(?!` `subexpression` `)`|Zero-width negative lookahead. Look ahead of the current position to determine whether `subexpression` does not match the input string.|  \n|`(?<=` `subexpression` `)`|Zero-width positive lookbehind. Look behind the current position to determine whether `subexpression` matches the input string.|  \n|`(?<!` `subexpression` `)`|Zero-width negative lookbehind. Look behind the current position to determine whether `subexpression` does not match the input string.|  \n  \n [Back to top](#top)  \n  \n<a name=\"Timeouts\"></a>   \n## Use Time-out Values  \n If your regular expressions processes input that nearly matches the regular expression pattern, it can often rely on excessive backtracking, which impacts its performance significantly. In addition to carefully considering your use of backtracking and testing the regular expression against near-matching input, you should always set a time-out value to ensure that the impact of excessive backtracking, if it occurs, is minimized.  \n  \n The regular expression time-out interval defines the period of time that the regular expression engine will look for a single match before it times out. The default time-out interval is <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.InfiniteMatchTimeout?displayProperty=fullName>, which means that the regular expression will not time out. You can override this value and define a time-out interval as follows:  \n  \n-   By providing a time-out value when you instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.%23ctor%28System.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName> constructor.  \n  \n-   By calling a static pattern matching method, such as <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName> or <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName>, that includes a `matchTimeout` parameter.  \n  \n-   For compiled regular expressions that are created by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method, by calling the constructor that has a parameter of type <xref:System.TimeSpan>.  \n  \n If you have defined a time-out interval and a match is not found at the end of that interval, the regular expression method throws a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexMatchTimeoutException> exception. In your exception handler, you can choose to retry the match with a longer time-out interval, abandon the match attempt and assume that there is no match, or abandon the match attempt and log the exception information for future analysis.  \n  \n The following example defines a `GetWordData` method that instantiates a regular expression with a time-out interval of 350 milliseconds to calculate the number of words and average number of characters in a word in a text document. If the matching operation times out, the time-out interval is increased by 350 milliseconds and the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is re-instantiated. If the new time-out interval exceeds 1 second, the method re-throws the exception to the caller.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/timeout1.cs#12)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/timeout1.vb#12)]  \n  \n [Back to top](#top)  \n  \n<a name=\"Capture\"></a>   \n## Capture Only When Necessary  \n Regular expressions in .NET support a number of grouping constructs, which let you group a regular expression pattern into one or more subexpressions. The most commonly used grouping constructs in .NET regular expression language are `(`*subexpression*`)`, which defines a numbered capturing group, and `(?<`*name*`>`*subexpression*`)`, which defines a named capturing group. Grouping constructs are essential for creating backreferences and for defining a subexpression to which a quantifier is applied.  \n  \n However, the use of these language elements has a cost. They cause the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> object returned by the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to be populated with the most recent unnamed or named captures, and if a single grouping construct has captured multiple substrings in the input string, they also populate the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> object returned by the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property of a particular capturing group with multiple <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Capture> objects.  \n  \n Often, grouping constructs are used in a regular expression only so that quantifiers can be applied to them, and the groups captured by these subexpressions are not subsequently used. For example, the regular expression `\\b(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]` is designed to capture an entire sentence. The following table describes the language elements in this regular expression pattern and their effect on the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match> object's <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName> collections.  \n  \n|Pattern|Description|  \n|-------------|-----------------|  \n|`\\b`|Begin the match at a word boundary.|  \n|`\\w+`|Match one or more word characters.|  \n|`[;,]?`|Match zero or one comma or semicolon.|  \n|`\\s?`|Match zero or one white-space character.|  \n|`(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+`|Match one or more occurrences of one or more word characters followed by an optional comma or semicolon followed by an optional white-space character. This defines the first capturing group, which is necessary so that the combination of multiple word characters (that is, a word) followed by an optional punctuation symbol will be repeated until the regular expression engine reaches the end of a sentence.|  \n|`[.?!]`|Match a period, question mark, or exclamation point.|  \n  \n As the following example shows, when a match is found, both the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> objects are populated with captures from the match. In this case, the capturing group `(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)` exists so that the `+` quantifier can be applied to it, which enables the regular expression pattern to match each word in a sentence. Otherwise, it would match the last word in a sentence.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group1.cs#8)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group1.vb#8)]  \n  \n When you use subexpressions only to apply quantifiers to them, and you are not interested in the captured text, you should disable group captures. For example, the `(?:``subexpression``)` language element prevents the group to which it applies from capturing matched substrings. In the following example, the regular expression pattern from the previous example is changed to `\\b(?:\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]`. As the output shows, it prevents the regular expression engine from populating the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> collections.  \n  \n [!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group2.cs#9)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group2.vb#9)]  \n  \n You can disable captures in one of the following ways:  \n  \n-   Use the `(?:``subexpression``)` language element. This element prevents the capture of matched substrings in the group to which it applies. It does not disable substring captures in any nested groups.  \n  \n-   Use the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option. It disables all unnamed or implicit captures in the regular expression pattern. When you use this option, only substrings that match named groups defined with the `(?<``name``>``subexpression``)` language element can be captured. The <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag can be passed to the `options` parameter of a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> class constructor or to the `options` parameter of a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> static matching method.  \n  \n-   Use the `n` option in the `(?imnsx)` language element. This option disables all unnamed or implicit captures from the point in the regular expression pattern at which the element appears. Captures are disabled either until the end of the pattern or until the `(-n)` option enables unnamed or implicit captures. For more information, see [Miscellaneous Constructs](../../../docs/standard/base-types/miscellaneous-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md).  \n  \n-   Use the `n` option in the `(?imnsx:``subexpression``)` language element. This option disables all unnamed or implicit captures in `subexpression`. Captures by any unnamed or implicit nested capturing groups are disabled as well.  \n  \n [Back to top](#top)  \n  \n<a name=\"RelatedTopics\"></a>   \n## Related Topics  \n  \n|Title|Description|  \n|-----------|-----------------|  \n|[Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md)|Examines the implementation of the regular expression engine in .NET. The topic focuses on the flexibility of regular expressions and explains the developer's responsibility for ensuring the efficient and robust operation of the regular expression engine.|  \n|[Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)|Explains what backtracking is and how it affects regular expression performance, and examines language elements that provide alternatives to backtracking.|  \n|[Regular Expression Language - Quick Reference](../../../docs/standard/base-types/regular-expression-language-quick-reference.md)|Describes the elements of the regular expression language in .NET and provides links to detailed documentation for each language element.|","nodes":[{"pos":[4,481],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: dotnet-standard\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \".NET Framework regular expressions, best practices\"\n  - \"regular expressions, best practices\"\nms.assetid: 618e5afb-3a97-440d-831a-70e4c526a51c\ncaps.latest.revision: 15\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"\nmanager: \"wpickett\"","nodes":[{"content":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"pos":[0,63],"content":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"content":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,63]}]}],"path":["title"]}],"yml":true},{"pos":[488,534],"content":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET","linkify":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET","nodes":[{"content":"Best Practices for Regular Expressions in .NET","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a name=\"top\"&gt;</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept> The regular expression engine in .NET is a powerful, full-featured tool that processes text based on pattern matches rather than on comparing and matching literal text.","pos":[535,722],"source":"<a name=\"top\"></a> The regular expression engine in .NET is a powerful, full-featured tool that processes text based on pattern matches rather than on comparing and matching literal text."},{"content":"In most cases, it performs pattern matching rapidly and efficiently.","pos":[723,791]},{"content":"However, in some cases, the regular expression engine can appear to be very slow.","pos":[792,873]},{"content":"In extreme cases, it can even appear to stop responding as it processes a relatively small input over the course of hours or even days.","pos":[874,1009]},{"content":"This topic outlines some of the best practices that developers can adopt to ensure that their regular expressions achieve optimal performance.","pos":[1016,1158]},{"content":"It contains the following sections:","pos":[1159,1194]},{"pos":[1204,1245],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Consider the Input Source<ept id=\"p1\">](#InputSource)</ept>","source":"[Consider the Input Source](#InputSource)"},{"pos":[1255,1320],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately<ept id=\"p1\">](#ObjectInstantiation)</ept>","source":"[Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately](#ObjectInstantiation)"},{"pos":[1330,1374],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Take Charge of Backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](#Backtracking)</ept>","source":"[Take Charge of Backtracking](#Backtracking)"},{"pos":[1384,1416],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use Time-out Values<ept id=\"p1\">](#Timeouts)</ept>","source":"[Use Time-out Values](#Timeouts)"},{"pos":[1426,1465],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Capture Only When Necessary<ept id=\"p1\">](#Capture)</ept>","source":"[Capture Only When Necessary](#Capture)"},{"pos":[1475,1507],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Related Topics<ept id=\"p1\">](#RelatedTopics)</ept>","source":"[Related Topics](#RelatedTopics)"},{"pos":[1546,1571],"content":"Consider the Input Source","linkify":"Consider the Input Source","nodes":[{"content":"Consider the Input Source","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"In general, regular expressions can accept two types of input: constrained or unconstrained.","pos":[1575,1667]},{"content":"Constrained input is text that originates from a known or reliable source and follows a predefined format.","pos":[1668,1774]},{"content":"Unconstrained input is text that originates from an unreliable source, such as a web user, and may not follow a predefined or expected format.","pos":[1775,1917]},{"content":"Regular expression patterns are typically written to match valid input.","pos":[1924,1995]},{"content":"That is, developers examine the text that they want to match and then write a regular expression pattern that matches it.","pos":[1996,2117]},{"content":"Developers then determine whether this pattern requires correction or further elaboration by testing it with multiple valid input items.","pos":[2118,2254]},{"content":"When the pattern matches all presumed valid inputs, it is declared to be production-ready and can be included in a released application.","pos":[2255,2391]},{"content":"This makes a regular expression pattern suitable for matching constrained input.","pos":[2392,2472]},{"content":"However, it does not make it suitable for matching unconstrained input.","pos":[2473,2544]},{"content":"To match unconstrained input, a regular expression must be able to efficiently handle three kinds of text:","pos":[2551,2657]},{"content":"Text that matches the regular expression pattern.","pos":[2667,2716]},{"content":"Text that does not match the regular expression pattern.","pos":[2726,2782]},{"content":"Text that nearly matches the regular expression pattern.","pos":[2792,2848]},{"content":"The last text type is especially problematic for a regular expression that has been written to handle constrained input.","pos":[2855,2975]},{"content":"If that regular expression also relies on extensive <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)</ept>, the regular expression engine can spend an inordinate amount of time (in some cases, many hours or days) processing seemingly innocuous text.","pos":[2976,3259],"source":" If that regular expression also relies on extensive [backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md), the regular expression engine can spend an inordinate amount of time (in some cases, many hours or days) processing seemingly innocuous text."},{"pos":[3267,3697],"content":"[!WARNING]\n The following example uses a regular expression that is prone to excessive backtracking and that is likely to reject valid email addresses. You should not use it in an email validation routine. If you would like a regular expression that validates email addresses, see [How to: Verify that Strings Are in Valid Email Format](../../../docs/standard/base-types/how-to-verify-that-strings-are-in-valid-email-format.md).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The following example uses a regular expression that is prone to excessive backtracking and that is likely to reject valid email addresses. You should not use it in an email validation routine. If you would like a regular expression that validates email addresses, see [How to: Verify that Strings Are in Valid Email Format](../../../docs/standard/base-types/how-to-verify-that-strings-are-in-valid-email-format.md).","pos":[12,428],"nodes":[{"content":"The following example uses a regular expression that is prone to excessive backtracking and that is likely to reject valid email addresses.","pos":[0,139]},{"content":"You should not use it in an email validation routine.","pos":[140,193]},{"content":"If you would like a regular expression that validates email addresses, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Verify that Strings Are in Valid Email Format<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/how-to-verify-that-strings-are-in-valid-email-format.md)</ept>.","pos":[194,416],"source":" If you would like a regular expression that validates email addresses, see [How to: Verify that Strings Are in Valid Email Format](../../../docs/standard/base-types/how-to-verify-that-strings-are-in-valid-email-format.md)."}]}]},{"content":"For example, consider a very commonly used but extremely problematic regular expression for validating the alias of an email address.","pos":[3704,3837]},{"content":"The regular expression <ph id=\"ph1\">`^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*$`</ph> is written to process what is considered to be a valid email address, which consists of an alphanumeric character, followed by zero or more characters that can be alphanumeric, periods, or hyphens.","pos":[3838,4089],"source":" The regular expression `^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*$` is written to process what is considered to be a valid email address, which consists of an alphanumeric character, followed by zero or more characters that can be alphanumeric, periods, or hyphens."},{"content":"The regular expression must end with an alphanumeric character.","pos":[4090,4153]},{"content":"However, as the following example shows, although this regular expression handles valid input easily, its performance is very inefficient when it is processing nearly valid input.","pos":[4154,4333]},{"pos":[4340,4685],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/design2.cs#1)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/design2.vb#1)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/design2.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/design2.vb#1)]"},{"content":"As the output from the example shows, the regular expression engine processes the valid email alias in about the same time interval regardless of its length.","pos":[4692,4849]},{"content":"On the other hand, when the nearly valid email address has more than five characters, processing time approximately doubles for each additional character in the string.","pos":[4850,5018]},{"content":"This means that a nearly valid 28-character string would take over an hour to process, and a nearly valid 33-character string would take nearly a day to process.","pos":[5019,5180]},{"content":"Because this regular expression was developed solely by considering the format of input to be matched, it fails to take account of input that does not match the pattern.","pos":[5187,5356]},{"content":"This, in turn, can allow unconstrained input that nearly matches the regular expression pattern to significantly degrade performance.","pos":[5357,5490]},{"content":"To solve this problem, you can do the following:","pos":[5497,5545]},{"content":"When developing a pattern, you should consider how backtracking might affect the performance of the regular expression engine, particularly if your regular expression is designed to process unconstrained input.","pos":[5555,5765]},{"content":"For more information, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Take Charge of Backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](#Backtracking)</ept> section.","pos":[5766,5849],"source":" For more information, see the [Take Charge of Backtracking](#Backtracking) section."},{"content":"Thoroughly test your regular expression using invalid and near-valid input as well as valid input.","pos":[5859,5957]},{"content":"To generate input for a particular regular expression randomly, you can use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Rex<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=210756)</ept>, which is a regular expression exploration tool from Microsoft Research.","pos":[5958,6159],"source":" To generate input for a particular regular expression randomly, you can use [Rex](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=210756), which is a regular expression exploration tool from Microsoft Research."},{"pos":[6166,6185],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Back to top<ept id=\"p1\">](#top)</ept>","source":"[Back to top](#top)"},{"pos":[6232,6273],"content":"Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately","linkify":"Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately","nodes":[{"content":"Handle Object Instantiation Appropriately","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"At the heart of .NET’s regular expression object model is the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> class, which represents the regular expression engine.","pos":[6277,6462],"source":"At the heart of .NET’s regular expression object model is the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex?displayProperty=fullName> class, which represents the regular expression engine."},{"content":"Often, the single greatest factor that affects regular expression performance is the way in which the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> engine is used.","pos":[6463,6624],"source":" Often, the single greatest factor that affects regular expression performance is the way in which the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> engine is used."},{"content":"Defining a regular expression involves tightly coupling the regular expression engine with a regular expression pattern.","pos":[6625,6745]},{"content":"That coupling process, whether it involves instantiating a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object by passing its constructor a regular expression pattern or calling a static method by passing it the regular expression pattern along with the string to be analyzed, is by necessity an expensive one.","pos":[6746,7055],"source":" That coupling process, whether it involves instantiating a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object by passing its constructor a regular expression pattern or calling a static method by passing it the regular expression pattern along with the string to be analyzed, is by necessity an expensive one."},{"pos":[7063,7348],"content":"[!NOTE]\n For a more detailed discussion of the performance implications of using interpreted and compiled regular expressions, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211566) in the BCL Team blog.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"For a more detailed discussion of the performance implications of using interpreted and compiled regular expressions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211566)</ept> in the BCL Team blog.","pos":[9,283],"source":"For a more detailed discussion of the performance implications of using interpreted and compiled regular expressions, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211566) in the BCL Team blog."}]},{"content":"You can couple the regular expression engine with a particular regular expression pattern and then use the engine to match text in several ways:","pos":[7355,7499]},{"content":"You can call a static pattern-matching method, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>.","pos":[7509,7674],"source":"You can call a static pattern-matching method, such as <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName>."},{"content":"This does not require instantiation of a regular expression object.","pos":[7675,7742]},{"content":"You can instantiate a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of an interpreted regular expression.","pos":[7752,7907],"source":"You can instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of an interpreted regular expression."},{"content":"This is the default method for binding the regular expression engine to a regular expression pattern.","pos":[7908,8009]},{"content":"It results when a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object is instantiated without an <ph id=\"ph2\">`options`</ph> argument that includes the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> flag.","pos":[8010,8199],"source":" It results when a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is instantiated without an `options` argument that includes the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag."},{"content":"You can instantiate a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of a compiled regular expression.","pos":[8209,8360],"source":"You can instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object and call an instance pattern-matching method of a compiled regular expression."},{"content":"Regular expression objects represent compiled patterns when a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object is instantiated with an <ph id=\"ph2\">`options`</ph> argument that includes the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> flag.","pos":[8361,8591],"source":" Regular expression objects represent compiled patterns when a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is instantiated with an `options` argument that includes the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag."},{"content":"You can create a special-purpose <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object that is tightly coupled with a particular regular expression pattern, compile it, and save it to a standalone assembly.","pos":[8601,8804],"source":"You can create a special-purpose <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object that is tightly coupled with a particular regular expression pattern, compile it, and save it to a standalone assembly."},{"content":"You do this by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[8805,8929],"source":" You do this by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method."},{"content":"The particular way in which you call regular expression matching methods can have a significant impact on your application.","pos":[8936,9059]},{"content":"The following sections discuss when to use static method calls, interpreted regular expressions, and compiled regular expressions to improve your application's performance.","pos":[9060,9232]},{"pos":[9240,9474],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\n The form of the method call (static, interpreted, compiled) affects performance if the same regular expression is used repeatedly in method calls, or if an application makes extensive use of regular expression objects.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The form of the method call (static, interpreted, compiled) affects performance if the same regular expression is used repeatedly in method calls, or if an application makes extensive use of regular expression objects.","pos":[14,232]}]},{"pos":[9484,9510],"content":"Static Regular Expressions","linkify":"Static Regular Expressions","nodes":[{"content":"Static Regular Expressions","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"Static regular expression methods are recommended as an alternative to repeatedly instantiating a regular expression object with the same regular expression.","pos":[9514,9671]},{"content":"Unlike regular expression patterns used by regular expression objects, either the operation codes or the compiled Microsoft intermediate language (MSIL) from patterns used in instance method calls is cached internally by the regular expression engine.","pos":[9672,9923]},{"content":"For example, an event handler frequently calls another method to validate user input.","pos":[9930,10015]},{"content":"This is reflected in the following code, in which a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Forms.Button&gt;</ph> control's <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Forms.Control.Click&gt;</ph> event is used to call a method named <ph id=\"ph3\">`IsValidCurrency`</ph>, which checks whether the user has entered a currency symbol followed by at least one decimal digit.","pos":[10016,10310],"source":" This is reflected in the following code, in which a <xref:System.Windows.Forms.Button> control's <xref:System.Windows.Forms.Control.Click> event is used to call a method named `IsValidCurrency`, which checks whether the user has entered a currency symbol followed by at least one decimal digit."},{"pos":[10317,10662],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#2)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#2)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#2)]"},{"content":"A very inefficient implementation of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`IsValidCurrency`</ph> method is shown in the following example.","pos":[10669,10769],"source":"A very inefficient implementation of the `IsValidCurrency` method is shown in the following example."},{"content":"Note that each method call reinstantiates a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object with the same pattern.","pos":[10770,10887],"source":" Note that each method call reinstantiates a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object with the same pattern."},{"content":"This, in turn, means that the regular expression pattern must be recompiled each time the method is called.","pos":[10888,10995]},{"pos":[11002,11347],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#3)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#3)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static1.cs#3)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#3](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static1.vb#3)]"},{"content":"You should replace this inefficient code with a call to the static <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[11354,11540],"source":"You should replace this inefficient code with a call to the static <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch%28System.String%2CSystem.String%29?displayProperty=fullName> method."},{"content":"This eliminates the need to instantiate a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object each time you want to call a pattern-matching method, and enables the regular expression engine to retrieve a compiled version of the regular expression from its cache.","pos":[11541,11802],"source":" This eliminates the need to instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object each time you want to call a pattern-matching method, and enables the regular expression engine to retrieve a compiled version of the regular expression from its cache."},{"pos":[11809,12154],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static2.cs#4)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static2.vb#4)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/static2.cs#4)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#4](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/static2.vb#4)]"},{"content":"By default, the last 15 most recently used static regular expression patterns are cached.","pos":[12161,12250]},{"content":"For applications that require a larger number of cached static regular expressions, the size of the cache can be adjusted by setting the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CacheSize%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[12251,12479],"source":" For applications that require a larger number of cached static regular expressions, the size of the cache can be adjusted by setting the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CacheSize%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property."},{"content":"The regular expression <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\p{Sc}+\\s*\\d+`</ph> that is used in this example verifies that the input string consists of a currency symbol and at least one decimal digit.","pos":[12486,12646],"source":"The regular expression `\\p{Sc}+\\s*\\d+` that is used in this example verifies that the input string consists of a currency symbol and at least one decimal digit."},{"content":"The pattern is defined as shown in the following table.","pos":[12647,12702]},{"content":"Pattern","pos":[12709,12716]},{"content":"Description","pos":[12717,12728]},{"content":"Match one or more characters in the Unicode Symbol, Currency category.","pos":[12779,12849]},{"content":"Match zero or more white-space characters.","pos":[12860,12902]},{"content":"Match one or more decimal digits.","pos":[12913,12946]},{"pos":[12987,13031],"content":"Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions","linkify":"Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions","nodes":[{"content":"Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"Regular expression patterns that are not bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> option are interpreted.","pos":[13035,13222],"source":"Regular expression patterns that are not bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option are interpreted."},{"content":"When a regular expression object is instantiated, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to a set of operation codes.","pos":[13223,13363]},{"content":"When an instance method is called, the operation codes are converted to MSIL and executed by the JIT compiler.","pos":[13364,13474]},{"content":"Similarly, when a static regular expression method is called and the regular expression cannot be found in the cache, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to a set of operation codes and stores them in the cache.","pos":[13475,13712]},{"content":"It then converts these operation codes to MSIL so that the JIT compiler can execute them.","pos":[13713,13802]},{"content":"Interpreted regular expressions reduce startup time at the cost of slower execution time.","pos":[13803,13892]},{"content":"Because of this, they are best used when the regular expression is used in a small number of method calls, or if the exact number of calls to regular expression methods is unknown but is expected to be small.","pos":[13893,14101]},{"content":"As the number of method calls increases, the performance gain from reduced startup time is outstripped by the slower execution speed.","pos":[14102,14235]},{"content":"Regular expression patterns that are bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> option are compiled.","pos":[14242,14422],"source":"Regular expression patterns that are bound to the regular expression engine through the specification of the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option are compiled."},{"content":"This means that, when a regular expression object is instantiated, or when a static regular expression method is called and the regular expression cannot be found in the cache, the regular expression engine converts the regular expression to an intermediary set of operation codes, which it then converts to MSIL.","pos":[14423,14736]},{"content":"When a method is called, the JIT compiler executes the MSIL.","pos":[14737,14797]},{"content":"In contrast to interpreted regular expressions, compiled regular expressions increase startup time but execute individual pattern-matching methods faster.","pos":[14798,14952]},{"content":"As a result, the performance benefit that results from compiling the regular expression increases in proportion to the number of regular expression methods called.","pos":[14953,15116]},{"content":"To summarize, we recommend that you use interpreted regular expressions when you call regular expression methods with a specific regular expression relatively infrequently.","pos":[15123,15295]},{"content":"You should use compiled regular expressions when you call regular expression methods with a specific regular expression relatively frequently.","pos":[15296,15438]},{"content":"The exact threshold at which the slower execution speeds of interpreted regular expressions outweigh gains from their reduced startup time, or the threshold at which the slower startup times of compiled regular expressions outweigh gains from their faster execution speeds, is difficult to determine.","pos":[15439,15739]},{"content":"It depends on a variety of factors, including the complexity of the regular expression and the specific data that it processes.","pos":[15740,15867]},{"content":"To determine whether interpreted or compiled regular expressions offer the best performance for your particular application scenario, you can use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Diagnostics.Stopwatch&gt;</ph> class to compare their execution times.","pos":[15868,16093],"source":" To determine whether interpreted or compiled regular expressions offer the best performance for your particular application scenario, you can use the <xref:System.Diagnostics.Stopwatch> class to compare their execution times."},{"content":"The following example compares the performance of compiled and interpreted regular expressions when reading the first ten sentences and when reading all the sentences in the text of Theodore Dreiser's <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>The Financier<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[16100,16317],"source":"The following example compares the performance of compiled and interpreted regular expressions when reading the first ten sentences and when reading all the sentences in the text of Theodore Dreiser's *The Financier*."},{"content":"As the output from the example shows, when only ten calls are made to regular expression matching methods, an interpreted regular expression offers better performance than a compiled regular expression.","pos":[16318,16520]},{"content":"However, a compiled regular expression offers better performance when a large number of calls (in this case, over 13,000) are made.","pos":[16521,16652]},{"pos":[16659,17006],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compare1.cs#5)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compare1.vb#5)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compare1.cs#5)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#5](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compare1.vb#5)]"},{"pos":[17013,17144],"content":"The regular expression pattern used in the example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b(\\w+((\\r?\\n)|,?\\s))*\\w+[.?:;!]`</ph>, is defined as shown in the following table.","source":"The regular expression pattern used in the example, `\\b(\\w+((\\r?\\n)|,?\\s))*\\w+[.?:;!]`, is defined as shown in the following table."},{"content":"Pattern","pos":[17151,17158]},{"content":"Description","pos":[17159,17170]},{"content":"Begin the match at a word boundary.","pos":[17216,17251]},{"content":"Match one or more word characters.","pos":[17262,17296]},{"content":"Match either zero or one carriage return followed by a newline character, or zero or one comma followed by a white-space character.","pos":[17322,17453]},{"content":"Match zero or more occurrences of one or more word characters that are followed either by zero or one carriage return and a newline character, or by zero or one comma followed by a white-space character.","pos":[17486,17689]},{"content":"Match one or more word characters.","pos":[17700,17734]},{"content":"Match a period, question mark, colon, semicolon, or exclamation point.","pos":[17749,17819]},{"pos":[17830,17874],"content":"Regular Expressions: Compiled to an Assembly","linkify":"Regular Expressions: Compiled to an Assembly","nodes":[{"content":"Regular Expressions: Compiled to an Assembly","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":".NET also enables you to create an assembly that contains compiled regular expressions.","pos":[17878,17965]},{"content":"This moves the performance hit of regular expression compilation from run time to design time.","pos":[17966,18060]},{"content":"However, it also involves some additional work: You must define the regular expressions in advance and compile them to an assembly.","pos":[18061,18192]},{"content":"The compiler can then reference this assembly when compiling source code that uses the assembly’s regular expressions.","pos":[18193,18311]},{"content":"Each compiled regular expression in the assembly is represented by a class that derives from <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph>.","pos":[18312,18449],"source":" Each compiled regular expression in the assembly is represented by a class that derives from <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex>."},{"content":"To compile regular expressions to an assembly, you call the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%28System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo%5B%5D%2CSystem.Reflection.AssemblyName%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method and pass it an array of <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo&gt;</ph> objects that represent the regular expressions to be compiled, and an <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Reflection.AssemblyName&gt;</ph> object that contains information about the assembly to be created.","pos":[18456,18963],"source":"To compile regular expressions to an assembly, you call the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%28System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo%5B%5D%2CSystem.Reflection.AssemblyName%29?displayProperty=fullName> method and pass it an array of <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexCompilationInfo> objects that represent the regular expressions to be compiled, and an <xref:System.Reflection.AssemblyName> object that contains information about the assembly to be created."},{"content":"We recommend that you compile regular expressions to an assembly in the following situations:","pos":[18970,19063]},{"content":"If you are a component developer who wants to create a library of reusable regular expressions.","pos":[19073,19168]},{"content":"If you expect your regular expression's pattern-matching methods to be called an indeterminate number of times -- anywhere from once or twice to thousands or tens of thousands of times.","pos":[19178,19363]},{"content":"Unlike compiled or interpreted regular expressions, regular expressions that are compiled to separate assemblies offer performance that is consistent regardless of the number of method calls.","pos":[19364,19555]},{"content":"If you are using compiled regular expressions to optimize performance, you should not use reflection to create the assembly, load the regular expression engine, and execute its pattern-matching methods.","pos":[19562,19764]},{"content":"This requires that you avoid building regular expression patterns dynamically, and that you specify any pattern-matching options (such as case-insensitive pattern matching) at the time the assembly is created.","pos":[19765,19974]},{"content":"It also requires that you separate the code that creates the assembly from the code that uses the regular expression.","pos":[19975,20092]},{"content":"The following example shows how to create an assembly that contains a compiled regular expression.","pos":[20099,20197]},{"content":"It creates an assembly named <ph id=\"ph1\">`RegexLib.dll`</ph> with a single regular expression class, <ph id=\"ph2\">`SentencePattern`</ph>, that contains the sentence-matching regular expression pattern used in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions<ept id=\"p1\">](#Interpreted)</ept> section.","pos":[20198,20445],"source":" It creates an assembly named `RegexLib.dll` with a single regular expression class, `SentencePattern`, that contains the sentence-matching regular expression pattern used in the [Interpreted vs. Compiled Regular Expressions](#Interpreted) section."},{"pos":[20452,20799],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile1.cs#6)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile1.vb#6)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","leadings":[""," "],"source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile1.cs#6)]\n[!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#6](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile1.vb#6)]"},{"content":"When the example is compiled to an executable and run, it creates an assembly named <ph id=\"ph1\">`RegexLib.dll`</ph>.","pos":[20806,20905],"source":"When the example is compiled to an executable and run, it creates an assembly named `RegexLib.dll`."},{"content":"The regular expression is represented by a class named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Utilities.RegularExpressions.SentencePattern`</ph> that is derived from <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph>.","pos":[20906,21073],"source":" The regular expression is represented by a class named `Utilities.RegularExpressions.SentencePattern` that is derived from <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex>."},{"content":"The following example then uses the compiled regular expression to extract the sentences from the text of Theodore Dreiser's <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>The Financier<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[21074,21215],"source":" The following example then uses the compiled regular expression to extract the sentences from the text of Theodore Dreiser's *The Financier*."},{"pos":[21222,21569],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile2.cs#7)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile2.vb#7)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","leadings":[""," "],"source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/compile2.cs#7)]\n[!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#7](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/compile2.vb#7)]"},{"pos":[21576,21595],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Back to top<ept id=\"p1\">](#top)</ept>","source":"[Back to top](#top)"},{"pos":[21635,21662],"content":"Take Charge of Backtracking","linkify":"Take Charge of Backtracking","nodes":[{"content":"Take Charge of Backtracking","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Ordinarily, the regular expression engine uses linear progression to move through an input string and compare it to a regular expression pattern.","pos":[21666,21811]},{"content":"However, when indeterminate quantifiers such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`*`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`+`</ph>, and <ph id=\"ph3\">`?`</ph> are used in a regular expression pattern, the regular expression engine may give up a portion of successful partial matches and return to a previously saved state in order to search for a successful match for the entire pattern.","pos":[21812,22106],"source":" However, when indeterminate quantifiers such as `*`, `+`, and `?` are used in a regular expression pattern, the regular expression engine may give up a portion of successful partial matches and return to a previously saved state in order to search for a successful match for the entire pattern."},{"content":"This process is known as backtracking.","pos":[22107,22145]},{"pos":[22153,22617],"content":"[!NOTE]\n For more information on backtracking, see [Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md) and [Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md). For a detailed discussion of backtracking, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211567) in the BCL Team blog.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"For more information on backtracking, see [Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md) and [Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md). For a detailed discussion of backtracking, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211567) in the BCL Team blog.","pos":[9,462],"nodes":[{"content":"For more information on backtracking, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Details of Regular Expression Behavior<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Backtracking<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)</ept>.","pos":[0,253],"source":"For more information on backtracking, see [Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md) and [Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)."},{"content":"For a detailed discussion of backtracking, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211567)</ept> in the BCL Team blog.","pos":[254,453],"source":" For a detailed discussion of backtracking, see [Optimizing Regular Expression Performance, Part II: Taking Charge of Backtracking](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=211567) in the BCL Team blog."}]}]},{"content":"Support for backtracking gives regular expressions power and flexibility.","pos":[22624,22697]},{"content":"It also places the responsibility for controlling the operation of the regular expression engine in the hands of regular expression developers.","pos":[22698,22841]},{"content":"Because developers are often not aware of this responsibility, their misuse of backtracking or reliance on excessive backtracking often plays the most significant role in degrading regular expression performance.","pos":[22842,23054]},{"content":"In a worst-case scenario, execution time can double for each additional character in the input string.","pos":[23055,23157]},{"content":"In fact, by using backtracking excessively, it is easy to create the programmatic equivalent of an endless loop if input nearly matches the regular expression pattern; the regular expression engine may take hours or even days to process a relatively short input string.","pos":[23158,23427]},{"content":"Often, applications pay a performance penalty for using backtracking despite the fact that backtracking is not essential for a match.","pos":[23434,23567]},{"content":"For example, the regular expression <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b`</ph> matches all words that begin with an uppercase character, as the following table shows.","pos":[23568,23707],"source":" For example, the regular expression `\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b` matches all words that begin with an uppercase character, as the following table shows."},{"content":"Pattern","pos":[23714,23721]},{"content":"Description","pos":[23722,23733]},{"content":"Begin the match at a word boundary.","pos":[23751,23786]},{"content":"Match an uppercase character.","pos":[23800,23829]},{"content":"Match zero or more word characters.","pos":[23840,23875]},{"content":"End the match at a word boundary.","pos":[23885,23918]},{"content":"Because a word boundary is not the same as, or a subset of, a word character, there is no possibility that the regular expression engine will cross a word boundary when matching word characters.","pos":[23926,24120]},{"content":"This means that for this regular expression, backtracking can never contribute to the overall success of any match -- it can only degrade performance, because the regular expression engine is forced to save its state for each successful preliminary match of a word character.","pos":[24121,24396]},{"content":"If you determine that backtracking is not necessary, you can disable it by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`(?&gt;``subexpression``)`</ph> language element.","pos":[24403,24529],"source":"If you determine that backtracking is not necessary, you can disable it by using the `(?>``subexpression``)` language element."},{"content":"The following example parses an input string by using two regular expressions.","pos":[24530,24608]},{"content":"The first, <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b`</ph>, relies on backtracking.","pos":[24609,24660],"source":" The first, `\\b\\p{Lu}\\w*\\b`, relies on backtracking."},{"content":"The second, <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b\\p{Lu}(?&gt;\\w*)\\b`</ph>, disables backtracking.","pos":[24661,24716],"source":" The second, `\\b\\p{Lu}(?>\\w*)\\b`, disables backtracking."},{"content":"As the output from the example shows, they both produce the same result.","pos":[24717,24789]},{"pos":[24796,25151],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack2.cs#10)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack2.vb#10)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack2.cs#10)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#10](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack2.vb#10)]"},{"content":"In many cases, backtracking is essential for matching a regular expression pattern to input text.","pos":[25158,25255]},{"content":"However, excessive backtracking can severely degrade performance and create the impression that an application has stopped responding.","pos":[25256,25390]},{"content":"In particular, this happens when quantifiers are nested and the text that matches the outer subexpression is a subset of the text that matches the inner subexpression.","pos":[25391,25558]},{"pos":[25566,25829],"content":"[!WARNING]\n In addition to avoiding excessive backtracking, you should use the timeout feature to ensure that excessive backtracking does not severely degrade regular expression performance. For more information, see the [Use Timeout Values](#Timeouts) section.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"In addition to avoiding excessive backtracking, you should use the timeout feature to ensure that excessive backtracking does not severely degrade regular expression performance. For more information, see the [Use Timeout Values](#Timeouts) section.","pos":[12,261],"nodes":[{"content":"In addition to avoiding excessive backtracking, you should use the timeout feature to ensure that excessive backtracking does not severely degrade regular expression performance.","pos":[0,178]},{"content":"For more information, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use Timeout Values<ept id=\"p1\">](#Timeouts)</ept> section.","pos":[179,249],"source":" For more information, see the [Use Timeout Values](#Timeouts) section."}]}]},{"content":"For example, the regular expression pattern <ph id=\"ph1\">`^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*\\$$`</ph> is intended to match a part number that consists of at least one alphanumeric character.","pos":[25836,26001],"source":"For example, the regular expression pattern `^[0-9A-Z]([-.\\w]*[0-9A-Z])*\\$$` is intended to match a part number that consists of at least one alphanumeric character."},{"content":"Any additional characters can consist of an alphanumeric character, a hyphen, an underscore, or a period, though the last character must be alphanumeric.","pos":[26002,26155]},{"content":"A dollar sign terminates the part number.","pos":[26156,26197]},{"content":"In some cases, this regular expression pattern can exhibit extremely poor performance because quantifiers are nested, and because the subexpression <ph id=\"ph1\">`[0-9A-Z]`</ph> is a subset of the subexpression <ph id=\"ph2\">`[-.\\w]*`</ph>.","pos":[26198,26400],"source":" In some cases, this regular expression pattern can exhibit extremely poor performance because quantifiers are nested, and because the subexpression `[0-9A-Z]` is a subset of the subexpression `[-.\\w]*`."},{"content":"In these cases, you can optimize regular expression performance by removing the nested quantifiers and replacing the outer subexpression with a zero-width lookahead or lookbehind assertion.","pos":[26407,26596]},{"content":"Lookahead and lookbehind assertions are anchors; they do not move the pointer in the input string, but instead look ahead or behind to check whether a specified condition is met.","pos":[26597,26775]},{"content":"For example, the part number regular expression can be rewritten as <ph id=\"ph1\">`^[0-9A-Z][-.\\w]*(?&lt;=[0-9A-Z])\\$$`</ph>.","pos":[26776,26879],"source":" For example, the part number regular expression can be rewritten as `^[0-9A-Z][-.\\w]*(?<=[0-9A-Z])\\$$`."},{"content":"This regular expression pattern is defined as shown in the following table.","pos":[26880,26955]},{"content":"Pattern","pos":[26962,26969]},{"content":"Description","pos":[26970,26981]},{"content":"Begin the match at the beginning of the input string.","pos":[27026,27079]},{"content":"Match an alphanumeric character.","pos":[27095,27127]},{"content":"The part number must consist of at least this character.","pos":[27128,27184]},{"content":"Match zero or more occurrences of any word character, hyphen, or period.","pos":[27199,27271]},{"content":"Match a dollar sign.","pos":[27281,27301]},{"content":"Look ahead of the ending dollar sign to ensure that the previous character is alphanumeric.","pos":[27322,27413]},{"content":"End the match at the end of the input string.","pos":[27422,27467]},{"content":"The following example illustrates the use of this regular expression to match an array containing possible part numbers.","pos":[27475,27595]},{"pos":[27602,27957],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack4.cs#11)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack4.vb#11)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/backtrack4.cs#11)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#11](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/backtrack4.vb#11)]"},{"content":"The regular expression language in .NET includes the following language elements that you can use to eliminate nested quantifiers.","pos":[27964,28094]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Grouping Constructs<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/grouping-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md)</ept>.","pos":[28095,28224],"source":" For more information, see [Grouping Constructs](../../../docs/standard/base-types/grouping-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md)."},{"content":"Language element","pos":[28231,28247]},{"content":"Description","pos":[28248,28259]},{"pos":[28309,28334],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`(?=`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`subexpression`</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">`)`</ph>","source":"`(?=` `subexpression` `)`"},{"content":"Zero-width positive lookahead.","pos":[28335,28365]},{"content":"Look ahead of the current position to determine whether <ph id=\"ph1\">`subexpression`</ph> matches the input string.","pos":[28366,28463],"source":" Look ahead of the current position to determine whether `subexpression` matches the input string."},{"pos":[28468,28493],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`(?!`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`subexpression`</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">`)`</ph>","source":"`(?!` `subexpression` `)`"},{"content":"Zero-width negative lookahead.","pos":[28494,28524]},{"content":"Look ahead of the current position to determine whether <ph id=\"ph1\">`subexpression`</ph> does not match the input string.","pos":[28525,28629],"source":" Look ahead of the current position to determine whether `subexpression` does not match the input string."},{"pos":[28634,28660],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`(?&lt;=`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`subexpression`</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">`)`</ph>","source":"`(?<=` `subexpression` `)`"},{"content":"Zero-width positive lookbehind.","pos":[28661,28692]},{"content":"Look behind the current position to determine whether <ph id=\"ph1\">`subexpression`</ph> matches the input string.","pos":[28693,28788],"source":" Look behind the current position to determine whether `subexpression` matches the input string."},{"pos":[28793,28819],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`(?&lt;!`</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">`subexpression`</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">`)`</ph>","source":"`(?<!` `subexpression` `)`"},{"content":"Zero-width negative lookbehind.","pos":[28820,28851]},{"content":"Look behind the current position to determine whether <ph id=\"ph1\">`subexpression`</ph> does not match the input string.","pos":[28852,28954],"source":" Look behind the current position to determine whether `subexpression` does not match the input string."},{"pos":[28962,28981],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Back to top<ept id=\"p1\">](#top)</ept>","source":"[Back to top](#top)"},{"pos":[29017,29036],"content":"Use Time-out Values","linkify":"Use Time-out Values","nodes":[{"content":"Use Time-out Values","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"If your regular expressions processes input that nearly matches the regular expression pattern, it can often rely on excessive backtracking, which impacts its performance significantly.","pos":[29040,29225]},{"content":"In addition to carefully considering your use of backtracking and testing the regular expression against near-matching input, you should always set a time-out value to ensure that the impact of excessive backtracking, if it occurs, is minimized.","pos":[29226,29471]},{"content":"The regular expression time-out interval defines the period of time that the regular expression engine will look for a single match before it times out. The default time-out interval is <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.InfiniteMatchTimeout?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>, which means that the regular expression will not time out. You can override this value and define a time-out interval as follows:","pos":[29478,29884],"source":"The regular expression time-out interval defines the period of time that the regular expression engine will look for a single match before it times out. The default time-out interval is <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.InfiniteMatchTimeout?displayProperty=fullName>, which means that the regular expression will not time out. You can override this value and define a time-out interval as follows:"},{"content":"By providing a time-out value when you instantiate a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object by calling the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.%23ctor%28System.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> constructor.","pos":[29894,30185],"source":"By providing a time-out value when you instantiate a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.%23ctor%28System.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName> constructor."},{"pos":[30195,30659],"content":"By calling a static pattern matching method, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>, that includes a <ph id=\"ph3\">`matchTimeout`</ph> parameter.","source":"By calling a static pattern matching method, such as <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName> or <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace%28System.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.String%2CSystem.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions%2CSystem.TimeSpan%29?displayProperty=fullName>, that includes a `matchTimeout` parameter."},{"content":"For compiled regular expressions that are created by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> method, by calling the constructor that has a parameter of type <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.TimeSpan&gt;</ph>.","pos":[30669,30911],"source":"For compiled regular expressions that are created by calling the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.CompileToAssembly%2A?displayProperty=fullName> method, by calling the constructor that has a parameter of type <xref:System.TimeSpan>."},{"content":"If you have defined a time-out interval and a match is not found at the end of that interval, the regular expression method throws a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexMatchTimeoutException&gt;</ph> exception.","pos":[30918,31126],"source":"If you have defined a time-out interval and a match is not found at the end of that interval, the regular expression method throws a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexMatchTimeoutException> exception."},{"content":"In your exception handler, you can choose to retry the match with a longer time-out interval, abandon the match attempt and assume that there is no match, or abandon the match attempt and log the exception information for future analysis.","pos":[31127,31365]},{"content":"The following example defines a <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetWordData`</ph> method that instantiates a regular expression with a time-out interval of 350 milliseconds to calculate the number of words and average number of characters in a word in a text document.","pos":[31372,31604],"source":"The following example defines a `GetWordData` method that instantiates a regular expression with a time-out interval of 350 milliseconds to calculate the number of words and average number of characters in a word in a text document."},{"content":"If the matching operation times out, the time-out interval is increased by 350 milliseconds and the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> object is re-instantiated.","pos":[31605,31775],"source":" If the matching operation times out, the time-out interval is increased by 350 milliseconds and the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> object is re-instantiated."},{"content":"If the new time-out interval exceeds 1 second, the method re-throws the exception to the caller.","pos":[31776,31872]},{"pos":[31879,32230],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/timeout1.cs#12)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/timeout1.vb#12)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","leadings":[""," "],"source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/timeout1.cs#12)]\n[!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#12](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/timeout1.vb#12)]"},{"pos":[32237,32256],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Back to top<ept id=\"p1\">](#top)</ept>","source":"[Back to top](#top)"},{"pos":[32291,32318],"content":"Capture Only When Necessary","linkify":"Capture Only When Necessary","nodes":[{"content":"Capture Only When Necessary","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Regular expressions in .NET support a number of grouping constructs, which let you group a regular expression pattern into one or more subexpressions.","pos":[32322,32472]},{"content":"The most commonly used grouping constructs in .NET regular expression language are <ph id=\"ph1\">`(`</ph><bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>subexpression<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph2\">`)`</ph>, which defines a numbered capturing group, and <ph id=\"ph3\">`(?&lt;`</ph><bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>name<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph4\">`&gt;`</ph><bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>subexpression<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept><ph id=\"ph5\">`)`</ph>, which defines a named capturing group.","pos":[32473,32697],"source":" The most commonly used grouping constructs in .NET regular expression language are `(`*subexpression*`)`, which defines a numbered capturing group, and `(?<`*name*`>`*subexpression*`)`, which defines a named capturing group."},{"content":"Grouping constructs are essential for creating backreferences and for defining a subexpression to which a quantifier is applied.","pos":[32698,32826]},{"content":"However, the use of these language elements has a cost.","pos":[32833,32888]},{"content":"They cause the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection&gt;</ph> object returned by the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property to be populated with the most recent unnamed or named captures, and if a single grouping construct has captured multiple substrings in the input string, they also populate the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection&gt;</ph> object returned by the <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property of a particular capturing group with multiple <ph id=\"ph5\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Capture&gt;</ph> objects.","pos":[32889,33514],"source":" They cause the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> object returned by the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to be populated with the most recent unnamed or named captures, and if a single grouping construct has captured multiple substrings in the input string, they also populate the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> object returned by the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property of a particular capturing group with multiple <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Capture> objects."},{"content":"Often, grouping constructs are used in a regular expression only so that quantifiers can be applied to them, and the groups captured by these subexpressions are not subsequently used.","pos":[33521,33704]},{"content":"For example, the regular expression <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]`</ph> is designed to capture an entire sentence.","pos":[33705,33807],"source":" For example, the regular expression `\\b(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]` is designed to capture an entire sentence."},{"content":"The following table describes the language elements in this regular expression pattern and their effect on the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match&gt;</ph> object's <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> collections.","pos":[33808,34148],"source":" The following table describes the language elements in this regular expression pattern and their effect on the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match> object's <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Match.Groups%2A?displayProperty=fullName> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Group.Captures%2A?displayProperty=fullName> collections."},{"content":"Pattern","pos":[34155,34162]},{"content":"Description","pos":[34163,34174]},{"content":"Begin the match at a word boundary.","pos":[34220,34255]},{"content":"Match one or more word characters.","pos":[34266,34300]},{"content":"Match zero or one comma or semicolon.","pos":[34313,34350]},{"content":"Match zero or one white-space character.","pos":[34361,34401]},{"content":"Match one or more occurrences of one or more word characters followed by an optional comma or semicolon followed by an optional white-space character.","pos":[34423,34573]},{"content":"This defines the first capturing group, which is necessary so that the combination of multiple word characters (that is, a word) followed by an optional punctuation symbol will be repeated until the regular expression engine reaches the end of a sentence.","pos":[34574,34829]},{"content":"Match a period, question mark, or exclamation point.","pos":[34842,34894]},{"content":"As the following example shows, when a match is found, both the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection&gt;</ph> objects are populated with captures from the match.","pos":[34902,35131],"source":"As the following example shows, when a match is found, both the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> objects are populated with captures from the match."},{"content":"In this case, the capturing group <ph id=\"ph1\">`(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)`</ph> exists so that the <ph id=\"ph2\">`+`</ph> quantifier can be applied to it, which enables the regular expression pattern to match each word in a sentence.","pos":[35132,35316],"source":" In this case, the capturing group `(\\w+[;,]?\\s?)` exists so that the `+` quantifier can be applied to it, which enables the regular expression pattern to match each word in a sentence."},{"content":"Otherwise, it would match the last word in a sentence.","pos":[35317,35371]},{"pos":[35378,35721],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group1.cs#8)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group1.vb#8)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group1.cs#8)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#8](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group1.vb#8)]"},{"content":"When you use subexpressions only to apply quantifiers to them, and you are not interested in the captured text, you should disable group captures.","pos":[35728,35874]},{"content":"For example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`(?:``subexpression``)`</ph> language element prevents the group to which it applies from capturing matched substrings.","pos":[35875,36006],"source":" For example, the `(?:``subexpression``)` language element prevents the group to which it applies from capturing matched substrings."},{"content":"In the following example, the regular expression pattern from the previous example is changed to <ph id=\"ph1\">`\\b(?:\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]`</ph>.","pos":[36007,36130],"source":" In the following example, the regular expression pattern from the previous example is changed to `\\b(?:\\w+[;,]?\\s?)+[.?!]`."},{"content":"As the output shows, it prevents the regular expression engine from populating the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection&gt;</ph> collections.","pos":[36131,36340],"source":" As the output shows, it prevents the regular expression engine from populating the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.GroupCollection> and <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.CaptureCollection> collections."},{"pos":[36347,36690],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group2.cs#9)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">[!code-vb</bpt><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9<ept id=\"p4\">](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group2.vb#9)</ept><ept id=\"p3\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/cs/group2.cs#9)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.RegularExpressions.BestPractices#9](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.regularexpressions.bestpractices/vb/group2.vb#9)]"},{"content":"You can disable captures in one of the following ways:","pos":[36697,36751]},{"content":"Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`(?:``subexpression``)`</ph> language element.","pos":[36761,36810],"source":"Use the `(?:``subexpression``)` language element."},{"content":"This element prevents the capture of matched substrings in the group to which it applies.","pos":[36811,36900]},{"content":"It does not disable substring captures in any nested groups.","pos":[36901,36961]},{"content":"Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> option.","pos":[36971,37037],"source":"Use the <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> option."},{"content":"It disables all unnamed or implicit captures in the regular expression pattern.","pos":[37038,37117]},{"content":"When you use this option, only substrings that match named groups defined with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`(?&lt;``name``&gt;``subexpression``)`</ph> language element can be captured.","pos":[37118,37267],"source":" When you use this option, only substrings that match named groups defined with the `(?<``name``>``subexpression``)` language element can be captured."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions&gt;</ph> flag can be passed to the <ph id=\"ph2\">`options`</ph> parameter of a <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> class constructor or to the <ph id=\"ph4\">`options`</ph> parameter of a <ph id=\"ph5\">&lt;xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex&gt;</ph> static matching method.","pos":[37268,37538],"source":" The <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.RegexOptions> flag can be passed to the `options` parameter of a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> class constructor or to the `options` parameter of a <xref:System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex> static matching method."},{"content":"Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`n`</ph> option in the <ph id=\"ph2\">`(?imnsx)`</ph> language element.","pos":[37548,37602],"source":"Use the `n` option in the `(?imnsx)` language element."},{"content":"This option disables all unnamed or implicit captures from the point in the regular expression pattern at which the element appears.","pos":[37603,37735]},{"content":"Captures are disabled either until the end of the pattern or until the <ph id=\"ph1\">`(-n)`</ph> option enables unnamed or implicit captures.","pos":[37736,37858],"source":" Captures are disabled either until the end of the pattern or until the `(-n)` option enables unnamed or implicit captures."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Miscellaneous Constructs<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/miscellaneous-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md)</ept>.","pos":[37859,37998],"source":" For more information, see [Miscellaneous Constructs](../../../docs/standard/base-types/miscellaneous-constructs-in-regular-expressions.md)."},{"content":"Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`n`</ph> option in the <ph id=\"ph2\">`(?imnsx:``subexpression``)`</ph> language element.","pos":[38008,38080],"source":"Use the `n` option in the `(?imnsx:``subexpression``)` language element."},{"content":"This option disables all unnamed or implicit captures in <ph id=\"ph1\">`subexpression`</ph>.","pos":[38081,38154],"source":" This option disables all unnamed or implicit captures in `subexpression`."},{"content":"Captures by any unnamed or implicit nested capturing groups are disabled as well.","pos":[38155,38236]},{"pos":[38243,38262],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Back to top<ept id=\"p1\">](#top)</ept>","source":"[Back to top](#top)"},{"pos":[38303,38317],"content":"Related Topics","linkify":"Related Topics","nodes":[{"content":"Related Topics","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Title","pos":[38324,38329]},{"content":"Description","pos":[38330,38341]},{"pos":[38380,38497],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Details of Regular Expression Behavior<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md)</ept>","source":"[Details of Regular Expression Behavior](../../../docs/standard/base-types/details-of-regular-expression-behavior.md)"},{"content":"Examines the implementation of the regular expression engine in .NET.","pos":[38498,38567]},{"content":"The topic focuses on the flexibility of regular expressions and explains the developer's responsibility for ensuring the efficient and robust operation of the regular expression engine.","pos":[38568,38753]},{"pos":[38758,38846],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Backtracking<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)</ept>","source":"[Backtracking](../../../docs/standard/base-types/backtracking-in-regular-expressions.md)"},{"content":"Explains what backtracking is and how it affects regular expression performance, and examines language elements that provide alternatives to backtracking.","pos":[38847,39001]},{"pos":[39006,39135],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Regular Expression Language - Quick Reference<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/base-types/regular-expression-language-quick-reference.md)</ept>","source":"[Regular Expression Language - Quick Reference](../../../docs/standard/base-types/regular-expression-language-quick-reference.md)"},{"content":"Describes the elements of the regular expression language in .NET and provides links to detailed documentation for each language element.","pos":[39136,39273]}]}