{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Message Security User Name\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"WS Security\"\nms.assetid: c63cfc87-6b20-4949-93b3-bcd4b732b0a2\n---\n# Message Security User Name\nThis sample demonstrates how to implement an application that uses WS-Security with username authentication for the client and requires server authentication using the server's X.509v3 certificate. All application messages between the client and server are signed and encrypted. By default, the username and password supplied by the client are used to logon to a valid Windows account. This sample is based on the [WSHttpBinding](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/wshttpbinding.md). This sample consists of a client console program (Client.exe) and a service library (Service.dll) hosted by Internet Information Services (IIS). The service implements a contract that defines a request-reply communication pattern.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.  \n  \n This sample also demonstrates:  \n  \n-   The default mapping to Windows accounts so that additional authorization can be performed.  \n  \n-   How to access the caller's identity information from the service code.  \n  \n The service exposes a single endpoint for communicating with the service, which is defined using the configuration file Web.config. The endpoint consists of an address, a binding, and a contract. The binding is configured with a standard [\\<wsHttpBinding>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md), which defaults to using message security. This sample sets the standard [\\<wsHttpBinding>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md) to use client username authentication. The behavior specifies that the user credentials are to be used for service authentication. The server certificate must contain the same value for the subject name as the `findValue` attribute in the [\\<serviceCredentials>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/servicecredentials.md).  \n  \n```xml  \n<system.serviceModel>  \n  <protocolMapping>  \n    <add scheme=\"http\" binding=\"wsHttpBinding\" />  \n  </protocolMapping>  \n  <bindings>  \n    <wsHttpBinding>  \n      <!--   \n      This configuration defines the security mode as Message and   \n      the clientCredentialType as Username.  \n      By default, Username authentication attempts to authenticate the provided  \n      username as a Windows computer or domain account.  \n      -->  \n      <binding>  \n        <security mode=\"Message\">  \n          <message clientCredentialType=\"UserName\"/>  \n        </security>  \n      </binding>  \n    </wsHttpBinding>  \n  </bindings>  \n  \n  <!--For debugging purposes set the includeExceptionDetailInFaults attribute to true.-->  \n  <behaviors>  \n    <serviceBehaviors>  \n      <behavior>  \n        <!--   \n      The serviceCredentials behavior allows one to define a service certificate.  \n      A service certificate is used by the service to authenticate itself to the client and to provide message protection.  \n      This configuration references the \"localhost\" certificate installed during the setup instructions.  \n      -->  \n        <serviceCredentials>  \n          <serviceCertificate findValue=\"localhost\" storeLocation=\"LocalMachine\" storeName=\"My\" x509FindType=\"FindBySubjectName\" />  \n        </serviceCredentials>  \n        <serviceMetadata httpGetEnabled=\"True\"/>  \n        <serviceDebug includeExceptionDetailInFaults=\"False\" />  \n      </behavior>  \n    </serviceBehaviors>  \n  </behaviors>  \n</system.serviceModel>  \n```  \n  \n The client endpoint configuration consists of an absolute address for the service endpoint, the binding, and the contract. The client binding is configured with the appropriate `securityMode` and `authenticationMode`. When running in a cross-computer scenario, the service endpoint address must be changed accordingly.  \n  \n```xml  \n<system.serviceModel>  \n  <client>  \n    <endpoint address=\"http://localhost/servicemodelsamples/service.svc\"   \n              binding=\"wsHttpBinding\"   \n              bindingConfiguration=\"Binding1\"   \n              behaviorConfiguration=\"ClientCredentialsBehavior\"  \n              contract=\"Microsoft.ServiceModel.Samples.ICalculator\" />  \n  </client>  \n  \n  <bindings>  \n    <wsHttpBinding>  \n      <!--   \n      This configuration defines the security mode as Message and   \n      the clientCredentialType as Username.  \n      -->  \n      <binding name=\"Binding1\">  \n        <security mode=\"Message\">  \n          <message clientCredentialType=\"UserName\"/>  \n        </security>  \n      </binding>  \n    </wsHttpBinding>  \n  </bindings>  \n  \n  <!--For debugging purposes set the includeExceptionDetailInFaults attribute to true.-->  \n  <behaviors>  \n    <endpointBehaviors>  \n      <behavior name=\"ClientCredentialsBehavior\">  \n        <!--   \n      Setting the certificateValidationMode to PeerOrChainTrust means that if the certificate   \n      is in the user's Trusted People store, then it is trusted without performing a  \n      validation of the certificate's issuer chain. This setting is used here for convenience so that the   \n      sample can be run without having to have certificates issued by a certification authority (CA).  \n      This setting is less secure than the default, ChainTrust. The security implications of this   \n      setting should be carefully considered before using PeerOrChainTrust in production code.   \n      -->  \n        <clientCredentials>  \n          <serviceCertificate>  \n            <authentication certificateValidationMode=\"PeerOrChainTrust\" />  \n          </serviceCertificate>  \n        </clientCredentials>  \n      </behavior>  \n    </endpointBehaviors>  \n  </behaviors>  \n</system.serviceModel>  \n```  \n  \n The client implementation sets the user name and password to use.  \n\n```csharp\n// Create a client.  \nCalculatorClient client = new CalculatorClient();  \n  \n// Configure client with valid computer or domain account (username,password).  \nclient.ClientCredentials.UserName.UserName = username;  \nclient.ClientCredentials.UserName.Password = password.ToString();  \n  \n// Call GetCallerIdentity service operation.  \nConsole.WriteLine(client.GetCallerIdentity());  \n...  \n//Closing the client gracefully closes the connection and cleans up resources.  \nclient.Close();  \n```\n\n When you run the sample, the operation requests and responses are displayed in the client console window. Press ENTER in the client window to shut down the client.  \n  \n```  \nMyMachine\\TestAccount  \nAdd(100,15.99) = 115.99  \nSubtract(145,76.54) = 68.46  \nMultiply(9,81.25) = 731.25  \nDivide(22,7) = 3.14285714285714  \nPress <ENTER> to terminate client.  \n```  \n  \n The Setup.bat batch file included with the MessageSecurity samples enables you to configure the server with a relevant certificate to run a hosted application that requires certificate-based security. The batch file can be run in two modes. To run the batch file in the single-computer mode, type `setup.bat` at the command line. To run it in service mode type `setup.bat service`. You use this mode when running the sample across computers. See the setup procedure at the end of this topic for details.  \n  \n The following provides a brief overview of the different sections of the batch files.  \n  \n-   Creating the server certificate  \n  \n     The following lines from the Setup.bat batch file create the server certificate to be used.  \n  \n    ```bat\n    echo ************  \n    echo Server cert setup starting  \n    echo %SERVER_NAME%  \n    echo ************  \n    echo making server cert  \n    echo ************  \n    makecert.exe -sr LocalMachine -ss MY -a sha1 -n CN=%SERVER_NAME% -sky exchange -pe  \n    ```  \n  \n     The %SERVER_NAME% variable specifies the server name. The certificate is stored in the LocalMachine store. If the Setup.bat batch file is run with an argument of service (such as `setup.bat service`) the %SERVER_NAME% contains the fully-qualified domain name of the computer.  Otherwise it defaults to localhost.  \n  \n-   Installing the server certificate into the client's trusted certificate store  \n  \n     The following line copies the server certificate into the client trusted people store. This step is required because certificates generated by Makecert.exe are not implicitly trusted by the client system. If you already have a certificate that is rooted in a client trusted root certificate—for example, a Microsoft-issued certificate—this step of populating the client certificate store with the server certificate is not required.  \n  \n    ```  \n    certmgr.exe -add -r LocalMachine -s My -c -n %SERVER_NAME% -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople  \n    ```  \n  \n-   Granting permissions on the certificate's private key  \n  \n     The following lines in the Setup.bat batch file make the server certificate stored in the LocalMachine store accessible to the [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)] worker process account.  \n  \n    ```bat\n    echo ************  \n    echo setting privileges on server certificates  \n    echo ************  \n    for /F \"delims=\" %%i in ('\"%ProgramFiles%\\ServiceModelSampleTools\\FindPrivateKey.exe\" My LocalMachine -n CN^=%SERVER_NAME% -a') do set PRIVATE_KEY_FILE=%%i  \n    set WP_ACCOUNT=NT AUTHORITY\\NETWORK SERVICE  \n    (ver | findstr /C:\"5.1\") && set WP_ACCOUNT=%COMPUTERNAME%\\ASPNET  \n    echo Y|cacls.exe \"%PRIVATE_KEY_FILE%\" /E /G \"%WP_ACCOUNT%\":R  \n    iisreset  \n    ```  \n  \n    > [!NOTE]\n    >  If you are using a non-U.S. English edition of Windows you must edit the Setup.bat file and replace the `NT AUTHORITY\\NETWORK SERVICE` account name with your regional equivalent.  \n  \n### To set up, build, and run the sample  \n  \n1.  Ensure that you have performed the [One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md).  \n  \n2.  To build the C# or Visual Basic .NET edition of the solution, follow the instructions in [Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md).  \n  \n### To run the sample on the same computer  \n  \n1.  Ensure that the path includes the folder where Makecert.exe and FindPrivateKey.exe are located.  \n  \n2.  Run Setup.bat from the sample install folder in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges. This installs all the certificates required for running the sample.  \n  \n    > [!NOTE]\n    >  The Setup.bat batch file is designed to be run from a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio. It requires that the path environment variable point to the directory where the SDK is installed. This environment variable is automatically set within a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio.  \n  \n3.  Verify access to the service using a browser by entering the address `http://localhost/servicemodelsamples/service.svc`.\n  \n4.  Launch Client.exe from \\client\\bin. Client activity is displayed on the client console application.  \n  \n5.  If the client and service are not able to communicate, see [Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90)).  \n  \n### To run the sample across computers  \n  \n1.  Create a directory on the service computer. Create a virtual application named servicemodelsamples for this directory by using the Internet Information Services management tool.  \n  \n2.  Copy the service program files from \\inetpub\\wwwroot\\servicemodelsamples to the virtual directory on the service computer. Ensure that you copy the files in the \\bin subdirectory. Also copy the Setup.bat and Cleanup.bat files to the service computer.  \n  \n3.  Create a directory on the client computer for the client binaries.  \n  \n4.  Copy the client program files to the client directory on the client computer. Also copy the Setup.bat, Cleanup.bat, and ImportServiceCert.bat files to the client.  \n  \n5.  On the server, run `setup.bat service` in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges. Running `setup.bat` with the `service` argument creates a service certificate with the fully-qualified domain name of the computer and exports the service certificate to a file named Service.cer.  \n  \n6.  Edit Web.config to reflect the new certificate name (in the findValue attribute in the serviceCertificate element) which is the same as the fully-qualified domain name of the computer`.`  \n  \n7.  Copy the Service.cer file from the service directory to the client directory on the client computer.  \n  \n8.  In the Client.exe.config file on the client computer, change the address value of the endpoint to match the new address of your service.  \n  \n9. On the client, run ImportServiceCert.bat in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges. This imports the service certificate from the Service.cer file into the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store.  \n  \n10. On the client computer, launch Client.exe from a command prompt. If the client and service are not able to communicate, see [Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90)).  \n  \n### To clean up after the sample  \n  \n-   Run Cleanup.bat in the samples folder after you have finished running the sample.  \n  \n    > [!NOTE]\n    >  This script does not remove service certificates on a client when running this sample across computers. If you have run Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) samples that use certificates across computers, be sure to clear the service certificates that have been installed in the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store. To do this, use the following command: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n <Fully Qualified Server Machine Name>` For example: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n server1.contoso.com`.  \n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,150],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Message Security User Name\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"WS Security\"\nms.assetid: c63cfc87-6b20-4949-93b3-bcd4b732b0a2","nodes":[{"content":"Message Security User Name","nodes":[{"pos":[0,26],"content":"Message Security User Name","nodes":[{"content":"Message Security User Name","pos":[0,26]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[157,183],"content":"Message Security User Name","linkify":"Message Security User Name","nodes":[{"content":"Message Security User Name","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"This sample demonstrates how to implement an application that uses WS-Security with username authentication for the client and requires server authentication using the server's X.509v3 certificate.","pos":[184,381]},{"content":"All application messages between the client and server are signed and encrypted.","pos":[382,462]},{"content":"By default, the username and password supplied by the client are used to logon to a valid Windows account.","pos":[463,569]},{"content":"This sample is based on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>WSHttpBinding<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/wshttpbinding.md)</ept>.","pos":[570,671],"source":" This sample is based on the [WSHttpBinding](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/wshttpbinding.md)."},{"content":"This sample consists of a client console program (Client.exe) and a service library (Service.dll) hosted by Internet Information Services (IIS).","pos":[672,816]},{"content":"The service implements a contract that defines a request-reply communication pattern.","pos":[817,902]},{"pos":[910,1017],"content":"[!NOTE]\n The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The setup procedure and build instructions for this sample are located at the end of this topic.","pos":[9,105]}]},{"content":"This sample also demonstrates:","pos":[1024,1054]},{"content":"The default mapping to Windows accounts so that additional authorization can be performed.","pos":[1064,1154]},{"content":"How to access the caller's identity information from the service code.","pos":[1164,1234]},{"content":"The service exposes a single endpoint for communicating with the service, which is defined using the configuration file Web.config. The endpoint consists of an address, a binding, and a contract.","pos":[1241,1436]},{"content":"The binding is configured with a standard <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>wsHttpBinding&gt;<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md)</ept>, which defaults to using message security.","pos":[1437,1616],"source":" The binding is configured with a standard [\\<wsHttpBinding>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md), which defaults to using message security."},{"content":"This sample sets the standard <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>wsHttpBinding&gt;<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md)</ept> to use client username authentication.","pos":[1617,1780],"source":" This sample sets the standard [\\<wsHttpBinding>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/wshttpbinding.md) to use client username authentication."},{"content":"The behavior specifies that the user credentials are to be used for service authentication.","pos":[1781,1872]},{"content":"The server certificate must contain the same value for the subject name as the <ph id=\"ph1\">`findValue`</ph> attribute in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph2\">\\&lt;</ph>serviceCredentials&gt;<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/servicecredentials.md)</ept>.","pos":[1873,2086],"source":" The server certificate must contain the same value for the subject name as the `findValue` attribute in the [\\<serviceCredentials>](../../../../docs/framework/configure-apps/file-schema/wcf/servicecredentials.md)."},{"content":"The client endpoint configuration consists of an absolute address for the service endpoint, the binding, and the contract.","pos":[3640,3762]},{"content":"The client binding is configured with the appropriate <ph id=\"ph1\">`securityMode`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`authenticationMode`</ph>.","pos":[3763,3857],"source":" The client binding is configured with the appropriate `securityMode` and `authenticationMode`."},{"content":"When running in a cross-computer scenario, the service endpoint address must be changed accordingly.","pos":[3858,3958]},{"content":"The client implementation sets the user name and password to use.","pos":[5833,5898]},{"content":"When you run the sample, the operation requests and responses are displayed in the client console window.","pos":[6405,6510]},{"content":"Press ENTER in the client window to shut down the client.","pos":[6511,6568]},{"content":"The Setup.bat batch file included with the MessageSecurity samples enables you to configure the server with a relevant certificate to run a hosted application that requires certificate-based security.","pos":[6770,6970]},{"content":"The batch file can be run in two modes.","pos":[6971,7010]},{"content":"To run the batch file in the single-computer mode, type <ph id=\"ph1\">`setup.bat`</ph> at the command line.","pos":[7011,7099],"source":" To run the batch file in the single-computer mode, type `setup.bat` at the command line."},{"content":"To run it in service mode type <ph id=\"ph1\">`setup.bat service`</ph>.","pos":[7100,7151],"source":" To run it in service mode type `setup.bat service`."},{"content":"You use this mode when running the sample across computers.","pos":[7152,7211]},{"content":"See the setup procedure at the end of this topic for details.","pos":[7212,7273]},{"content":"The following provides a brief overview of the different sections of the batch files.","pos":[7280,7365]},{"content":"Creating the server certificate","pos":[7375,7406]},{"content":"The following lines from the Setup.bat batch file create the server certificate to be used.","pos":[7417,7508]},{"content":"The %SERVER_NAME% variable specifies the server name.","pos":[7797,7850]},{"content":"The certificate is stored in the LocalMachine store.","pos":[7851,7903]},{"content":"If the Setup.bat batch file is run with an argument of service (such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`setup.bat service`</ph>) the %SERVER_NAME% contains the fully-qualified domain name of the computer.","pos":[7904,8072],"source":" If the Setup.bat batch file is run with an argument of service (such as `setup.bat service`) the %SERVER_NAME% contains the fully-qualified domain name of the computer."},{"content":"Otherwise it defaults to localhost.","pos":[8074,8109]},{"content":"Installing the server certificate into the client's trusted certificate store","pos":[8119,8196]},{"content":"The following line copies the server certificate into the client trusted people store.","pos":[8207,8293]},{"content":"This step is required because certificates generated by Makecert.exe are not implicitly trusted by the client system.","pos":[8294,8411]},{"content":"If you already have a certificate that is rooted in a client trusted root certificate—for example, a Microsoft-issued certificate—this step of populating the client certificate store with the server certificate is not required.","pos":[8412,8639]},{"content":"Granting permissions on the certificate's private key","pos":[8769,8822]},{"pos":[8833,9041],"content":"The following lines in the Setup.bat batch file make the server certificate stored in the LocalMachine store accessible to the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)]</ph> worker process account.","source":"The following lines in the Setup.bat batch file make the server certificate stored in the LocalMachine store accessible to the [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)] worker process account."},{"pos":[9543,9736],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf you are using a non-U.S. English edition of Windows you must edit the Setup.bat file and replace the `NT AUTHORITY\\NETWORK SERVICE` account name with your regional equivalent.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"If you are using a non-U.S. English edition of Windows you must edit the Setup.bat file and replace the <ph id=\"ph1\">`NT AUTHORITY\\NETWORK SERVICE`</ph> account name with your regional equivalent.","pos":[8,186],"source":"If you are using a non-U.S. English edition of Windows you must edit the Setup.bat file and replace the `NT AUTHORITY\\NETWORK SERVICE` account name with your regional equivalent."}]},{"pos":[9746,9782],"content":"To set up, build, and run the sample","linkify":"To set up, build, and run the sample","nodes":[{"content":"To set up, build, and run the sample","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[9792,9991],"content":"Ensure that you have performed the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md)</ept>.","source":"Ensure that you have performed the [One-Time Setup Procedure for the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/one-time-setup-procedure-for-the-wcf-samples.md)."},{"pos":[10001,10210],"content":"To build the C# or Visual Basic .NET edition of the solution, follow the instructions in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md)</ept>.","source":"To build the C# or Visual Basic .NET edition of the solution, follow the instructions in [Building the Windows Communication Foundation Samples](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/samples/building-the-samples.md)."},{"pos":[10220,10258],"content":"To run the sample on the same computer","linkify":"To run the sample on the same computer","nodes":[{"content":"To run the sample on the same computer","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"Ensure that the path includes the folder where Makecert.exe and FindPrivateKey.exe are located.","pos":[10268,10363]},{"content":"Run Setup.bat from the sample install folder in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges.","pos":[10373,10503]},{"content":"This installs all the certificates required for running the sample.","pos":[10504,10571]},{"pos":[10583,10893],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThe Setup.bat batch file is designed to be run from a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio. It requires that the path environment variable point to the directory where the SDK is installed. This environment variable is automatically set within a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"The Setup.bat batch file is designed to be run from a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio. It requires that the path environment variable point to the directory where the SDK is installed. This environment variable is automatically set within a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio.","pos":[8,303],"nodes":[{"content":"The Setup.bat batch file is designed to be run from a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio.","pos":[0,97]},{"content":"It requires that the path environment variable point to the directory where the SDK is installed.","pos":[98,195]},{"content":"This environment variable is automatically set within a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio.","pos":[196,295]}]}]},{"pos":[10903,11023],"content":"Verify access to the service using a browser by entering the address <ph id=\"ph1\">`http://localhost/servicemodelsamples/service.svc`</ph>.","source":"Verify access to the service using a browser by entering the address `http://localhost/servicemodelsamples/service.svc`."},{"content":"Launch Client.exe from \\client\\bin.","pos":[11031,11066]},{"content":"Client activity is displayed on the client console application.","pos":[11067,11130]},{"pos":[11140,11326],"content":"If the client and service are not able to communicate, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90))</ept>.","source":"If the client and service are not able to communicate, see [Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90))."},{"pos":[11336,11370],"content":"To run the sample across computers","linkify":"To run the sample across computers","nodes":[{"content":"To run the sample across computers","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Create a directory on the service computer.","pos":[11380,11423]},{"content":"Create a virtual application named servicemodelsamples for this directory by using the Internet Information Services management tool.","pos":[11424,11557]},{"content":"Copy the service program files from \\inetpub\\wwwroot\\servicemodelsamples to the virtual directory on the service computer.","pos":[11567,11689]},{"content":"Ensure that you copy the files in the \\bin subdirectory.","pos":[11690,11746]},{"content":"Also copy the Setup.bat and Cleanup.bat files to the service computer.","pos":[11747,11817]},{"content":"Create a directory on the client computer for the client binaries.","pos":[11827,11893]},{"content":"Copy the client program files to the client directory on the client computer.","pos":[11903,11980]},{"content":"Also copy the Setup.bat, Cleanup.bat, and ImportServiceCert.bat files to the client.","pos":[11981,12065]},{"content":"On the server, run <ph id=\"ph1\">`setup.bat service`</ph> in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges.","pos":[12075,12199],"source":"On the server, run `setup.bat service` in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges."},{"content":"Running <ph id=\"ph1\">`setup.bat`</ph> with the <ph id=\"ph2\">`service`</ph> argument creates a service certificate with the fully-qualified domain name of the computer and exports the service certificate to a file named Service.cer.","pos":[12200,12395],"source":" Running `setup.bat` with the `service` argument creates a service certificate with the fully-qualified domain name of the computer and exports the service certificate to a file named Service.cer."},{"pos":[12405,12591],"content":"Edit Web.config to reflect the new certificate name (in the findValue attribute in the serviceCertificate element) which is the same as the fully-qualified domain name of the computer<ph id=\"ph1\">`.`</ph>","source":"Edit Web.config to reflect the new certificate name (in the findValue attribute in the serviceCertificate element) which is the same as the fully-qualified domain name of the computer`.`"},{"content":"Copy the Service.cer file from the service directory to the client directory on the client computer.","pos":[12601,12701]},{"content":"In the Client.exe.config file on the client computer, change the address value of the endpoint to match the new address of your service.","pos":[12711,12847]},{"content":"On the client, run ImportServiceCert.bat in a Developer Command Prompt for Visual Studio opened with administrator privileges.","pos":[12856,12982]},{"content":"This imports the service certificate from the Service.cer file into the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store.","pos":[12983,13089]},{"content":"On the client computer, launch Client.exe from a command prompt.","pos":[13099,13163]},{"content":"If the client and service are not able to communicate, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90))</ept>.","pos":[13164,13350],"source":" If the client and service are not able to communicate, see [Troubleshooting Tips for WCF Samples](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.5/ms751511(v=vs.90))."},{"pos":[13360,13388],"content":"To clean up after the sample","linkify":"To clean up after the sample","nodes":[{"content":"To clean up after the sample","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"Run Cleanup.bat in the samples folder after you have finished running the sample.","pos":[13398,13479]},{"pos":[13491,14038],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis script does not remove service certificates on a client when running this sample across computers. If you have run Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) samples that use certificates across computers, be sure to clear the service certificates that have been installed in the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store. To do this, use the following command: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n <Fully Qualified Server Machine Name>` For example: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n server1.contoso.com`.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"This script does not remove service certificates on a client when running this sample across computers. If you have run Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) samples that use certificates across computers, be sure to clear the service certificates that have been installed in the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store. To do this, use the following command: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n <Fully Qualified Server Machine Name>` For example: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n server1.contoso.com`.","pos":[8,540],"nodes":[{"content":"This script does not remove service certificates on a client when running this sample across computers.","pos":[0,103]},{"content":"If you have run Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) samples that use certificates across computers, be sure to clear the service certificates that have been installed in the CurrentUser - TrustedPeople store.","pos":[104,315]},{"content":"To do this, use the following command: <ph id=\"ph1\">`certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n &lt;Fully Qualified Server Machine Name&gt;`</ph> For example: <ph id=\"ph2\">`certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n server1.contoso.com`</ph>.","pos":[316,532],"source":" To do this, use the following command: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n <Fully Qualified Server Machine Name>` For example: `certmgr -del -r CurrentUser -s TrustedPeople -c -n server1.contoso.com`."}]}]}]}