{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Runnable Instances Detection Period\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 4ea5c787-b638-47fd-bfc8-ede8c2898ce6\n---\n# Runnable Instances Detection Period\nThe SQL Workflow Instance Store runs an internal task that periodically wakes up and detects runnable or activatable instances in the persistence database. The **Runnable Instances Detection Period** property of the SQL Workflow Instance Store specifies the time period after which the SQL Workflow Instance Store runs a detection task to detect any runnable or activatable workflow instances in the persistence database after the previous detection cycle.  \n  \n Setting a shorter interval for this property reduces the time between the expiration of a timer associated with a workflow instance and the signaling of the event and subsequent loading of the instance. However, it also increases the processing load on a host and may not be desirable in scenarios where durable timers and/or host failures are rare. The type of the property is TimeSpan and the value of the property follows the format: hh:mm:ss. The minimum value for this property is 00:00:01. The default value for the property is 00:00:05.  \n  \n For more information detecting and activating runnable and activatable workflow instances, see [Instance Activation](instance-activation.md).\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,119],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Runnable Instances Detection Period\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 4ea5c787-b638-47fd-bfc8-ede8c2898ce6","nodes":[{"content":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","nodes":[{"pos":[0,35],"content":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","nodes":[{"content":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","pos":[0,35]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[126,161],"content":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","linkify":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","nodes":[{"content":"Runnable Instances Detection Period","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"The SQL Workflow Instance Store runs an internal task that periodically wakes up and detects runnable or activatable instances in the persistence database.","pos":[162,317]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Runnable Instances Detection Period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property of the SQL Workflow Instance Store specifies the time period after which the SQL Workflow Instance Store runs a detection task to detect any runnable or activatable workflow instances in the persistence database after the previous detection cycle.","pos":[318,618],"source":" The **Runnable Instances Detection Period** property of the SQL Workflow Instance Store specifies the time period after which the SQL Workflow Instance Store runs a detection task to detect any runnable or activatable workflow instances in the persistence database after the previous detection cycle."},{"content":"Setting a shorter interval for this property reduces the time between the expiration of a timer associated with a workflow instance and the signaling of the event and subsequent loading of the instance.","pos":[625,827]},{"content":"However, it also increases the processing load on a host and may not be desirable in scenarios where durable timers and/or host failures are rare.","pos":[828,974]},{"content":"The type of the property is TimeSpan and the value of the property follows the format: hh:mm:ss.","pos":[975,1071]},{"content":"The minimum value for this property is 00:00:01.","pos":[1072,1120]},{"content":"The default value for the property is 00:00:05.","pos":[1121,1168]},{"pos":[1175,1316],"content":"For more information detecting and activating runnable and activatable workflow instances, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Instance Activation<ept id=\"p1\">](instance-activation.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information detecting and activating runnable and activatable workflow instances, see [Instance Activation](instance-activation.md)."}]}