{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Security Negotiation and Timeouts\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 02a428f1-84e5-4d28-a11f-53ce31d63196\n---\n# Security Negotiation and Timeouts\nWhen clients and services authenticate, Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) supports a mode where the service credential is negotiated as part of authentication. In such scenarios, a potentially multi-leg exchange occurs between the client and the service to propagate the service credential to the client. The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.LocalServiceSecuritySettings.NegotiationTimeout%2A> property controls how long the multi-leg exchange can take to complete. However, this timeout only applies if the exchange actually takes more that a single request-response. In cases where the negotiation completes in a single round trip, the timeout does not apply.  \n  \n## See also\n\n- <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.LocalServiceSecuritySettings>\n- [How to: Set a Max Clock Skew](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/how-to-set-a-max-clock-skew.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,117],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Security Negotiation and Timeouts\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 02a428f1-84e5-4d28-a11f-53ce31d63196","nodes":[{"content":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","nodes":[{"pos":[0,33],"content":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","nodes":[{"content":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","pos":[0,33]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[124,157],"content":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","linkify":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","nodes":[{"content":"Security Negotiation and Timeouts","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"When clients and services authenticate, Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) supports a mode where the service credential is negotiated as part of authentication.","pos":[158,322]},{"content":"In such scenarios, a potentially multi-leg exchange occurs between the client and the service to propagate the service credential to the client.","pos":[323,467]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.LocalServiceSecuritySettings.NegotiationTimeout%2A&gt;</ph> property controls how long the multi-leg exchange can take to complete.","pos":[468,630],"source":" The <xref:System.ServiceModel.Channels.LocalServiceSecuritySettings.NegotiationTimeout%2A> property controls how long the multi-leg exchange can take to complete."},{"content":"However, this timeout only applies if the exchange actually takes more that a single request-response.","pos":[631,733]},{"content":"In cases where the negotiation completes in a single round trip, the timeout does not apply.","pos":[734,826]},{"pos":[835,843],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[914,1023],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Set a Max Clock Skew<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/how-to-set-a-max-clock-skew.md)</ept>","source":"[How to: Set a Max Clock Skew](../../../../docs/framework/wcf/feature-details/how-to-set-a-max-clock-skew.md)"}]}