{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Introduction to Extensibility\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"WCF [WCF], extensibility\"\n  - \"Windows Communication Foundation [WCF], extensibility\"\n  - \"extensibility [WCF]\"\nms.assetid: ef56c251-d63c-4b3f-944f-b0c67bfb0f68\n---\n# Introduction to Extensibility\nThe Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) application model is designed to solve the greater part of the communication requirements of any distributed application. But there are always scenarios that the default application model and system-provided implementations do not support. The WCF extensibility model is intended to support custom scenarios by enabling you to modify system behavior at every level, even to the point of replacing the entire application model. This topic outlines the various areas of extension and points to more information about each.  \n  \n## Areas to Extend  \n You can extend:  \n  \n-   The application runtime. This extends the dispatching and the processing of messages for the application. This area also includes extending the security system, the metadata system, the serialization system, and the bindings and binding elements that connect the application with the underlying channel system.  \n  \n-   The channel and channel runtime. This extends the system that functions at the message level, providing protocol, transport, and encoding support.  \n  \n-   The host runtime. This extends the relationship of the hosting application domain to the channel and application runtime.  \n  \n### Extending the Application Runtime  \n In WCF applications, there is a distinction between messages that are destined for a corresponding channel and messages that are destined for the application itself. Channel messages support some channel-related functionality, such as establishing a secure conversation or establishing a reliable session. These messages are not available to the application runtime; they are processed before the application layer is involved.  \n  \n Application messages contain data that is destined for a client or service operation that you or your customer has created. These messages are available to the application-level extension system in message or object form, depending upon your needs.  \n  \n All messages pass through the channel system; only application messages are passed from the channel system into the application. To create new channel-level functionality, you must extend the channel system. To create new application-level functionality, you must extend the service or client runtime (dispatchers and channel factories, respectively). For more information about extending the application runtime, see [Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md).  \n  \n#### Extending Security  \n To build custom security mechanisms such as tokens and credentials, you must extend the security system. For more information, see [Extending Security](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-security.md).  \n  \n#### Extending Metadata  \n To expose your metadata in differently than the default, you must extend the metadata system. For more information, see [Extending the Metadata System](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-metadata-system.md).  \n  \n#### Extending Serialization  \n To build custom encoders, provide data surrogates, or other work involving the customization of transferred data, you must extend the serialization system. For more information, see [Extending Encoders and Serializers](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-encoders-and-serializers.md).  \n  \n#### Extending Bindings  \n To associate transport or protocol channels with the application layer, you must extend the binding system. For more information, see [Extending Bindings](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-bindings.md).  \n  \n### Extending the Channel System  \n To create channels that support custom transports or protocol functionality, see [Extending the Channel Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-channel-layer.md).  \n  \n### Extending the Service Hosting System  \n To modify the service-wide application model, you must extend <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase?displayProperty=nameWithType> class. For more information, see [Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md).  \n  \n To modify the relationship between the hosting application domain and the service host, you must extend the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Activation.ServiceHostFactory?displayProperty=nameWithType> class. For more information, see [Extending Hosting Using ServiceHostFactory](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-hosting-using-servicehostfactory.md).  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Extending WCF](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/index.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,252],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Introduction to Extensibility\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"WCF [WCF], extensibility\"\n  - \"Windows Communication Foundation [WCF], extensibility\"\n  - \"extensibility [WCF]\"\nms.assetid: ef56c251-d63c-4b3f-944f-b0c67bfb0f68","nodes":[{"content":"Introduction to Extensibility","nodes":[{"pos":[0,29],"content":"Introduction to Extensibility","nodes":[{"content":"Introduction to Extensibility","pos":[0,29]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[259,288],"content":"Introduction to Extensibility","linkify":"Introduction to Extensibility","nodes":[{"content":"Introduction to Extensibility","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"The Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) application model is designed to solve the greater part of the communication requirements of any distributed application.","pos":[289,453]},{"content":"But there are always scenarios that the default application model and system-provided implementations do not support.","pos":[454,571]},{"content":"The WCF extensibility model is intended to support custom scenarios by enabling you to modify system behavior at every level, even to the point of replacing the entire application model.","pos":[572,758]},{"content":"This topic outlines the various areas of extension and points to more information about each.","pos":[759,852]},{"pos":[861,876],"content":"Areas to Extend","linkify":"Areas to Extend","nodes":[{"content":"Areas to Extend","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"You can extend:","pos":[880,895]},{"content":"The application runtime.","pos":[905,929]},{"content":"This extends the dispatching and the processing of messages for the application.","pos":[930,1010]},{"content":"This area also includes extending the security system, the metadata system, the serialization system, and the bindings and binding elements that connect the application with the underlying channel system.","pos":[1011,1215]},{"content":"The channel and channel runtime.","pos":[1225,1257]},{"content":"This extends the system that functions at the message level, providing protocol, transport, and encoding support.","pos":[1258,1371]},{"content":"The host runtime.","pos":[1381,1398]},{"content":"This extends the relationship of the hosting application domain to the channel and application runtime.","pos":[1399,1502]},{"pos":[1512,1545],"content":"Extending the Application Runtime","linkify":"Extending the Application Runtime","nodes":[{"content":"Extending the Application Runtime","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"In WCF applications, there is a distinction between messages that are destined for a corresponding channel and messages that are destined for the application itself.","pos":[1549,1714]},{"content":"Channel messages support some channel-related functionality, such as establishing a secure conversation or establishing a reliable session.","pos":[1715,1854]},{"content":"These messages are not available to the application runtime; they are processed before the application layer is involved.","pos":[1855,1976]},{"content":"Application messages contain data that is destined for a client or service operation that you or your customer has created.","pos":[1983,2106]},{"content":"These messages are available to the application-level extension system in message or object form, depending upon your needs.","pos":[2107,2231]},{"content":"All messages pass through the channel system; only application messages are passed from the channel system into the application.","pos":[2238,2366]},{"content":"To create new channel-level functionality, you must extend the channel system.","pos":[2367,2445]},{"content":"To create new application-level functionality, you must extend the service or client runtime (dispatchers and channel factories, respectively).","pos":[2446,2589]},{"content":"For more information about extending the application runtime, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md)</ept>.","pos":[2590,2800],"source":" For more information about extending the application runtime, see [Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md)."},{"pos":[2811,2829],"content":"Extending Security","linkify":"Extending Security","nodes":[{"content":"Extending Security","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"To build custom security mechanisms such as tokens and credentials, you must extend the security system.","pos":[2833,2937]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending Security<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-security.md)</ept>.","pos":[2938,3046],"source":" For more information, see [Extending Security](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-security.md)."},{"pos":[3057,3075],"content":"Extending Metadata","linkify":"Extending Metadata","nodes":[{"content":"Extending Metadata","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"To expose your metadata in differently than the default, you must extend the metadata system.","pos":[3079,3172]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending the Metadata System<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-metadata-system.md)</ept>.","pos":[3173,3303],"source":" For more information, see [Extending the Metadata System](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-metadata-system.md)."},{"pos":[3314,3337],"content":"Extending Serialization","linkify":"Extending Serialization","nodes":[{"content":"Extending Serialization","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"To build custom encoders, provide data surrogates, or other work involving the customization of transferred data, you must extend the serialization system.","pos":[3341,3496]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending Encoders and Serializers<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-encoders-and-serializers.md)</ept>.","pos":[3497,3637],"source":" For more information, see [Extending Encoders and Serializers](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-encoders-and-serializers.md)."},{"pos":[3648,3666],"content":"Extending Bindings","linkify":"Extending Bindings","nodes":[{"content":"Extending Bindings","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"To associate transport or protocol channels with the application layer, you must extend the binding system.","pos":[3670,3777]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending Bindings<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-bindings.md)</ept>.","pos":[3778,3886],"source":" For more information, see [Extending Bindings](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-bindings.md)."},{"pos":[3896,3924],"content":"Extending the Channel System","linkify":"Extending the Channel System","nodes":[{"content":"Extending the Channel System","pos":[0,28]}]},{"pos":[3928,4109],"content":"To create channels that support custom transports or protocol functionality, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending the Channel Layer<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-channel-layer.md)</ept>.","source":"To create channels that support custom transports or protocol functionality, see [Extending the Channel Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-the-channel-layer.md)."},{"pos":[4119,4155],"content":"Extending the Service Hosting System","linkify":"Extending the Service Hosting System","nodes":[{"content":"Extending the Service Hosting System","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"To modify the service-wide application model, you must extend <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[4159,4299],"source":"To modify the service-wide application model, you must extend <xref:System.ServiceModel.ServiceHostBase?displayProperty=nameWithType> class."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md)</ept>.","pos":[4300,4470],"source":" For more information, see [Extending ServiceHost and the Service Model Layer](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-servicehost-and-the-service-model-layer.md)."},{"content":"To modify the relationship between the hosting application domain and the service host, you must extend the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.ServiceModel.Activation.ServiceHostFactory?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[4477,4677],"source":"To modify the relationship between the hosting application domain and the service host, you must extend the <xref:System.ServiceModel.Activation.ServiceHostFactory?displayProperty=nameWithType> class."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending Hosting Using ServiceHostFactory<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-hosting-using-servicehostfactory.md)</ept>.","pos":[4678,4834],"source":" For more information, see [Extending Hosting Using ServiceHostFactory](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/extending-hosting-using-servicehostfactory.md)."},{"pos":[4843,4851],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[4855,4918],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extending WCF<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/index.md)</ept>","source":"[Extending WCF](../../../docs/framework/wcf/extending/index.md)"}]}