{"content":"---\ntitle: \"IdentityModel Exceptions | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-clr\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nms.assetid: 4ef34497-8ff5-4621-b773-7731cc721231\ncaps.latest.revision: 7\nauthor: \"Erikre\"\nms.author: \"erikre\"\nmanager: \"erikre\"\n---\n# IdentityModel Exceptions\nThis topic lists all exceptions generated by IdentityModel.  \n  \n## Exception List  \n  \n|Resource Code|Current String|  \n|-------------------|--------------------|  \n|ValueMustBeOf2Types|The value of this argument must be one of these two types.|  \n|SAMLSubjectNameIdentifierRequiresNameValue|The 'Name' specified for a SamlNameIdentifier cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderEndSecurityNegotiation|The IssuanceTokenProvider has completed the security negotiation.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityNewServerSessionKeyIssued|A new security session key was issued by the server.|  \n|SAMLAttributeMissingNameAttributeOnRead|The 'Name' for the SamlAttribute being read is missing or is of length 0.|  \n|UnknownICryptoType|The ICrypto implementation is not supported.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityTokenProviderClosed|Security Token Provider was closed.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadAdvice|Failed to load the \\<saml:advice> element.|  \n|SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationMethodOnRead|The 'AuthenticationMethod' attribute being read for a SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing or of length 0.|  \n|UnsupportedTransformAlgorithm|Unsupported transform or canonicalization algorithm.|  \n|SAMLAudienceRestrictionShouldHaveOneAudience|A SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition must contain at least one Audience (URI).|  \n|SAMLEvidenceShouldHaveOneAssertion|SamlEvidence must reference at least one SamlAssertion either by Id or reference.|  \n|SAMLAudienceRestrictionInvalidAudienceValueOnRead|The SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition being read is missing a value in the 'Audience' element.|  \n|X509ChainBuildFail|The specific X.509 certificate chain building failed. The certificate that was used has a trust chain that cannot be verified. Replace the certificate or change the certificateValidationMode.|  \n|XDCannotFindValueInDictionaryString|The specific value id not found in the dictionary string.|  \n|TraceCodeImportSecurityChannelBindingEntry|Starting Security ImportChannelBinding.|  \n|PrivateKeyExchangeNotSupported|The private key does not support the exchange KeySpec.|  \n|TokenProviderUnableToGetToken|The specific token provider was unable to provide a security token.|  \n|SAMLEntityCannotBeNullOrEmpty|The specific SamlAssertion entity cannot be null or empty.|  \n|SAMLAssertionRequireOneStatement|A SamlAssertion requires at least one statement. Ensure that you have added at least one SamlStatement to the SamlAssertion you are creating.|  \n|AESInvalidInputBlockSize|The input size must be a multiple of specific bytes.|  \n|AESCryptAcquireContextFailed|Failed to acquire the CSP context.|  \n|SAMLAssertionRequireOneStatementOnRead|The SamlAssertion being read did not contain any SamlStatement. A SamlAssertion must contain at least one SamlStatement.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedFaultReceived|The client security session received a session closed fault from the server.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderRedirectApplied|IssuanceTokenProvider applied a redirection header.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedFaultSendFailure|A failure occurred when sending a security session closed fault to the client.|  \n|ValueMustBeZero|The value of this argument must be 0.|  \n|SAMLUnableToResolveSignatureKey|Unable to resolve SecurityKeyIdentifier found in the SamlAssertion signature. The SamlAssertion signature cannot be validated for the specific Issuer.|  \n|X509IsNotInTrustedStore|The specific X.509 certificate is not in the trusted people store.|  \n|SAMLElementNotRecognized|The specific element is not supported.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingResourceAttributeOnRead|The 'Resource' attribute for the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SamlTokenMissingSignature|The SamlAssertion is not signed. SamlAssertions can be signed by setting the SigningCredentials.|  \n|ExpectedElementMissing|The expected element with the specific namespace is missing.|  \n|NoKeyIdentifierClauseFound|No clause of the specific type was found in the SecurityKeyIdentifier.|  \n|MissingPrivateKey|The private key is not present in the X.509 certificate.|  \n|UnexpectedEOFFromReader|Unexpected EOF from XML reader.|  \n|UnsupportedKeyDerivationAlgorithm|The specific key derivation algorithm is not supported.|  \n|TokenDoesNotSupportKeyIdentifierClauseCreation|The specific token does not support the specific key identifier clause creation.|  \n|LastMessageNumberExceeded|A violation of sequence number protocol has been detected.|  \n|SymmetricKeyLengthTooShort|The length of the symmetric key specified is too short.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingAuthorityKindOnRead|The SamlAuthorityBinding being read was found to contain an 'AuthorityKind' that was missing or of length 0.  This is not allowed.|  \n|XmlTokenBufferIsEmpty|XmlTokenBuffer is empty.|  \n|InvalidXmlQualifiedName|An Xml qualified name was expected, but an invalid name  was found.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityKindMissingName|The XmlQualifiedName that represents the 'AuthorityKind' in the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|AESCryptEncryptFailed|Failed to encrypt the specific data.|  \n|AuthorizationContextCreated|Authorization Context with the specific id is created.|  \n|SamlSerializerUnableToReadSecurityKeyIdentifier|The SamlSerializer does not contain a SecurityTokenSerializer capable of reading the SecurityKeyIdentifier. If you are using a custom SecurityKeyIdentifier, you must provide a custom SecurityTokenSerializer.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderServiceTokenCacheFull|IssuanceTokenProvider reduced the service token cache.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityTokenProviderOpened|Security Token Provider was opened.|  \n|PublicKeyNotRSA|The public key is not an RSA key.|  \n|InvalidReaderState|The specific state is invalid for the supplied input reader.|  \n|UnableToResolveReferenceUriForSignature|Unable to resolve the specific URI in the signature to compute the digest.|  \n|EmptyBase64Attribute|An empty value was found for the required base64 attribute name and namespace.|  \n|SAMLSubjectRequiresConfirmationMethodWhenConfirmationDataOrKeyInfoIsSpecified|The SAML SubjectConfirmation requires a Confirmation method when the Confirmation Data or KeyInfo is specified.|  \n|SAMLAudienceRestrictionShouldHaveOneAudienceOnRead|The SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition being read must contain at least one 'Audience' value. None were found.|  \n|TokenProviderUnableToRenewToken|The specific token provider was unable to renew the security token.|  \n|AESIVLengthNotSupported|The specific bits IV is not supported. Only 128 bits IV is supported.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingAuthorityKind|A SamlAuthorityBinding must contain an 'AuthorityKind' that is not null.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionDemuxFailure|The incoming message is not part of an existing security session.|  \n|TokenRenewalNotSupported|The specific token provider does not support token renewal.|  \n|AtLeastOneReferenceRequired|At least one reference is required in a signature.|  \n|SAMLSignatureAlreadyRead|The signature is already read in the SAML assertion.|  \n|AlgorithmAndPrivateKeyMisMatch|The algorithm specified and the private key do not match.|  \n|EmptyTransformChainNotSupported|The empty transform chain is not supported.|  \n|SspiWrapperEncryptDecryptAssert1|SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&#124;'offset' is out of range.|  \n|SspiWrapperEncryptDecryptAssert2|SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&#124;'size' is out of range. SecurityTokenManagerCannotCreateAuthenticatorForRequirement=The security token manager cannot create a token authenticator for the specific requirement.|  \n|UnableToCreateKeyedHashAlgorithm|Unable to create a KeyedHashAlgorithm from the specific value for the specific signature algorithm.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadAssertion|The \\<saml:assertion> element failed to load.|  \n|X509FindValueMismatchMulti|The specific X509FindType requires the type of the argument findValue to be one of the 2 values. The argument findValue is of another type.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityIdentityDeterminationSuccess|Identity was determined for an EndpointAddress.|  \n|UndefinedUseOfPrefixAtElement|The specific prefix that is used at the element has no namespace defined.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionResponderOperationFailure|Security session operation failed at the server.|  \n|CannotFindCert|Unable to find the X.509 certificate using the specific search criteria: StoreName , StoreLocation, FindType, FindValue.|  \n|X509InvalidUsageTime|The specific X.509 certificate usage time is invalid. The usage time does not fall between the required NotBefore time and NotAfter time.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityIdentityDeterminationFailure|Identity cannot be determined for an EndpointAddress.|  \n|AsyncObjectAlreadyEnded|The End method has already been called on this asynchronous result object.|  \n|ExternalDictionaryDoesNotContainAllRequiredStrings|The external dictionary does not contain definitions for all the required strings. The specific string is not available in the remote dictionary.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionKeyRenewalFaultReceived|The client security session received a key renewal fault from the server.|  \n|SAMLActionNameRequired|The string that represents the SamlAction cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|SignatureVerificationFailed|The signature verification failed.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityContextTokenCacheFull|The SecurityContextSecurityToken cache is full.|  \n|SAMLAssertionMissingMajorVersionAttributeOnRead|The MajorVersion for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.|  \n|SamlAttributeClaimRightShouldBePossessProperty|This SamlAttribute constructor requires that the Right of the Claim have the value System.IdentityModel.Claims.Rights.PossessProperty.|  \n|AuthorizationPolicyEvaluated|Policy with the specific id is evaluated.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadCondtions|The \\<saml:conditions> element failed to load.|  \n|AESKeyLengthNotSupported|The specific bits key is not supported. Only 128, 192 and 256 bits key is supported.|  \n|UserNameCannotBeEmpty|The username cannot be empty.|  \n|AlgorithmAndPublicKeyMisMatch|The algorithm specified and the public key do not match.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadCondtion|The \\<saml:conditions> element failed to load.|  \n|SamlAssertionMissingSigningCredentials|SigningCredentials have not been set on the SamlAssertion. SamlAssertions must be signed, please set a valid SigningCredentials on the SamlAssertion to proceed.|  \n|SspiPayloadNotEncrypted|The binary data was not encrypted with the SSPI security context.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionShouldHaveOneActionOnRead|The SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement that is being read does not contain any SamlAction.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityBindingSecureOutgoingMessageFailure|The security protocol cannot secure the outgoing message.|  \n|UndefinedUseOfPrefixAtAttribute|The specific prefix used at the specific attribute has no namespace defined.|  \n|NoInputIsSetForCanonicalization|No input is set for writing canonicalized output.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionAdded|A pending security session is added to the server.|  \n|AsyncCallbackException|An AsyncCallback threw an exception.|  \n|PrivateKeyNotRSA|The private key is not a RSA key.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionKeyRenewed|The client security session renewed the session key.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingDecisionAttributeOnRead|The 'Decision' for the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SAMLAttributeNameAttributeRequired|The 'Name' specified for a SamlAttribute cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|SamlSerializerRequiresExternalSerializers|The SamlSerializer requires a SecurityTokenSerializer to serialize the SecurityKeyIdentifier present in the token.|  \n|UnableToResolveKeyReference|The token resolver is unable to resolve the specific security key reference.|  \n|UnsupportedKeyWrapAlgorithm|The specific key wrap algorithm is not supported.|  \n|SAMLAssertionMissingIssuerAttributeOnRead|The 'Issuer' for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderUsingCachedToken|The IssuanceTokenProvider used the cached service token.|  \n|AESCryptGetKeyParamFailed|Failed to get the specific key parameter.|  \n|InvalidNamespaceForEmptyPrefix|The namespace is invalid for the empty prefix.|  \n|AESCipherModeNotSupported|The specific cipher mode is not supported. Only CBC is supported.|  \n|ArgumentCannotBeEmptyString|The argument must be a non-empty string.|  \n|SAMLAssertionMissingMinorVersionAttributeOnRead|The MinorVersion for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.|  \n|SpecifiedStringNotAvailableInDictionary|The specified string is not an entry in the current dictionary.|  \n|KerberosApReqInvalidOrOutOfMemory|The AP-REQ is invalid or the system does not have enough memory.|  \n|FailLogonUser|The LogonUser failed for the specified user. Ensure that the user has a valid Windows account.|  \n|ValueMustBeNonNegative|The value of this argument must be non-negative.|  \n|X509ValidationFail|The specified X.509 certificate validation failed.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorOperationSuccess|The security session operation completed successfully at the client.|  \n|SAMLActionNameRequiredOnRead|The string that is read for the SamlAction is missing or is of length 0.|  \n|KerberosMultilegsNotSupported|Identity is specified as UPN. Authenticating a service running under a user account requires Kerberos multi-legs, which is unsupported.|  \n|SAMLAssertionIdRequired|The 'assertionId' for a SamlAssertion cannot be null or empty.|  \n|InvalidOperationForWriterState|The specified operation is invalid in the specified XmlWriter state.|  \n|CannotValidateSecurityTokenType|The specified security token authenticator cannot validate a token of the specified type.|  \n|X509FindValueMismatch|The specified X509FindType requires the type of the argument findValue to be the specified value. The argument findValue is of another type.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionCloseSent|A Close message was sent by the client security session.|  \n|SuiteDoesNotAcceptAlgorithm|The specified algorithm is not accepted for the specified  operation by the specified algorithm suite|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorOperationFailure|The client security session operation failed.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadStatement|Failed to load a SamlStatement.|  \n|InnerReaderMustBeAtElement|The inner reader must be at the element.|  \n|UnableToCreateTokenReference|Unable to create a security token reference.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityBindingIncomingMessageVerified|The security protocol verified the incoming message.|  \n|ObjectIsReadOnly|The object is read-only.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionPreviousKeyDiscarded|The client security session discarded the previous session key.|  \n|SAMLTokenTimeInvalid|The SamlToken is not time valid. The current time is outside the Effective and Expiration time of the token.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityIdentityVerificationSuccess|Identity verification succeeded.|  \n|SigningTokenHasNoKeys|The specified signing token has no keys.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityIdentityVerificationFailure|Identity verification failed.|  \n|AESCryptImportKeyFailed|Failed to import the key material.|  \n|FailInitializeSecurityContext|InitializeSecurityContent failed. Ensure the service principal name is correct.|  \n|TraceCodeStreamSecurityUpgradeAccepted|The stream security upgrade was accepted successfully.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingRequiresLocation|The 'Location' attribute that is specified on the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|PublicKeyNotDSA|The public key is not a DSA key.|  \n|ImpersonationLevelNotSupported|The authentication modes using Kerberos do not support the specified impersonation level. Specify a valid identification or impersonation level.|  \n|RequiredTargetNotSigned|The element with the specified id is required to be signed, but was not.|  \n|SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationInstanceOnRead|The 'AuthenticationInstant' attribute being read for a SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SAMLEvidenceShouldHaveOneAssertionOnRead|The SamlEvidence being read did not contain either a reference to or an embedded SamlAssertion.|  \n|LengthOfArrayToConvertMustGreaterThanZero|The length of the array to convert to an integer must be greater than 0.|  \n|InvalidAsyncResult|Invalid AsyncResult.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderRemovedCachedToken|The IssuanceTokenProvider removed the expired service token.|  \n|IncorrectUserNameFormat|The username is in an invalid format. The username format must be in the form of \"username' or 'domain\\\\\\username'.|  \n|TraceCodeExportSecurityChannelBindingEntry|Starting Security ExportChannelBinding.|  \n|UnsupportedInputTypeForTransform|The specified input type is not supported for the transform.|  \n|CannotFindDocumentRoot|Cannot find the root of the document.|  \n|XmlBufferQuotaExceeded|The size necessary to buffer the XML content exceeded the buffer quota.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedResponseSendFailure|A failure occurred when sending a security session Close response to the client.|  \n|UnableToResolveReferenceInSamlSignature|Unable to resolve the specified reference in the SAML signature with AssertionID.|  \n|SAMLSubjectRequiresNameIdentifierOrConfirmationMethod|A SamlSubject requires that a 'NameIdentifier' or 'ConfirmationMethod' be specified. Both were missing.|  \n|SAMLAttributeMissingNamespaceAttributeOnRead|The 'Namespace' for the SamlAttribute being read is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SAMLSubjectConfirmationClauseMissingConfirmationMethodOnRead|A 'ConfirmationMethod' cannot be found on the SamlSubjectConfirmation being read.|  \n|SecurityTokenRequirementHasInvalidTypeForProperty|The token requirement has an unexpected type for the specified property. The expected property type is of another value.|  \n|TraceCodeNegotiationTokenProviderAttached|NegotiationTokenProvider was attached.|  \n|TraceCodeSpnegoClientNegotiationCompleted|SpnegoTokenProvider completed SSPI negotiation.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadUnknownElement|The selected SamlSerializer is unable to deserialize this element. Please register a custom SamlSerializer to deserialize custom elements.|  \n|CreateSequenceRefused|The create sequence request has been refused by the RM Destination.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionRedirectApplied|The client security session was redirected.|  \n|SecurityTokenRequirementDoesNotContainProperty|The token requirement does not contain the specified property.|  \n|SAMLAttributeValueCannotBeNull|One of the attributeValues found in the SamlAttribute was found to be a null value. Ensure that lists are not null when creating the SamlAttribute.|  \n|ValueMustBeGreaterThanZero|The value of this argument must be greater than 0.|  \n|TraceCodeNegotiationAuthenticatorAttached|NegotiationTokenAuthenticator was attached.|  \n|ValueMustBePositive||  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionShouldHaveOneAction|A SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement must have at least one SamlAction.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityTokenAuthenticatorClosed|Security Token Authenticator was closed.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityAuditWrittenSuccess|The security audit log is written successfully.|  \n|PrivateKeyNotDSA|The private key is not a DSA key.|  \n|MessageNumberRollover|The maximum sequence number for this sequence has been exceeded.|  \n|AESPaddingModeNotSupported|The specified padding mode is not supported. Only PKCS7 and ISO10126 is supported.|  \n|SAMLSubjectRequiresNameIdentifierOrConfirmationMethodOnRead|The required 'NameIdentifier' and the 'ConfirmationMethod' elements are not found for the SamlSubject being read.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityAuditWrittenFailure|A failure occurred while writing to the security audit log.|  \n|UnsupportedCryptoAlgorithm|The specified crypto algorithm is not supported in this context.|  \n|SigningTokenHasNoKeysSupportingTheAlgorithmSuite|The signing token has no key that supports the specified algorithm suite.|  \n|SAMLNameIdentifierMissingIdentifierValueOnRead|The 'Identifier' string for the SamlNameIdentifier being read is missing.|  \n|SAMLSubjectStatementRequiresSubject|The SAML Subject Statement requires a SAML subject to be specified.|  \n|TraceCodeSslClientCertMissing|The remote SSL client failed to provide a required certificate.|  \n|SAMLTokenVersionNotSupported|The specified major version and minor version are not supported.|  \n|TraceCodeConfigurationIsReadOnly|The configuration is read-only.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionRenewFaultSendFailure|A failure occurred when sending a renewal fault on the security session key to the client.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityInactiveSessionFaulted|An inactive security session was faulted by the server.|  \n|SAMLUnableToLoadAttribute|Failed to load a SamlAttribute.|  \n|Psha1KeyLengthInvalid|The specified PSHA1 key length is invalid.|  \n|KeyIdentifierCannotCreateKey|This SecurityKeyIdentifier does not have any clause that can create a key.|  \n|X509IsInUntrustedStore|The specified X.509 certificate is in an untrusted certificate store.|  \n|UnexpectedXmlChildNode|The specified XML child node of specified type is unexpected for the specified element.|  \n|TokenDoesNotMeetKeySizeRequirements|The key size requirements for the specified algorithm suite are not met by the specified token.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorStartOperation|A security session operation was started at the client.|  \n|InvalidHexString|Invalid hexadecimal string format.|  \n|SamlAttributeClaimResourceShouldBeAString|This SamlAttribute constructor requires that the resource of the claim is of type 'string'.|  \n|SamlSigningTokenNotFound|The SamlAssertion is signed but the token that signed the SamlAssertion cannot be found. Ensure that the SecurityTokenResolver contains the token that signed the SamlAssertion.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySpnToSidMappingFailure|The ServicePrincipalName could not be mapped to a SecurityIdentifier.|  \n|UnableToCreateSignatureFormatterFromAsymmetricCrypto|Unable to create a signature formatter for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionClosedFaultSent|The server security session sent a session closed fault to the client.|  \n|UnableToFindPrefix|Unable to find the prefix for the specified visibly used prefix at the specified element.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityTokenAuthenticatorOpened|Security Token Authenticator was opened.|  \n|RequiredAttributeMissing|The specified attribute is required on the specified element.|  \n|LocalIdCannotBeEmpty|The localId cannot be empty. Specify a valid 'localId'.|  \n|ValueMustBeInRange|The value of this argument must fall within the specified range.|  \n|TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderBeginSecurityNegotiation|IssuanceTokenProvider started a new security negotiation.|  \n|InvalidNtMapping|The specified X.509 certificate cannot be mapped to a Windows account. The UPN subject alternate name is required.|  \n|AESCryptSetKeyParamFailed|Failed to set the specified key parameter.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedResponseReceived|The client security session received a closed response from the server.|  \n|UnableToCreateSignatureDeformatterFromAsymmetricCrypto|Unable to create a signature deformatter for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.|  \n|TraceCodeIdentityModelAsyncCallbackThrewException|An asynchronous callback threw an exception.|  \n|LengthMustBeGreaterThanZero|The length of this argument must be greater than 0.|  \n|FoundMultipleCerts|Found multiple X.509 certificates using the specified search criteria: StoreName, StoreLocation, FindType, FindValue. Provide a more specific find value.|  \n|AtLeastOneTransformRequired|The Transforms element must contain at least one transform.|  \n|SAMLTokenNotSerialized|The SamlAssertion could not be serialized to XML. Please see inner exception for details.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityBindingOutgoingMessageSecured|The security protocol secured the outgoing message.|  \n|KeyIdentifierClauseDoesNotSupportKeyCreation|This SecurityKeyIdentifierClause does not support key creation.|  \n|UnableToResolveTokenReference|The token resolver is unable to resolve the specified token reference.|  \n|UnsupportedEncryptionAlgorithm|The specified encryption algorithm is not supported.|  \n|SamlSerializerUnableToWriteSecurityKeyIdentifier|The SamlSerializer does not contain a SecurityTokenSerializer capable of serializing the given SecurityKeyIdentifier. If you are using a custom SecurityKeyIdentifier, you must provide a custom SecurityTokenSerializer.|  \n|SAMLAttributeShouldHaveOneValue|No attribute values were found. A SamlAttribute attribute must have at least one attribute value.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityBindingVerifyIncomingMessageFailure|Security protocol cannot verify the incoming message.|  \n|SamlSigningTokenMissing|The SamlAssertion passed to the SamlSecurityTokenAuthenticator does not contain a signing token.|  \n|NoPrivateKeyAvailable|No private key is available.|  \n|ValueMustBeOne|The value of this argument must be 1.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionRemoved|A pending security session was made active by the server.|  \n|TraceCodeImportSecurityChannelBindingExit|Finished Security ImportChannelBinding.|  \n|X509CertStoreLocationNotValid|The StoreLocation must be either LocalMachine or CurrentUser.|  \n|SettingdMayBeModifiedOnlyWhenTheWriterIsInStartState|The writer settings may be modified only when the writer is in the Start state.|  \n|ArgumentInvalidCertificate|The certificate is invalid.|  \n|DigestVerificationFailedForReference|Digest verification failed for the specified Reference.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingRequiresBinding|The 'Binding' attribute specified on the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|AESInsufficientOutputBuffer|The output buffer must be greater than the specified bytes.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingBindingOnRead|The 'Binding' attribute for the SamlAuthorityBinding being read is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingInvalidAuthorityKind|The SamlAuthorityBinding being read has an invalid AuthorityKind. The format of the AuthorityKind must be a QName.|  \n|ProvidedNetworkCredentialsForKerberosHasInvalidUserName|The NetworkCredentials provided for the Kerberos Token does not have a valid UserName.|  \n|SSPIPackageNotSupported|The specified SSPI package is not supported.|  \n|TokenCancellationNotSupported|The specified token provider does not support token cancellation.|  \n|UnboundPrefixInQName|An unbound prefix is used in the specified qualified name.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionResourceRequired|The 'resource' specified to the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityNegotiationProcessingFailure|Service security negotiation processing failure.|  \n|SAMLAssertionIssuerRequired|The 'Issuer' specified for a SamlAssertion cannot be null or empty.|  \n|UnableToCreateHashAlgorithmFromAsymmetricCrypto|Unable to create a HashAlgorithm for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.|  \n|SamlUnableToExtractSubjectKey|The SecurityKeyIdentifier that was found in the SamlSubject cannot be resolved to a SecurityToken. The SecurityTokenResolver must contain a SecurityToken that the SecurityKeyIdentifier resolves to.|  \n|ChildNodeTypeMissing|The specified XML element does not have a child of the specified type.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionClosed|The pending security session was closed by the server.|  \n|TraceCodeSecuritySessionCloseResponseSent|The server security session sent a Close response to the client.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityIdentityHostNameNormalizationFailure|The HostName portion of an endpoint address cannot be normalized.|  \n|FailAcceptSecurityContext|The AcceptSecurityContext failed.|  \n|EmptyXmlElementError|The specified element cannot be empty.|  \n|PrefixNotDefinedForNamespace|A prefix for the specified namespace is not defined in this context and cannot be declared.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionHasMoreThanOneEvidence|The SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read was found to contain more than one Evidence. This is not allowed.|  \n|SamlTokenAuthenticatorCanOnlyProcessSamlTokens|The SamlSecurityTokenAuthenticator can only process SamlSecurityTokens. The specified SecurityTokenType was received .|  \n|SAMLAttributeStatementMissingAttributeOnRead|The SamlAttributeStatement being read does not contain any 'SamlAttribute' elements. This is not allowed.|  \n|CouldNotFindNamespaceForPrefix|Cannot look up the namespace for the specified prefix.|  \n|TraceCodeExportSecurityChannelBindingExit|Finished Security ExportChannelBinding.|  \n|AESCryptDecryptFailed|Failed to decrypt the specified data.|  \n|SAMLAttributeNamespaceAttributeRequired|The 'Namespace' specified for a SamlAttribute cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|TraceCodeSpnegoServiceNegotiationCompleted|SpnegoTokenAuthenticator completed SSPI negotiation.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionRenewalFaultSent|The server security session sent a key renewal fault to the client.|  \n|AlgorithmMismatchForTransform|A mismatch occurred on the algorithm for the transform.|  \n|UserNameAuthenticationFailed|Authentication of a username/password using the specified mechanism failed. User is not authenticated.|  \n|SamlInvalidSigningToken|The SamlAssertion has been signed with a token that was not validated according to the protocol. If you are using X.509 certificates, examine your validation semantics.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionKeyUpdated|The security session key was updated by the server.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionCloseReceived|The server security session received a Close message from the client.|  \n|SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingSubject|The SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing the required SamlSubjectStatement.|  \n|UnexpectedEndOfFile|Unexpected end of file.|  \n|UnsupportedAlgorithmForCryptoOperation|The specified algorithm is not supported for the specified operation.|  \n|XmlLangAttributeMissing|The required xml:lang attribute is missing.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityImpersonationSuccess|Security Impersonation succeeded at the server.|  \n|SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingLocationOnRead|The 'Location' attribute for the SamlAuthorityBinding being read is missing or of length 0.|  \n|SAMLAttributeStatementMissingSubjectOnRead|The 'SamlSubject' element for the SamlAttributeStatement is missing.|  \n|SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingSubjectOnRead|The 'SamlSubject' element for SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing.|  \n|SAMLBadSchema|While reading a SamlAssertion this specified element was found not to comply with the schema.|  \n|SAMLAssertionIDIsInvalid|The specified 'assertionId' for a SamlAssertion must start with a letter or '_'.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityActiveServerSessionRemoved|An active security session was removed by the server.|  \n|UnableToCreateKeyedHashAlgorithmFromSymmetricCrypto|Unable to create a keyedHashAlgorithm for the specified algorithm from the specified symmetric crypto.|  \n|SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationMethod|The 'AuthenticationMethod' specified for a SamlAuthenticationStatement cannot be null or of length 0.|  \n|TraceCodeSecurityImpersonationFailure|Security impersonation failed at the server.|  \n|Default|(Default)|  \n|UnsupportedNodeTypeInReader|The specified node type with the specified name is not supported.|","nodes":[{"pos":[12,53],"content":"IdentityModel Exceptions | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"IdentityModel Exceptions | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[351,375],"content":"IdentityModel Exceptions","linkify":"IdentityModel Exceptions","nodes":[{"content":"IdentityModel Exceptions","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"This topic lists all exceptions generated by IdentityModel.","pos":[376,435]},{"pos":[444,458],"content":"Exception List","linkify":"Exception List","nodes":[{"content":"Exception List","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Resource Code","pos":[465,478]},{"content":"Current String","pos":[479,493]},{"content":"ValueMustBeOf2Types","pos":[543,562]},{"content":"The value of this argument must be one of these two types.","pos":[563,621]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectNameIdentifierRequiresNameValue","pos":[626,668]},{"content":"The 'Name' specified for a SamlNameIdentifier cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[669,745]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderEndSecurityNegotiation","pos":[750,802]},{"content":"The IssuanceTokenProvider has completed the security negotiation.","pos":[803,868]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityNewServerSessionKeyIssued","pos":[873,915]},{"content":"A new security session key was issued by the server.","pos":[916,968]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeMissingNameAttributeOnRead","pos":[973,1012]},{"content":"The 'Name' for the SamlAttribute being read is missing or is of length 0.","pos":[1013,1086]},{"content":"UnknownICryptoType","pos":[1091,1109]},{"content":"The ICrypto implementation is not supported.","pos":[1110,1154]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityTokenProviderClosed","pos":[1159,1195]},{"content":"Security Token Provider was closed.","pos":[1196,1231]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadAdvice","pos":[1236,1258]},{"content":"Failed to load the <ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>saml:advice&gt; element.","pos":[1259,1301],"source":"Failed to load the \\<saml:advice> element."},{"content":"SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationMethodOnRead","pos":[1306,1366]},{"content":"The 'AuthenticationMethod' attribute being read for a SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing or of length 0.","pos":[1367,1475]},{"content":"UnsupportedTransformAlgorithm","pos":[1480,1509]},{"content":"Unsupported transform or canonicalization algorithm.","pos":[1510,1562]},{"content":"SAMLAudienceRestrictionShouldHaveOneAudience","pos":[1567,1611]},{"content":"A SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition must contain at least one Audience (URI).","pos":[1612,1688]},{"content":"SAMLEvidenceShouldHaveOneAssertion","pos":[1693,1727]},{"content":"SamlEvidence must reference at least one SamlAssertion either by Id or reference.","pos":[1728,1809]},{"content":"SAMLAudienceRestrictionInvalidAudienceValueOnRead","pos":[1814,1863]},{"content":"The SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition being read is missing a value in the 'Audience' element.","pos":[1864,1957]},{"content":"X509ChainBuildFail","pos":[1962,1980]},{"content":"The specific X.509 certificate chain building failed.","pos":[1981,2034]},{"content":"The certificate that was used has a trust chain that cannot be verified.","pos":[2035,2107]},{"content":"Replace the certificate or change the certificateValidationMode.","pos":[2108,2172]},{"content":"XDCannotFindValueInDictionaryString","pos":[2177,2212]},{"content":"The specific value id not found in the dictionary string.","pos":[2213,2270]},{"content":"TraceCodeImportSecurityChannelBindingEntry","pos":[2275,2317]},{"content":"Starting Security ImportChannelBinding.","pos":[2318,2357]},{"content":"PrivateKeyExchangeNotSupported","pos":[2362,2392]},{"content":"The private key does not support the exchange KeySpec.","pos":[2393,2447]},{"content":"TokenProviderUnableToGetToken","pos":[2452,2481]},{"content":"The specific token provider was unable to provide a security token.","pos":[2482,2549]},{"content":"SAMLEntityCannotBeNullOrEmpty","pos":[2554,2583]},{"content":"The specific SamlAssertion entity cannot be null or empty.","pos":[2584,2642]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionRequireOneStatement","pos":[2647,2679]},{"content":"A SamlAssertion requires at least one statement.","pos":[2680,2728]},{"content":"Ensure that you have added at least one SamlStatement to the SamlAssertion you are creating.","pos":[2729,2821]},{"content":"AESInvalidInputBlockSize","pos":[2826,2850]},{"content":"The input size must be a multiple of specific bytes.","pos":[2851,2903]},{"content":"AESCryptAcquireContextFailed","pos":[2908,2936]},{"content":"Failed to acquire the CSP context.","pos":[2937,2971]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionRequireOneStatementOnRead","pos":[2976,3014]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion being read did not contain any SamlStatement.","pos":[3015,3078]},{"content":"A SamlAssertion must contain at least one SamlStatement.","pos":[3079,3135]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedFaultReceived","pos":[3140,3183]},{"content":"The client security session received a session closed fault from the server.","pos":[3184,3260]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderRedirectApplied","pos":[3265,3310]},{"content":"IssuanceTokenProvider applied a redirection header.","pos":[3311,3362]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedFaultSendFailure","pos":[3367,3413]},{"content":"A failure occurred when sending a security session closed fault to the client.","pos":[3414,3492]},{"content":"ValueMustBeZero","pos":[3497,3512]},{"content":"The value of this argument must be 0.","pos":[3513,3550]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToResolveSignatureKey","pos":[3555,3586]},{"content":"Unable to resolve SecurityKeyIdentifier found in the SamlAssertion signature.","pos":[3587,3664]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion signature cannot be validated for the specific Issuer.","pos":[3665,3737]},{"content":"X509IsNotInTrustedStore","pos":[3742,3765]},{"content":"The specific X.509 certificate is not in the trusted people store.","pos":[3766,3832]},{"content":"SAMLElementNotRecognized","pos":[3837,3861]},{"content":"The specific element is not supported.","pos":[3862,3900]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingResourceAttributeOnRead","pos":[3905,3969]},{"content":"The 'Resource' attribute for the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing or of length 0.","pos":[3970,4075]},{"content":"SamlTokenMissingSignature","pos":[4080,4105]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion is not signed.","pos":[4106,4138]},{"content":"SamlAssertions can be signed by setting the SigningCredentials.","pos":[4139,4202]},{"content":"ExpectedElementMissing","pos":[4207,4229]},{"content":"The expected element with the specific namespace is missing.","pos":[4230,4290]},{"content":"NoKeyIdentifierClauseFound","pos":[4295,4321]},{"content":"No clause of the specific type was found in the SecurityKeyIdentifier.","pos":[4322,4392]},{"content":"MissingPrivateKey","pos":[4397,4414]},{"content":"The private key is not present in the X.509 certificate.","pos":[4415,4471]},{"content":"UnexpectedEOFFromReader","pos":[4476,4499]},{"content":"Unexpected EOF from XML reader.","pos":[4500,4531]},{"content":"UnsupportedKeyDerivationAlgorithm","pos":[4536,4569]},{"content":"The specific key derivation algorithm is not supported.","pos":[4570,4625]},{"content":"TokenDoesNotSupportKeyIdentifierClauseCreation","pos":[4630,4676]},{"content":"The specific token does not support the specific key identifier clause creation.","pos":[4677,4757]},{"content":"LastMessageNumberExceeded","pos":[4762,4787]},{"content":"A violation of sequence number protocol has been detected.","pos":[4788,4846]},{"content":"SymmetricKeyLengthTooShort","pos":[4851,4877]},{"content":"The length of the symmetric key specified is too short.","pos":[4878,4933]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingAuthorityKindOnRead","pos":[4938,4984]},{"content":"The SamlAuthorityBinding being read was found to contain an 'AuthorityKind' that was missing or of length 0.","pos":[4985,5093]},{"content":"This is not allowed.","pos":[5095,5115]},{"content":"XmlTokenBufferIsEmpty","pos":[5120,5141]},{"content":"XmlTokenBuffer is empty.","pos":[5142,5166]},{"content":"InvalidXmlQualifiedName","pos":[5171,5194]},{"content":"An Xml qualified name was expected, but an invalid name  was found.","pos":[5195,5262]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityKindMissingName","pos":[5267,5295]},{"content":"The XmlQualifiedName that represents the 'AuthorityKind' in the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[5296,5411]},{"content":"AESCryptEncryptFailed","pos":[5416,5437]},{"content":"Failed to encrypt the specific data.","pos":[5438,5474]},{"content":"AuthorizationContextCreated","pos":[5479,5506]},{"content":"Authorization Context with the specific id is created.","pos":[5507,5561]},{"content":"SamlSerializerUnableToReadSecurityKeyIdentifier","pos":[5566,5613]},{"content":"The SamlSerializer does not contain a SecurityTokenSerializer capable of reading the SecurityKeyIdentifier.","pos":[5614,5721]},{"content":"If you are using a custom SecurityKeyIdentifier, you must provide a custom SecurityTokenSerializer.","pos":[5722,5821]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderServiceTokenCacheFull","pos":[5826,5877]},{"content":"IssuanceTokenProvider reduced the service token cache.","pos":[5878,5932]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityTokenProviderOpened","pos":[5937,5973]},{"content":"Security Token Provider was opened.","pos":[5974,6009]},{"content":"PublicKeyNotRSA","pos":[6014,6029]},{"content":"The public key is not an RSA key.","pos":[6030,6063]},{"content":"InvalidReaderState","pos":[6068,6086]},{"content":"The specific state is invalid for the supplied input reader.","pos":[6087,6147]},{"content":"UnableToResolveReferenceUriForSignature","pos":[6152,6191]},{"content":"Unable to resolve the specific URI in the signature to compute the digest.","pos":[6192,6266]},{"content":"EmptyBase64Attribute","pos":[6271,6291]},{"content":"An empty value was found for the required base64 attribute name and namespace.","pos":[6292,6370]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectRequiresConfirmationMethodWhenConfirmationDataOrKeyInfoIsSpecified","pos":[6375,6452]},{"content":"The SAML SubjectConfirmation requires a Confirmation method when the Confirmation Data or KeyInfo is specified.","pos":[6453,6564]},{"content":"SAMLAudienceRestrictionShouldHaveOneAudienceOnRead","pos":[6569,6619]},{"content":"The SamlAudienceRestrictionCondition being read must contain at least one 'Audience' value.","pos":[6620,6711]},{"content":"None were found.","pos":[6712,6728]},{"content":"TokenProviderUnableToRenewToken","pos":[6733,6764]},{"content":"The specific token provider was unable to renew the security token.","pos":[6765,6832]},{"content":"AESIVLengthNotSupported","pos":[6837,6860]},{"content":"The specific bits IV is not supported.","pos":[6861,6899]},{"content":"Only 128 bits IV is supported.","pos":[6900,6930]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingAuthorityKind","pos":[6935,6975]},{"content":"A SamlAuthorityBinding must contain an 'AuthorityKind' that is not null.","pos":[6976,7048]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionDemuxFailure","pos":[7053,7089]},{"content":"The incoming message is not part of an existing security session.","pos":[7090,7155]},{"content":"TokenRenewalNotSupported","pos":[7160,7184]},{"content":"The specific token provider does not support token renewal.","pos":[7185,7244]},{"content":"AtLeastOneReferenceRequired","pos":[7249,7276]},{"content":"At least one reference is required in a signature.","pos":[7277,7327]},{"content":"SAMLSignatureAlreadyRead","pos":[7332,7356]},{"content":"The signature is already read in the SAML assertion.","pos":[7357,7409]},{"content":"AlgorithmAndPrivateKeyMisMatch","pos":[7414,7444]},{"content":"The algorithm specified and the private key do not match.","pos":[7445,7502]},{"content":"EmptyTransformChainNotSupported","pos":[7507,7538]},{"content":"The empty transform chain is not supported.","pos":[7539,7582]},{"content":"SspiWrapperEncryptDecryptAssert1","pos":[7587,7619]},{"content":"SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&amp;#124;'offset' is out of range.","pos":[7620,7684],"source":"SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&#124;'offset' is out of range."},{"content":"SspiWrapperEncryptDecryptAssert2","pos":[7689,7721]},{"content":"SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&amp;#124;'size' is out of range.","pos":[7722,7784],"source":"SSPIWrapper::EncryptDecryptHelper&#124;'size' is out of range."},{"content":"SecurityTokenManagerCannotCreateAuthenticatorForRequirement=The security token manager cannot create a token authenticator for the specific requirement.","pos":[7785,7937]},{"content":"UnableToCreateKeyedHashAlgorithm","pos":[7942,7974]},{"content":"Unable to create a KeyedHashAlgorithm from the specific value for the specific signature algorithm.","pos":[7975,8074]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadAssertion","pos":[8079,8104]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>saml:assertion&gt; element failed to load.","pos":[8105,8150],"source":"The \\<saml:assertion> element failed to load."},{"content":"X509FindValueMismatchMulti","pos":[8155,8181]},{"content":"The specific X509FindType requires the type of the argument findValue to be one of the 2 values.","pos":[8182,8278]},{"content":"The argument findValue is of another type.","pos":[8279,8321]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityIdentityDeterminationSuccess","pos":[8326,8371]},{"content":"Identity was determined for an EndpointAddress.","pos":[8372,8419]},{"content":"UndefinedUseOfPrefixAtElement","pos":[8424,8453]},{"content":"The specific prefix that is used at the element has no namespace defined.","pos":[8454,8527]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionResponderOperationFailure","pos":[8532,8581]},{"content":"Security session operation failed at the server.","pos":[8582,8630]},{"content":"CannotFindCert","pos":[8635,8649]},{"content":"Unable to find the X.509 certificate using the specific search criteria: StoreName , StoreLocation, FindType, FindValue.","pos":[8650,8770]},{"content":"X509InvalidUsageTime","pos":[8775,8795]},{"content":"The specific X.509 certificate usage time is invalid.","pos":[8796,8849]},{"content":"The usage time does not fall between the required NotBefore time and NotAfter time.","pos":[8850,8933]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityIdentityDeterminationFailure","pos":[8938,8983]},{"content":"Identity cannot be determined for an EndpointAddress.","pos":[8984,9037]},{"content":"AsyncObjectAlreadyEnded","pos":[9042,9065]},{"content":"The End method has already been called on this asynchronous result object.","pos":[9066,9140]},{"content":"ExternalDictionaryDoesNotContainAllRequiredStrings","pos":[9145,9195]},{"content":"The external dictionary does not contain definitions for all the required strings.","pos":[9196,9278]},{"content":"The specific string is not available in the remote dictionary.","pos":[9279,9341]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionKeyRenewalFaultReceived","pos":[9346,9393]},{"content":"The client security session received a key renewal fault from the server.","pos":[9394,9467]},{"content":"SAMLActionNameRequired","pos":[9472,9494]},{"content":"The string that represents the SamlAction cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[9495,9567]},{"content":"SignatureVerificationFailed","pos":[9572,9599]},{"content":"The signature verification failed.","pos":[9600,9634]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityContextTokenCacheFull","pos":[9639,9677]},{"content":"The SecurityContextSecurityToken cache is full.","pos":[9678,9725]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionMissingMajorVersionAttributeOnRead","pos":[9730,9777]},{"content":"The MajorVersion for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.","pos":[9778,9857]},{"content":"SamlAttributeClaimRightShouldBePossessProperty","pos":[9862,9908]},{"content":"This SamlAttribute constructor requires that the Right of the Claim have the value System.IdentityModel.Claims.Rights.PossessProperty.","pos":[9909,10043]},{"content":"AuthorizationPolicyEvaluated","pos":[10048,10076]},{"content":"Policy with the specific id is evaluated.","pos":[10077,10118]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadCondtions","pos":[10123,10148]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>saml:conditions&gt; element failed to load.","pos":[10149,10195],"source":"The \\<saml:conditions> element failed to load."},{"content":"AESKeyLengthNotSupported","pos":[10200,10224]},{"content":"The specific bits key is not supported.","pos":[10225,10264]},{"content":"Only 128, 192 and 256 bits key is supported.","pos":[10265,10309]},{"content":"UserNameCannotBeEmpty","pos":[10314,10335]},{"content":"The username cannot be empty.","pos":[10336,10365]},{"content":"AlgorithmAndPublicKeyMisMatch","pos":[10370,10399]},{"content":"The algorithm specified and the public key do not match.","pos":[10400,10456]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadCondtion","pos":[10461,10485]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph>saml:conditions&gt; element failed to load.","pos":[10486,10532],"source":"The \\<saml:conditions> element failed to load."},{"content":"SamlAssertionMissingSigningCredentials","pos":[10537,10575]},{"content":"SigningCredentials have not been set on the SamlAssertion.","pos":[10576,10634]},{"content":"SamlAssertions must be signed, please set a valid SigningCredentials on the SamlAssertion to proceed.","pos":[10635,10736]},{"content":"SspiPayloadNotEncrypted","pos":[10741,10764]},{"content":"The binary data was not encrypted with the SSPI security context.","pos":[10765,10830]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionShouldHaveOneActionOnRead","pos":[10835,10885]},{"content":"The SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement that is being read does not contain any SamlAction.","pos":[10886,10976]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityBindingSecureOutgoingMessageFailure","pos":[10981,11033]},{"content":"The security protocol cannot secure the outgoing message.","pos":[11034,11091]},{"content":"UndefinedUseOfPrefixAtAttribute","pos":[11096,11127]},{"content":"The specific prefix used at the specific attribute has no namespace defined.","pos":[11128,11204]},{"content":"NoInputIsSetForCanonicalization","pos":[11209,11240]},{"content":"No input is set for writing canonicalized output.","pos":[11241,11290]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionAdded","pos":[11295,11337]},{"content":"A pending security session is added to the server.","pos":[11338,11388]},{"content":"AsyncCallbackException","pos":[11393,11415]},{"content":"An AsyncCallback threw an exception.","pos":[11416,11452]},{"content":"PrivateKeyNotRSA","pos":[11457,11473]},{"content":"The private key is not a RSA key.","pos":[11474,11507]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionKeyRenewed","pos":[11512,11552]},{"content":"The client security session renewed the session key.","pos":[11553,11605]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingDecisionAttributeOnRead","pos":[11610,11674]},{"content":"The 'Decision' for the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing or of length 0.","pos":[11675,11770]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeNameAttributeRequired","pos":[11775,11809]},{"content":"The 'Name' specified for a SamlAttribute cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[11810,11881]},{"content":"SamlSerializerRequiresExternalSerializers","pos":[11886,11927]},{"content":"The SamlSerializer requires a SecurityTokenSerializer to serialize the SecurityKeyIdentifier present in the token.","pos":[11928,12042]},{"content":"UnableToResolveKeyReference","pos":[12047,12074]},{"content":"The token resolver is unable to resolve the specific security key reference.","pos":[12075,12151]},{"content":"UnsupportedKeyWrapAlgorithm","pos":[12156,12183]},{"content":"The specific key wrap algorithm is not supported.","pos":[12184,12233]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionMissingIssuerAttributeOnRead","pos":[12238,12279]},{"content":"The 'Issuer' for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.","pos":[12280,12355]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderUsingCachedToken","pos":[12360,12406]},{"content":"The IssuanceTokenProvider used the cached service token.","pos":[12407,12463]},{"content":"AESCryptGetKeyParamFailed","pos":[12468,12493]},{"content":"Failed to get the specific key parameter.","pos":[12494,12535]},{"content":"InvalidNamespaceForEmptyPrefix","pos":[12540,12570]},{"content":"The namespace is invalid for the empty prefix.","pos":[12571,12617]},{"content":"AESCipherModeNotSupported","pos":[12622,12647]},{"content":"The specific cipher mode is not supported.","pos":[12648,12690]},{"content":"Only CBC is supported.","pos":[12691,12713]},{"content":"ArgumentCannotBeEmptyString","pos":[12718,12745]},{"content":"The argument must be a non-empty string.","pos":[12746,12786]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionMissingMinorVersionAttributeOnRead","pos":[12791,12838]},{"content":"The MinorVersion for the SamlAssertion being read is missing or is of length 0.","pos":[12839,12918]},{"content":"SpecifiedStringNotAvailableInDictionary","pos":[12923,12962]},{"content":"The specified string is not an entry in the current dictionary.","pos":[12963,13026]},{"content":"KerberosApReqInvalidOrOutOfMemory","pos":[13031,13064]},{"content":"The AP-REQ is invalid or the system does not have enough memory.","pos":[13065,13129]},{"content":"FailLogonUser","pos":[13134,13147]},{"content":"The LogonUser failed for the specified user.","pos":[13148,13192]},{"content":"Ensure that the user has a valid Windows account.","pos":[13193,13242]},{"content":"ValueMustBeNonNegative","pos":[13247,13269]},{"content":"The value of this argument must be non-negative.","pos":[13270,13318]},{"content":"X509ValidationFail","pos":[13323,13341]},{"content":"The specified X.509 certificate validation failed.","pos":[13342,13392]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorOperationSuccess","pos":[13397,13446]},{"content":"The security session operation completed successfully at the client.","pos":[13447,13515]},{"content":"SAMLActionNameRequiredOnRead","pos":[13520,13548]},{"content":"The string that is read for the SamlAction is missing or is of length 0.","pos":[13549,13621]},{"content":"KerberosMultilegsNotSupported","pos":[13626,13655]},{"content":"Identity is specified as UPN.","pos":[13656,13685]},{"content":"Authenticating a service running under a user account requires Kerberos multi-legs, which is unsupported.","pos":[13686,13791]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionIdRequired","pos":[13796,13819]},{"content":"The 'assertionId' for a SamlAssertion cannot be null or empty.","pos":[13820,13882]},{"content":"InvalidOperationForWriterState","pos":[13887,13917]},{"content":"The specified operation is invalid in the specified XmlWriter state.","pos":[13918,13986]},{"content":"CannotValidateSecurityTokenType","pos":[13991,14022]},{"content":"The specified security token authenticator cannot validate a token of the specified type.","pos":[14023,14112]},{"content":"X509FindValueMismatch","pos":[14117,14138]},{"content":"The specified X509FindType requires the type of the argument findValue to be the specified value.","pos":[14139,14236]},{"content":"The argument findValue is of another type.","pos":[14237,14279]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionCloseSent","pos":[14284,14323]},{"content":"A Close message was sent by the client security session.","pos":[14324,14380]},{"content":"SuiteDoesNotAcceptAlgorithm","pos":[14385,14412]},{"content":"The specified algorithm is not accepted for the specified  operation by the specified algorithm suite","pos":[14413,14514]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorOperationFailure","pos":[14519,14568]},{"content":"The client security session operation failed.","pos":[14569,14614]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadStatement","pos":[14619,14644]},{"content":"Failed to load a SamlStatement.","pos":[14645,14676]},{"content":"InnerReaderMustBeAtElement","pos":[14681,14707]},{"content":"The inner reader must be at the element.","pos":[14708,14748]},{"content":"UnableToCreateTokenReference","pos":[14753,14781]},{"content":"Unable to create a security token reference.","pos":[14782,14826]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityBindingIncomingMessageVerified","pos":[14831,14878]},{"content":"The security protocol verified the incoming message.","pos":[14879,14931]},{"content":"ObjectIsReadOnly","pos":[14936,14952]},{"content":"The object is read-only.","pos":[14953,14977]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityClientSessionPreviousKeyDiscarded","pos":[14982,15032]},{"content":"The client security session discarded the previous session key.","pos":[15033,15096]},{"content":"SAMLTokenTimeInvalid","pos":[15101,15121]},{"content":"The SamlToken is not time valid.","pos":[15122,15154]},{"content":"The current time is outside the Effective and Expiration time of the token.","pos":[15155,15230]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityIdentityVerificationSuccess","pos":[15235,15279]},{"content":"Identity verification succeeded.","pos":[15280,15312]},{"content":"SigningTokenHasNoKeys","pos":[15317,15338]},{"content":"The specified signing token has no keys.","pos":[15339,15379]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityIdentityVerificationFailure","pos":[15384,15428]},{"content":"Identity verification failed.","pos":[15429,15458]},{"content":"AESCryptImportKeyFailed","pos":[15463,15486]},{"content":"Failed to import the key material.","pos":[15487,15521]},{"content":"FailInitializeSecurityContext","pos":[15526,15555]},{"content":"InitializeSecurityContent failed.","pos":[15556,15589]},{"content":"Ensure the service principal name is correct.","pos":[15590,15635]},{"content":"TraceCodeStreamSecurityUpgradeAccepted","pos":[15640,15678]},{"content":"The stream security upgrade was accepted successfully.","pos":[15679,15733]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingRequiresLocation","pos":[15738,15774]},{"content":"The 'Location' attribute that is specified on the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[15775,15876]},{"content":"PublicKeyNotDSA","pos":[15881,15896]},{"content":"The public key is not a DSA key.","pos":[15897,15929]},{"content":"ImpersonationLevelNotSupported","pos":[15934,15964]},{"content":"The authentication modes using Kerberos do not support the specified impersonation level.","pos":[15965,16054]},{"content":"Specify a valid identification or impersonation level.","pos":[16055,16109]},{"content":"RequiredTargetNotSigned","pos":[16114,16137]},{"content":"The element with the specified id is required to be signed, but was not.","pos":[16138,16210]},{"content":"SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationInstanceOnRead","pos":[16215,16277]},{"content":"The 'AuthenticationInstant' attribute being read for a SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing or of length 0.","pos":[16278,16387]},{"content":"SAMLEvidenceShouldHaveOneAssertionOnRead","pos":[16392,16432]},{"content":"The SamlEvidence being read did not contain either a reference to or an embedded SamlAssertion.","pos":[16433,16528]},{"content":"LengthOfArrayToConvertMustGreaterThanZero","pos":[16533,16574]},{"content":"The length of the array to convert to an integer must be greater than 0.","pos":[16575,16647]},{"content":"InvalidAsyncResult","pos":[16652,16670]},{"content":"Invalid AsyncResult.","pos":[16671,16691]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderRemovedCachedToken","pos":[16696,16744]},{"content":"The IssuanceTokenProvider removed the expired service token.","pos":[16745,16805]},{"content":"IncorrectUserNameFormat","pos":[16810,16833]},{"content":"The username is in an invalid format.","pos":[16834,16871]},{"content":"The username format must be in the form of \"username' or 'domain<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>\\username'.","pos":[16872,16949],"source":" The username format must be in the form of \"username' or 'domain\\\\\\username'."},{"content":"TraceCodeExportSecurityChannelBindingEntry","pos":[16954,16996]},{"content":"Starting Security ExportChannelBinding.","pos":[16997,17036]},{"content":"UnsupportedInputTypeForTransform","pos":[17041,17073]},{"content":"The specified input type is not supported for the transform.","pos":[17074,17134]},{"content":"CannotFindDocumentRoot","pos":[17139,17161]},{"content":"Cannot find the root of the document.","pos":[17162,17199]},{"content":"XmlBufferQuotaExceeded","pos":[17204,17226]},{"content":"The size necessary to buffer the XML content exceeded the buffer quota.","pos":[17227,17298]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedResponseSendFailure","pos":[17303,17352]},{"content":"A failure occurred when sending a security session Close response to the client.","pos":[17353,17433]},{"content":"UnableToResolveReferenceInSamlSignature","pos":[17438,17477]},{"content":"Unable to resolve the specified reference in the SAML signature with AssertionID.","pos":[17478,17559]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectRequiresNameIdentifierOrConfirmationMethod","pos":[17564,17617]},{"content":"A SamlSubject requires that a 'NameIdentifier' or 'ConfirmationMethod' be specified.","pos":[17618,17702]},{"content":"Both were missing.","pos":[17703,17721]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeMissingNamespaceAttributeOnRead","pos":[17726,17770]},{"content":"The 'Namespace' for the SamlAttribute being read is missing or of length 0.","pos":[17771,17846]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectConfirmationClauseMissingConfirmationMethodOnRead","pos":[17851,17911]},{"content":"A 'ConfirmationMethod' cannot be found on the SamlSubjectConfirmation being read.","pos":[17912,17993]},{"content":"SecurityTokenRequirementHasInvalidTypeForProperty","pos":[17998,18047]},{"content":"The token requirement has an unexpected type for the specified property.","pos":[18048,18120]},{"content":"The expected property type is of another value.","pos":[18121,18168]},{"content":"TraceCodeNegotiationTokenProviderAttached","pos":[18173,18214]},{"content":"NegotiationTokenProvider was attached.","pos":[18215,18253]},{"content":"TraceCodeSpnegoClientNegotiationCompleted","pos":[18258,18299]},{"content":"SpnegoTokenProvider completed SSPI negotiation.","pos":[18300,18347]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadUnknownElement","pos":[18352,18382]},{"content":"The selected SamlSerializer is unable to deserialize this element.","pos":[18383,18449]},{"content":"Please register a custom SamlSerializer to deserialize custom elements.","pos":[18450,18521]},{"content":"CreateSequenceRefused","pos":[18526,18547]},{"content":"The create sequence request has been refused by the RM Destination.","pos":[18548,18615]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionRedirectApplied","pos":[18620,18659]},{"content":"The client security session was redirected.","pos":[18660,18703]},{"content":"SecurityTokenRequirementDoesNotContainProperty","pos":[18708,18754]},{"content":"The token requirement does not contain the specified property.","pos":[18755,18817]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeValueCannotBeNull","pos":[18822,18852]},{"content":"One of the attributeValues found in the SamlAttribute was found to be a null value.","pos":[18853,18936]},{"content":"Ensure that lists are not null when creating the SamlAttribute.","pos":[18937,19000]},{"content":"ValueMustBeGreaterThanZero","pos":[19005,19031]},{"content":"The value of this argument must be greater than 0.","pos":[19032,19082]},{"content":"TraceCodeNegotiationAuthenticatorAttached","pos":[19087,19128]},{"content":"NegotiationTokenAuthenticator was attached.","pos":[19129,19172]},{"content":"ValueMustBePositive","pos":[19177,19196]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionShouldHaveOneAction","pos":[19202,19246]},{"content":"A SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement must have at least one SamlAction.","pos":[19247,19318]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityTokenAuthenticatorClosed","pos":[19323,19364]},{"content":"Security Token Authenticator was closed.","pos":[19365,19405]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityAuditWrittenSuccess","pos":[19410,19446]},{"content":"The security audit log is written successfully.","pos":[19447,19494]},{"content":"PrivateKeyNotDSA","pos":[19499,19515]},{"content":"The private key is not a DSA key.","pos":[19516,19549]},{"content":"MessageNumberRollover","pos":[19554,19575]},{"content":"The maximum sequence number for this sequence has been exceeded.","pos":[19576,19640]},{"content":"AESPaddingModeNotSupported","pos":[19645,19671]},{"content":"The specified padding mode is not supported.","pos":[19672,19716]},{"content":"Only PKCS7 and ISO10126 is supported.","pos":[19717,19754]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectRequiresNameIdentifierOrConfirmationMethodOnRead","pos":[19759,19818]},{"content":"The required 'NameIdentifier' and the 'ConfirmationMethod' elements are not found for the SamlSubject being read.","pos":[19819,19932]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityAuditWrittenFailure","pos":[19937,19973]},{"content":"A failure occurred while writing to the security audit log.","pos":[19974,20033]},{"content":"UnsupportedCryptoAlgorithm","pos":[20038,20064]},{"content":"The specified crypto algorithm is not supported in this context.","pos":[20065,20129]},{"content":"SigningTokenHasNoKeysSupportingTheAlgorithmSuite","pos":[20134,20182]},{"content":"The signing token has no key that supports the specified algorithm suite.","pos":[20183,20256]},{"content":"SAMLNameIdentifierMissingIdentifierValueOnRead","pos":[20261,20307]},{"content":"The 'Identifier' string for the SamlNameIdentifier being read is missing.","pos":[20308,20381]},{"content":"SAMLSubjectStatementRequiresSubject","pos":[20386,20421]},{"content":"The SAML Subject Statement requires a SAML subject to be specified.","pos":[20422,20489]},{"content":"TraceCodeSslClientCertMissing","pos":[20494,20523]},{"content":"The remote SSL client failed to provide a required certificate.","pos":[20524,20587]},{"content":"SAMLTokenVersionNotSupported","pos":[20592,20620]},{"content":"The specified major version and minor version are not supported.","pos":[20621,20685]},{"content":"TraceCodeConfigurationIsReadOnly","pos":[20690,20722]},{"content":"The configuration is read-only.","pos":[20723,20754]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionRenewFaultSendFailure","pos":[20759,20804]},{"content":"A failure occurred when sending a renewal fault on the security session key to the client.","pos":[20805,20895]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityInactiveSessionFaulted","pos":[20900,20939]},{"content":"An inactive security session was faulted by the server.","pos":[20940,20995]},{"content":"SAMLUnableToLoadAttribute","pos":[21000,21025]},{"content":"Failed to load a SamlAttribute.","pos":[21026,21057]},{"content":"Psha1KeyLengthInvalid","pos":[21062,21083]},{"content":"The specified PSHA1 key length is invalid.","pos":[21084,21126]},{"content":"KeyIdentifierCannotCreateKey","pos":[21131,21159]},{"content":"This SecurityKeyIdentifier does not have any clause that can create a key.","pos":[21160,21234]},{"content":"X509IsInUntrustedStore","pos":[21239,21261]},{"content":"The specified X.509 certificate is in an untrusted certificate store.","pos":[21262,21331]},{"content":"UnexpectedXmlChildNode","pos":[21336,21358]},{"content":"The specified XML child node of specified type is unexpected for the specified element.","pos":[21359,21446]},{"content":"TokenDoesNotMeetKeySizeRequirements","pos":[21451,21486]},{"content":"The key size requirements for the specified algorithm suite are not met by the specified token.","pos":[21487,21582]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionRequestorStartOperation","pos":[21587,21634]},{"content":"A security session operation was started at the client.","pos":[21635,21690]},{"content":"InvalidHexString","pos":[21695,21711]},{"content":"Invalid hexadecimal string format.","pos":[21712,21746]},{"content":"SamlAttributeClaimResourceShouldBeAString","pos":[21751,21792]},{"content":"This SamlAttribute constructor requires that the resource of the claim is of type 'string'.","pos":[21793,21884]},{"content":"SamlSigningTokenNotFound","pos":[21889,21913]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion is signed but the token that signed the SamlAssertion cannot be found.","pos":[21914,22002]},{"content":"Ensure that the SecurityTokenResolver contains the token that signed the SamlAssertion.","pos":[22003,22090]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySpnToSidMappingFailure","pos":[22095,22134]},{"content":"The ServicePrincipalName could not be mapped to a SecurityIdentifier.","pos":[22135,22204]},{"content":"UnableToCreateSignatureFormatterFromAsymmetricCrypto","pos":[22209,22261]},{"content":"Unable to create a signature formatter for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.","pos":[22262,22366]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionClosedFaultSent","pos":[22371,22416]},{"content":"The server security session sent a session closed fault to the client.","pos":[22417,22487]},{"content":"UnableToFindPrefix","pos":[22492,22510]},{"content":"Unable to find the prefix for the specified visibly used prefix at the specified element.","pos":[22511,22600]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityTokenAuthenticatorOpened","pos":[22605,22646]},{"content":"Security Token Authenticator was opened.","pos":[22647,22687]},{"content":"RequiredAttributeMissing","pos":[22692,22716]},{"content":"The specified attribute is required on the specified element.","pos":[22717,22778]},{"content":"LocalIdCannotBeEmpty","pos":[22783,22803]},{"content":"The localId cannot be empty.","pos":[22804,22832]},{"content":"Specify a valid 'localId'.","pos":[22833,22859]},{"content":"ValueMustBeInRange","pos":[22864,22882]},{"content":"The value of this argument must fall within the specified range.","pos":[22883,22947]},{"content":"TraceCodeIssuanceTokenProviderBeginSecurityNegotiation","pos":[22952,23006]},{"content":"IssuanceTokenProvider started a new security negotiation.","pos":[23007,23064]},{"content":"InvalidNtMapping","pos":[23069,23085]},{"content":"The specified X.509 certificate cannot be mapped to a Windows account.","pos":[23086,23156]},{"content":"The UPN subject alternate name is required.","pos":[23157,23200]},{"content":"AESCryptSetKeyParamFailed","pos":[23205,23230]},{"content":"Failed to set the specified key parameter.","pos":[23231,23273]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionClosedResponseReceived","pos":[23278,23324]},{"content":"The client security session received a closed response from the server.","pos":[23325,23396]},{"content":"UnableToCreateSignatureDeformatterFromAsymmetricCrypto","pos":[23401,23455]},{"content":"Unable to create a signature deformatter for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.","pos":[23456,23562]},{"content":"TraceCodeIdentityModelAsyncCallbackThrewException","pos":[23567,23616]},{"content":"An asynchronous callback threw an exception.","pos":[23617,23661]},{"content":"LengthMustBeGreaterThanZero","pos":[23666,23693]},{"content":"The length of this argument must be greater than 0.","pos":[23694,23745]},{"content":"FoundMultipleCerts","pos":[23750,23768]},{"content":"Found multiple X.509 certificates using the specified search criteria: StoreName, StoreLocation, FindType, FindValue.","pos":[23769,23886]},{"content":"Provide a more specific find value.","pos":[23887,23922]},{"content":"AtLeastOneTransformRequired","pos":[23927,23954]},{"content":"The Transforms element must contain at least one transform.","pos":[23955,24014]},{"content":"SAMLTokenNotSerialized","pos":[24019,24041]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion could not be serialized to XML.","pos":[24042,24091]},{"content":"Please see inner exception for details.","pos":[24092,24131]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityBindingOutgoingMessageSecured","pos":[24136,24182]},{"content":"The security protocol secured the outgoing message.","pos":[24183,24234]},{"content":"KeyIdentifierClauseDoesNotSupportKeyCreation","pos":[24239,24283]},{"content":"This SecurityKeyIdentifierClause does not support key creation.","pos":[24284,24347]},{"content":"UnableToResolveTokenReference","pos":[24352,24381]},{"content":"The token resolver is unable to resolve the specified token reference.","pos":[24382,24452]},{"content":"UnsupportedEncryptionAlgorithm","pos":[24457,24487]},{"content":"The specified encryption algorithm is not supported.","pos":[24488,24540]},{"content":"SamlSerializerUnableToWriteSecurityKeyIdentifier","pos":[24545,24593]},{"content":"The SamlSerializer does not contain a SecurityTokenSerializer capable of serializing the given SecurityKeyIdentifier.","pos":[24594,24711]},{"content":"If you are using a custom SecurityKeyIdentifier, you must provide a custom SecurityTokenSerializer.","pos":[24712,24811]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeShouldHaveOneValue","pos":[24816,24847]},{"content":"No attribute values were found.","pos":[24848,24879]},{"content":"A SamlAttribute attribute must have at least one attribute value.","pos":[24880,24945]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityBindingVerifyIncomingMessageFailure","pos":[24950,25002]},{"content":"Security protocol cannot verify the incoming message.","pos":[25003,25056]},{"content":"SamlSigningTokenMissing","pos":[25061,25084]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion passed to the SamlSecurityTokenAuthenticator does not contain a signing token.","pos":[25085,25181]},{"content":"NoPrivateKeyAvailable","pos":[25186,25207]},{"content":"No private key is available.","pos":[25208,25236]},{"content":"ValueMustBeOne","pos":[25241,25255]},{"content":"The value of this argument must be 1.","pos":[25256,25293]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionRemoved","pos":[25298,25342]},{"content":"A pending security session was made active by the server.","pos":[25343,25400]},{"content":"TraceCodeImportSecurityChannelBindingExit","pos":[25405,25446]},{"content":"Finished Security ImportChannelBinding.","pos":[25447,25486]},{"content":"X509CertStoreLocationNotValid","pos":[25491,25520]},{"content":"The StoreLocation must be either LocalMachine or CurrentUser.","pos":[25521,25582]},{"content":"SettingdMayBeModifiedOnlyWhenTheWriterIsInStartState","pos":[25587,25639]},{"content":"The writer settings may be modified only when the writer is in the Start state.","pos":[25640,25719]},{"content":"ArgumentInvalidCertificate","pos":[25724,25750]},{"content":"The certificate is invalid.","pos":[25751,25778]},{"content":"DigestVerificationFailedForReference","pos":[25783,25819]},{"content":"Digest verification failed for the specified Reference.","pos":[25820,25875]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingRequiresBinding","pos":[25880,25915]},{"content":"The 'Binding' attribute specified on the SamlAuthorityBinding cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[25916,26008]},{"content":"AESInsufficientOutputBuffer","pos":[26013,26040]},{"content":"The output buffer must be greater than the specified bytes.","pos":[26041,26100]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingBindingOnRead","pos":[26105,26145]},{"content":"The 'Binding' attribute for the SamlAuthorityBinding being read is missing or of length 0.","pos":[26146,26236]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingInvalidAuthorityKind","pos":[26241,26281]},{"content":"The SamlAuthorityBinding being read has an invalid AuthorityKind.","pos":[26282,26347]},{"content":"The format of the AuthorityKind must be a QName.","pos":[26348,26396]},{"content":"ProvidedNetworkCredentialsForKerberosHasInvalidUserName","pos":[26401,26456]},{"content":"The NetworkCredentials provided for the Kerberos Token does not have a valid UserName.","pos":[26457,26543]},{"content":"SSPIPackageNotSupported","pos":[26548,26571]},{"content":"The specified SSPI package is not supported.","pos":[26572,26616]},{"content":"TokenCancellationNotSupported","pos":[26621,26650]},{"content":"The specified token provider does not support token cancellation.","pos":[26651,26716]},{"content":"UnboundPrefixInQName","pos":[26721,26741]},{"content":"An unbound prefix is used in the specified qualified name.","pos":[26742,26800]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionResourceRequired","pos":[26805,26846]},{"content":"The 'resource' specified to the SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[26847,26944]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityNegotiationProcessingFailure","pos":[26949,26994]},{"content":"Service security negotiation processing failure.","pos":[26995,27043]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionIssuerRequired","pos":[27048,27075]},{"content":"The 'Issuer' specified for a SamlAssertion cannot be null or empty.","pos":[27076,27143]},{"content":"UnableToCreateHashAlgorithmFromAsymmetricCrypto","pos":[27148,27195]},{"content":"Unable to create a HashAlgorithm for the specified algorithm from the specified asymmetric crypto.","pos":[27196,27294]},{"content":"SamlUnableToExtractSubjectKey","pos":[27299,27328]},{"content":"The SecurityKeyIdentifier that was found in the SamlSubject cannot be resolved to a SecurityToken.","pos":[27329,27427]},{"content":"The SecurityTokenResolver must contain a SecurityToken that the SecurityKeyIdentifier resolves to.","pos":[27428,27526]},{"content":"ChildNodeTypeMissing","pos":[27531,27551]},{"content":"The specified XML element does not have a child of the specified type.","pos":[27552,27622]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityPendingServerSessionClosed","pos":[27627,27670]},{"content":"The pending security session was closed by the server.","pos":[27671,27725]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecuritySessionCloseResponseSent","pos":[27730,27771]},{"content":"The server security session sent a Close response to the client.","pos":[27772,27836]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityIdentityHostNameNormalizationFailure","pos":[27841,27894]},{"content":"The HostName portion of an endpoint address cannot be normalized.","pos":[27895,27960]},{"content":"FailAcceptSecurityContext","pos":[27965,27990]},{"content":"The AcceptSecurityContext failed.","pos":[27991,28024]},{"content":"EmptyXmlElementError","pos":[28029,28049]},{"content":"The specified element cannot be empty.","pos":[28050,28088]},{"content":"PrefixNotDefinedForNamespace","pos":[28093,28121]},{"content":"A prefix for the specified namespace is not defined in this context and cannot be declared.","pos":[28122,28213]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionHasMoreThanOneEvidence","pos":[28218,28265]},{"content":"The SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read was found to contain more than one Evidence.","pos":[28266,28360]},{"content":"This is not allowed.","pos":[28361,28381]},{"content":"SamlTokenAuthenticatorCanOnlyProcessSamlTokens","pos":[28386,28432]},{"content":"The SamlSecurityTokenAuthenticator can only process SamlSecurityTokens.","pos":[28433,28504]},{"content":"The specified SecurityTokenType was received .","pos":[28505,28551]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeStatementMissingAttributeOnRead","pos":[28556,28600]},{"content":"The SamlAttributeStatement being read does not contain any 'SamlAttribute' elements.","pos":[28601,28685]},{"content":"This is not allowed.","pos":[28686,28706]},{"content":"CouldNotFindNamespaceForPrefix","pos":[28711,28741]},{"content":"Cannot look up the namespace for the specified prefix.","pos":[28742,28796]},{"content":"TraceCodeExportSecurityChannelBindingExit","pos":[28801,28842]},{"content":"Finished Security ExportChannelBinding.","pos":[28843,28882]},{"content":"AESCryptDecryptFailed","pos":[28887,28908]},{"content":"Failed to decrypt the specified data.","pos":[28909,28946]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeNamespaceAttributeRequired","pos":[28951,28990]},{"content":"The 'Namespace' specified for a SamlAttribute cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[28991,29067]},{"content":"TraceCodeSpnegoServiceNegotiationCompleted","pos":[29072,29114]},{"content":"SpnegoTokenAuthenticator completed SSPI negotiation.","pos":[29115,29167]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionRenewalFaultSent","pos":[29172,29218]},{"content":"The server security session sent a key renewal fault to the client.","pos":[29219,29286]},{"content":"AlgorithmMismatchForTransform","pos":[29291,29320]},{"content":"A mismatch occurred on the algorithm for the transform.","pos":[29321,29376]},{"content":"UserNameAuthenticationFailed","pos":[29381,29409]},{"content":"Authentication of a username/password using the specified mechanism failed.","pos":[29410,29485]},{"content":"User is not authenticated.","pos":[29486,29512]},{"content":"SamlInvalidSigningToken","pos":[29517,29540]},{"content":"The SamlAssertion has been signed with a token that was not validated according to the protocol.","pos":[29541,29637]},{"content":"If you are using X.509 certificates, examine your validation semantics.","pos":[29638,29709]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionKeyUpdated","pos":[29714,29754]},{"content":"The security session key was updated by the server.","pos":[29755,29806]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityServerSessionCloseReceived","pos":[29811,29854]},{"content":"The server security session received a Close message from the client.","pos":[29855,29924]},{"content":"SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingSubject","pos":[29929,29970]},{"content":"The SamlAuthenticationStatement is missing the required SamlSubjectStatement.","pos":[29971,30048]},{"content":"UnexpectedEndOfFile","pos":[30053,30072]},{"content":"Unexpected end of file.","pos":[30073,30096]},{"content":"UnsupportedAlgorithmForCryptoOperation","pos":[30101,30139]},{"content":"The specified algorithm is not supported for the specified operation.","pos":[30140,30209]},{"content":"XmlLangAttributeMissing","pos":[30214,30237]},{"content":"The required xml:lang attribute is missing.","pos":[30238,30281]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityImpersonationSuccess","pos":[30286,30323]},{"content":"Security Impersonation succeeded at the server.","pos":[30324,30371]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorityBindingMissingLocationOnRead","pos":[30376,30417]},{"content":"The 'Location' attribute for the SamlAuthorityBinding being read is missing or of length 0.","pos":[30418,30509]},{"content":"SAMLAttributeStatementMissingSubjectOnRead","pos":[30514,30556]},{"content":"The 'SamlSubject' element for the SamlAttributeStatement is missing.","pos":[30557,30625]},{"content":"SAMLAuthorizationDecisionStatementMissingSubjectOnRead","pos":[30630,30684]},{"content":"The 'SamlSubject' element for SamlAuthorizationDecisionStatement being read is missing.","pos":[30685,30772]},{"content":"SAMLBadSchema","pos":[30777,30790]},{"content":"While reading a SamlAssertion this specified element was found not to comply with the schema.","pos":[30791,30884]},{"content":"SAMLAssertionIDIsInvalid","pos":[30889,30913]},{"content":"The specified 'assertionId' for a SamlAssertion must start with a letter or '_'.","pos":[30914,30994]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityActiveServerSessionRemoved","pos":[30999,31042]},{"content":"An active security session was removed by the server.","pos":[31043,31096]},{"content":"UnableToCreateKeyedHashAlgorithmFromSymmetricCrypto","pos":[31101,31152]},{"content":"Unable to create a keyedHashAlgorithm for the specified algorithm from the specified symmetric crypto.","pos":[31153,31255]},{"content":"SAMLAuthenticationStatementMissingAuthenticationMethod","pos":[31260,31314]},{"content":"The 'AuthenticationMethod' specified for a SamlAuthenticationStatement cannot be null or of length 0.","pos":[31315,31416]},{"content":"TraceCodeSecurityImpersonationFailure","pos":[31421,31458]},{"content":"Security impersonation failed at the server.","pos":[31459,31503]},{"content":"Default","pos":[31508,31515]},{"content":"(Default)","pos":[31516,31525]},{"content":"UnsupportedNodeTypeInReader","pos":[31530,31557]},{"content":"The specified node type with the specified name is not supported.","pos":[31558,31623]}]}