{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Connection Grouping | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"VB\"\n  - \"CSharp\"\n  - \"C++\"\n  - \"jsharp\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"Internet, connections\"\n  - \"connections [.NET Framework], grouping\"\n  - \"WebRequest class, connection grouping\"\n  - \"network resources, connections\"\n  - \"connection pooling\"\nms.assetid: 2ec502e8-4ba0-4c22-9410-f28eaf4eee63\ncaps.latest.revision: 7\nauthor: \"mcleblanc\"\nms.author: \"markl\"\nmanager: \"markl\"\n---\n# Connection Grouping\nConnection grouping associates specific requests within a single application to a defined connection pool. This can be required by a middle-tier application that connects to a back-end server on behalf of a user and uses an authentication protocol that supports delegation, such as Kerberos, or by a middle-tier application that supplies its own credentials, as in the example below. For example, suppose a user, Joe, visits an internal Web site that displays his payroll information. After authenticating Joe, the middle-tier application server uses Joe's credentials to connect to the back-end server to retrieve his payroll information. Next, Susan visits the site and requests her payroll information. Because the middle-tier application has already made a connection using Joe's credentials, the back-end server responds with Joe's information. However, if the application assigns each request sent to the back-end server to a connection group formed from the user name, then each user belongs to a separate connection pool and cannot accidentally share authentication information with another user.  \n  \n To assign a request to a specific connection group, you must assign a name to the <xref:System.Net.WebRequest.ConnectionGroupName%2A> property of your <xref:System.Net.WebRequest> before making the request.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [Managing Connections](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/managing-connections.md)   \n [How to: Assign User Information to Group Connections](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/how-to-assign-user-information-to-group-connections.md)","nodes":[{"pos":[12,48],"content":"Connection Grouping | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Connection Grouping | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[572,591],"content":"Connection Grouping","linkify":"Connection Grouping","nodes":[{"content":"Connection Grouping","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Connection grouping associates specific requests within a single application to a defined connection pool.","pos":[592,698]},{"content":"This can be required by a middle-tier application that connects to a back-end server on behalf of a user and uses an authentication protocol that supports delegation, such as Kerberos, or by a middle-tier application that supplies its own credentials, as in the example below.","pos":[699,975]},{"content":"For example, suppose a user, Joe, visits an internal Web site that displays his payroll information.","pos":[976,1076]},{"content":"After authenticating Joe, the middle-tier application server uses Joe's credentials to connect to the back-end server to retrieve his payroll information.","pos":[1077,1231]},{"content":"Next, Susan visits the site and requests her payroll information.","pos":[1232,1297]},{"content":"Because the middle-tier application has already made a connection using Joe's credentials, the back-end server responds with Joe's information.","pos":[1298,1441]},{"content":"However, if the application assigns each request sent to the back-end server to a connection group formed from the user name, then each user belongs to a separate connection pool and cannot accidentally share authentication information with another user.","pos":[1442,1696]},{"content":"To assign a request to a specific connection group, you must assign a name to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Net.WebRequest.ConnectionGroupName%2A&gt;</ph> property of your <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Net.WebRequest&gt;</ph> before making the request.","pos":[1703,1909],"source":"To assign a request to a specific connection group, you must assign a name to the <xref:System.Net.WebRequest.ConnectionGroupName%2A> property of your <xref:System.Net.WebRequest> before making the request."},{"pos":[1918,1926],"content":"See Also","linkify":"See Also","nodes":[{"content":"See Also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managing Connections<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/managing-connections.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[1930,2022],"source":"[Managing Connections](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/managing-connections.md) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\"> [</bpt>How to: Assign User Information to Group Connections<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/how-to-assign-user-information-to-group-connections.md)</ept>","pos":[2025,2180],"source":" [How to: Assign User Information to Group Connections](../../../docs/framework/network-programming/how-to-assign-user-information-to-group-connections.md)"}]}