{"content":"---\ntitle: \"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nms.assetid: b555544e-7abb-4814-859b-ab9cdd7d8716\n---\n# System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server\nThe [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] version 2.0 introduced a transaction framework that can be accessed through the <xref:System.Transactions> namespace. This framework exposes transactions in a way that is fully integrated in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)], including [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)].  \n  \n In addition to the programmability enhancements, <xref:System.Transactions> and [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] can work together to coordinate optimizations when you work with transactions. A promotable transaction is a lightweight (local) transaction that can be automatically promoted to a fully distributed transaction on an as-needed basis.  \n  \n Starting with [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] 2.0, <xref:System.Data.SqlClient> supports promotable transactions when you work with SQL Server. A promotable transaction does not invoke the added overhead of a distributed transaction unless the added overhead is required. Promotable transactions are automatic and require no intervention from the developer.  \n  \n Promotable transactions are only available when you use the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] Data Provider for SQL Server (`SqlClient`) with SQL Server.  \n  \n## Creating Promotable Transactions  \n The [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] Provider for SQL Server provides support for promotable transactions, which are handled through the classes in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] <xref:System.Transactions> namespace. Promotable transactions optimize distributed transactions by deferring creating a distributed transaction until it is needed. If only one resource manager is required, no distributed transaction occurs.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  In a partially trusted scenario, the <xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission> is required when a transaction is promoted to a distributed transaction.  \n  \n## Promotable Transaction Scenarios  \n Distributed transactions typically consume significant system resources, being managed by Microsoft Distributed Transaction Coordinator (MS DTC), which integrates all the resource managers accessed in the transaction. A promotable transaction is a special form of a <xref:System.Transactions> transaction that effectively delegates the work to a simple SQL Server transaction. <xref:System.Transactions>, <xref:System.Data.SqlClient>, and SQL Server coordinate the work involved in handling the transaction, promoting it to a full distributed transaction as needed.  \n  \n The benefit of using promotable transactions is that when a connection is opened by using an active <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> transaction, and no other connections are opened, the transaction commits as a lightweight transaction, instead of incurring the additional overhead of a full distributed transaction.  \n  \n### Connection String Keywords  \n The <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection.ConnectionString%2A> property supports a keyword, `Enlist`, which indicates whether <xref:System.Data.SqlClient> will detect transactional contexts and automatically enlist the connection in a distributed transaction. If `Enlist=true`, the connection is automatically enlisted in the opening thread's current transaction context. If `Enlist=false`, the `SqlClient` connection does not interact with a distributed transaction. The default value for `Enlist` is true. If `Enlist` is not specified in the connection string, the connection is automatically enlisted in a distributed transaction if one is detected when the connection is opened.  \n  \n The `Transaction Binding` keywords in a <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection> connection string control the connection's association with an enlisted `System.Transactions` transaction. It is also available through the <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder.TransactionBinding%2A> property of a <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder>.  \n  \n The following table describes the possible values.  \n  \n|Keyword|Description|  \n|-------------|-----------------|  \n|Implicit Unbind|The default. The connection detaches from the transaction when it ends, switching back to autocommit mode.|  \n|Explicit Unbind|The connection remains attached to the transaction until the transaction is closed. The connection will fail if the associated transaction is not active or does not match <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.Current%2A>.|  \n  \n## Using TransactionScope  \n The <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class makes a code block transactional by implicitly enlisting connections in a distributed transaction. You must call the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A> method at the end of the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block before leaving it. Leaving the block invokes the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> method. If an exception has been thrown that causes the code to leave scope, the transaction is considered aborted.  \n  \n We recommend that you use a `using` block to make sure that <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> is called on the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> object when the using block is exited. Failure to commit or roll back pending transactions can significantly damage performance because the default time-out for the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is one minute. If you do not use a `using` statement, you must perform all work in a `Try` block and explicitly call the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> method in the `Finally` block.  \n  \n If an exception occurs in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope>, the transaction is marked as inconsistent and is abandoned. It will be rolled back when the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is disposed. If no exception occurs, participating transactions commit.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  The `TransactionScope` class creates a transaction with a <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.IsolationLevel%2A> of `Serializable` by default. Depending on your application, you might want to consider lowering the isolation level to avoid high contention in your application.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  We recommend that you perform only updates, inserts, and deletes within distributed transactions because they consume significant database resources. Select statements may lock database resources unnecessarily, and in some scenarios, you may have to use transactions for selects. Any non-database work should be done outside the scope of the transaction, unless it involves other transacted resource managers. Although an exception in the scope of the transaction prevents the transaction from committing, the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class has no provision for rolling back any changes your code has made outside the scope of the transaction itself. If you have to take some action when the transaction is rolled back, you must write your own implementation of the <xref:System.Transactions.IEnlistmentNotification> interface and explicitly enlist in the transaction.  \n  \n## Example  \n Working with <xref:System.Transactions> requires that you have a reference to System.Transactions.dll.  \n  \n The following function demonstrates how to create a promotable transaction against two different SQL Server instances, represented by two different <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection> objects, which are wrapped in a <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block. The code creates the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block with a `using` statement and opens the first connection, which automatically enlists it in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope>. The transaction is initially enlisted as a lightweight transaction, not a full distributed transaction. The second connection is enlisted in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> only if the command in the first connection does not throw an exception. When the second connection is opened, the transaction is automatically promoted to a full distributed transaction. The <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A> method is invoked, which commits the transaction only if no exceptions have been thrown. If an exception has been thrown at any point in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block, `Complete` will not be called, and the distributed transaction will roll back when the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is disposed at the end of its `using` block.  \n  \n```csharp  \n// This function takes arguments for the 2 connection strings and commands in order  \n// to create a transaction involving two SQL Servers. It returns a value > 0 if the  \n// transaction committed, 0 if the transaction rolled back. To test this code, you can   \n// connect to two different databases on the same server by altering the connection string,  \n// or to another RDBMS such as Oracle by altering the code in the connection2 code block.  \nstatic public int CreateTransactionScope(  \n    string connectString1, string connectString2,  \n    string commandText1, string commandText2)  \n{  \n    // Initialize the return value to zero and create a StringWriter to display results.  \n    int returnValue = 0;  \n    System.IO.StringWriter writer = new System.IO.StringWriter();  \n  \n    // Create the TransactionScope in which to execute the commands, guaranteeing  \n    // that both commands will commit or roll back as a single unit of work.  \n    using (TransactionScope scope = new TransactionScope())  \n    {  \n        using (SqlConnection connection1 = new SqlConnection(connectString1))  \n        {  \n            try  \n            {  \n                // Opening the connection automatically enlists it in the   \n                // TransactionScope as a lightweight transaction.  \n                connection1.Open();  \n  \n                // Create the SqlCommand object and execute the first command.  \n                SqlCommand command1 = new SqlCommand(commandText1, connection1);  \n                returnValue = command1.ExecuteNonQuery();  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"Rows to be affected by command1: {0}\", returnValue);  \n  \n                // if you get here, this means that command1 succeeded. By nesting  \n                // the using block for connection2 inside that of connection1, you  \n                // conserve server and network resources by opening connection2   \n                // only when there is a chance that the transaction can commit.     \n                using (SqlConnection connection2 = new SqlConnection(connectString2))  \n                    try  \n                    {  \n                        // The transaction is promoted to a full distributed  \n                        // transaction when connection2 is opened.  \n                        connection2.Open();  \n  \n                        // Execute the second command in the second database.  \n                        returnValue = 0;  \n                        SqlCommand command2 = new SqlCommand(commandText2, connection2);  \n                        returnValue = command2.ExecuteNonQuery();  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"Rows to be affected by command2: {0}\", returnValue);  \n                    }  \n                    catch (Exception ex)  \n                    {  \n                        // Display information that command2 failed.  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"returnValue for command2: {0}\", returnValue);  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"Exception Message2: {0}\", ex.Message);  \n                    }  \n            }  \n            catch (Exception ex)  \n            {  \n                // Display information that command1 failed.  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"returnValue for command1: {0}\", returnValue);  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"Exception Message1: {0}\", ex.Message);  \n            }  \n        }  \n  \n        // If an exception has been thrown, Complete will not   \n        // be called and the transaction is rolled back.  \n        scope.Complete();  \n    }  \n  \n    // The returnValue is greater than 0 if the transaction committed.  \n    if (returnValue > 0)  \n    {  \n        writer.WriteLine(\"Transaction was committed.\");  \n    }  \n    else  \n    {  \n        // You could write additional business logic here, notify the caller by  \n        // throwing a TransactionAbortedException, or log the failure.  \n        writer.WriteLine(\"Transaction rolled back.\");  \n    }  \n  \n    // Display messages.  \n    Console.WriteLine(writer.ToString());  \n  \n    return returnValue;  \n}  \n```  \n  \n```vb  \n' This function takes arguments for the 2 connection strings and commands in order  \n' to create a transaction involving two SQL Servers. It returns a value > 0 if the  \n' transaction committed, 0 if the transaction rolled back. To test this code, you can   \n' connect to two different databases on the same server by altering the connection string,  \n' or to another RDBMS such as Oracle by altering the code in the connection2 code block.  \nPublic Function CreateTransactionScope( _  \n  ByVal connectString1 As String, ByVal connectString2 As String, _  \n  ByVal commandText1 As String, ByVal commandText2 As String) As Integer  \n  \n    ' Initialize the return value to zero and create a StringWriter to display results.  \n    Dim returnValue As Integer = 0  \n    Dim writer As System.IO.StringWriter = New System.IO.StringWriter  \n  \n    ' Create the TransactionScope in which to execute the commands, guaranteeing  \n    ' that both commands will commit or roll back as a single unit of work.  \n    Using scope As New TransactionScope()  \n        Using connection1 As New SqlConnection(connectString1)  \n            Try  \n                ' Opening the connection automatically enlists it in the   \n                ' TransactionScope as a lightweight transaction.  \n                connection1.Open()  \n  \n                ' Create the SqlCommand object and execute the first command.  \n                Dim command1 As SqlCommand = New SqlCommand(commandText1, connection1)  \n                returnValue = command1.ExecuteNonQuery()  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"Rows to be affected by command1: {0}\", returnValue)  \n  \n                ' If you get here, this means that command1 succeeded. By nesting  \n                ' the Using block for connection2 inside that of connection1, you  \n                ' conserve server and network resources by opening connection2   \n                ' only when there is a chance that the transaction can commit.     \n                Using connection2 As New SqlConnection(connectString2)  \n                    Try  \n                        ' The transaction is promoted to a full distributed  \n                        ' transaction when connection2 is opened.  \n                        connection2.Open()  \n  \n                        ' Execute the second command in the second database.  \n                        returnValue = 0  \n                        Dim command2 As SqlCommand = New SqlCommand(commandText2, connection2)  \n                        returnValue = command2.ExecuteNonQuery()  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"Rows to be affected by command2: {0}\", returnValue)  \n  \n                    Catch ex As Exception  \n                        ' Display information that command2 failed.  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"returnValue for command2: {0}\", returnValue)  \n                        writer.WriteLine(\"Exception Message2: {0}\", ex.Message)  \n                    End Try  \n                End Using  \n  \n            Catch ex As Exception  \n                ' Display information that command1 failed.  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"returnValue for command1: {0}\", returnValue)  \n                writer.WriteLine(\"Exception Message1: {0}\", ex.Message)  \n            End Try  \n        End Using  \n  \n        ' If an exception has been thrown, Complete will   \n        ' not be called and the transaction is rolled back.  \n        scope.Complete()  \n    End Using  \n  \n    ' The returnValue is greater than 0 if the transaction committed.  \n    If returnValue > 0 Then  \n        writer.WriteLine(\"Transaction was committed.\")  \n    Else  \n        ' You could write additional business logic here, notify the caller by  \n        ' throwing a TransactionAbortedException, or log the failure.  \n       writer.WriteLine(\"Transaction rolled back.\")  \n     End If  \n  \n    ' Display messages.  \n    Console.WriteLine(writer.ToString())  \n  \n    Return returnValue  \nEnd Function  \n```  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Transactions and Concurrency](../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/transactions-and-concurrency.md)\n- [ADO.NET Managed Providers and DataSet Developer Center](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=217917)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,165],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nms.assetid: b555544e-7abb-4814-859b-ab9cdd7d8716","nodes":[{"content":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","nodes":[{"pos":[0,47],"content":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","nodes":[{"content":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","pos":[0,47]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[172,219],"content":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","linkify":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","nodes":[{"content":"System.Transactions Integration with SQL Server","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> version 2.0 introduced a transaction framework that can be accessed through the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph> namespace.","pos":[220,405],"source":"The [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] version 2.0 introduced a transaction framework that can be accessed through the <xref:System.Transactions> namespace."},{"content":"This framework exposes transactions in a way that is fully integrated in the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph>, including <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph>.","pos":[406,616],"source":" This framework exposes transactions in a way that is fully integrated in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)], including [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]."},{"content":"In addition to the programmability enhancements, <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph> can work together to coordinate optimizations when you work with transactions.","pos":[623,839],"source":"In addition to the programmability enhancements, <xref:System.Transactions> and [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] can work together to coordinate optimizations when you work with transactions."},{"content":"A promotable transaction is a lightweight (local) transaction that can be automatically promoted to a fully distributed transaction on an as-needed basis.","pos":[840,994]},{"content":"Starting with <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph> 2.0, <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient&gt;</ph> supports promotable transactions when you work with SQL Server.","pos":[1001,1170],"source":"Starting with [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] 2.0, <xref:System.Data.SqlClient> supports promotable transactions when you work with SQL Server."},{"content":"A promotable transaction does not invoke the added overhead of a distributed transaction unless the added overhead is required.","pos":[1171,1298]},{"content":"Promotable transactions are automatic and require no intervention from the developer.","pos":[1299,1384]},{"pos":[1391,1574],"content":"Promotable transactions are only available when you use the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> Data Provider for SQL Server (<ph id=\"ph2\">`SqlClient`</ph>) with SQL Server.","source":"Promotable transactions are only available when you use the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] Data Provider for SQL Server (`SqlClient`) with SQL Server."},{"pos":[1583,1615],"content":"Creating Promotable Transactions","linkify":"Creating Promotable Transactions","nodes":[{"content":"Creating Promotable Transactions","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> Provider for SQL Server provides support for promotable transactions, which are handled through the classes in the <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph> namespace.","pos":[1619,1903],"source":"The [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] Provider for SQL Server provides support for promotable transactions, which are handled through the classes in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] <xref:System.Transactions> namespace."},{"content":"Promotable transactions optimize distributed transactions by deferring creating a distributed transaction until it is needed.","pos":[1904,2029]},{"content":"If only one resource manager is required, no distributed transaction occurs.","pos":[2030,2106]},{"pos":[2114,2294],"content":"[!NOTE]\n In a partially trusted scenario, the <xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission> is required when a transaction is promoted to a distributed transaction.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"In a partially trusted scenario, the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission&gt;</ph> is required when a transaction is promoted to a distributed transaction.","pos":[9,178],"source":"In a partially trusted scenario, the <xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission> is required when a transaction is promoted to a distributed transaction."}]},{"pos":[2303,2335],"content":"Promotable Transaction Scenarios","linkify":"Promotable Transaction Scenarios","nodes":[{"content":"Promotable Transaction Scenarios","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"Distributed transactions typically consume significant system resources, being managed by Microsoft Distributed Transaction Coordinator (MS DTC), which integrates all the resource managers accessed in the transaction.","pos":[2339,2556]},{"content":"A promotable transaction is a special form of a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph> transaction that effectively delegates the work to a simple SQL Server transaction.","pos":[2557,2715],"source":" A promotable transaction is a special form of a <xref:System.Transactions> transaction that effectively delegates the work to a simple SQL Server transaction."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient&gt;</ph>, and SQL Server coordinate the work involved in handling the transaction, promoting it to a full distributed transaction as needed.","pos":[2716,2904],"source":"<xref:System.Transactions>, <xref:System.Data.SqlClient>, and SQL Server coordinate the work involved in handling the transaction, promoting it to a full distributed transaction as needed."},{"pos":[2911,3238],"content":"The benefit of using promotable transactions is that when a connection is opened by using an active <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> transaction, and no other connections are opened, the transaction commits as a lightweight transaction, instead of incurring the additional overhead of a full distributed transaction.","source":"The benefit of using promotable transactions is that when a connection is opened by using an active <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> transaction, and no other connections are opened, the transaction commits as a lightweight transaction, instead of incurring the additional overhead of a full distributed transaction."},{"pos":[3248,3274],"content":"Connection String Keywords","linkify":"Connection String Keywords","nodes":[{"content":"Connection String Keywords","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection.ConnectionString%2A&gt;</ph> property supports a keyword, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Enlist`</ph>, which indicates whether <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient&gt;</ph> will detect transactional contexts and automatically enlist the connection in a distributed transaction.","pos":[3278,3541],"source":"The <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection.ConnectionString%2A> property supports a keyword, `Enlist`, which indicates whether <xref:System.Data.SqlClient> will detect transactional contexts and automatically enlist the connection in a distributed transaction."},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enlist=true`</ph>, the connection is automatically enlisted in the opening thread's current transaction context.","pos":[3542,3653],"source":" If `Enlist=true`, the connection is automatically enlisted in the opening thread's current transaction context."},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enlist=false`</ph>, the <ph id=\"ph2\">`SqlClient`</ph> connection does not interact with a distributed transaction.","pos":[3654,3749],"source":" If `Enlist=false`, the `SqlClient` connection does not interact with a distributed transaction."},{"content":"The default value for <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enlist`</ph> is true.","pos":[3750,3789],"source":" The default value for `Enlist` is true."},{"content":"If <ph id=\"ph1\">`Enlist`</ph> is not specified in the connection string, the connection is automatically enlisted in a distributed transaction if one is detected when the connection is opened.","pos":[3790,3964],"source":" If `Enlist` is not specified in the connection string, the connection is automatically enlisted in a distributed transaction if one is detected when the connection is opened."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Transaction Binding`</ph> keywords in a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection&gt;</ph> connection string control the connection's association with an enlisted <ph id=\"ph3\">`System.Transactions`</ph> transaction.","pos":[3971,4160],"source":"The `Transaction Binding` keywords in a <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection> connection string control the connection's association with an enlisted `System.Transactions` transaction."},{"content":"It is also available through the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder.TransactionBinding%2A&gt;</ph> property of a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder&gt;</ph>.","pos":[4161,4342],"source":" It is also available through the <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder.TransactionBinding%2A> property of a <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnectionStringBuilder>."},{"content":"The following table describes the possible values.","pos":[4349,4399]},{"content":"Keyword","pos":[4406,4413]},{"content":"Description","pos":[4414,4425]},{"content":"Implicit Unbind","pos":[4466,4481]},{"content":"The default.","pos":[4482,4494]},{"content":"The connection detaches from the transaction when it ends, switching back to autocommit mode.","pos":[4495,4588]},{"content":"Explicit Unbind","pos":[4593,4608]},{"content":"The connection remains attached to the transaction until the transaction is closed.","pos":[4609,4692]},{"content":"The connection will fail if the associated transaction is not active or does not match <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.Current%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[4693,4830],"source":" The connection will fail if the associated transaction is not active or does not match <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.Current%2A>."},{"pos":[4840,4862],"content":"Using TransactionScope","linkify":"Using TransactionScope","nodes":[{"content":"Using TransactionScope","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> class makes a code block transactional by implicitly enlisting connections in a distributed transaction.","pos":[4866,5018],"source":"The <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class makes a code block transactional by implicitly enlisting connections in a distributed transaction."},{"content":"You must call the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A&gt;</ph> method at the end of the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> block before leaving it.","pos":[5019,5186],"source":" You must call the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A> method at the end of the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block before leaving it."},{"content":"Leaving the block invokes the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[5187,5279],"source":" Leaving the block invokes the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> method."},{"content":"If an exception has been thrown that causes the code to leave scope, the transaction is considered aborted.","pos":[5280,5387]},{"content":"We recommend that you use a <ph id=\"ph1\">`using`</ph> block to make sure that <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A&gt;</ph> is called on the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> object when the using block is exited.","pos":[5394,5608],"source":"We recommend that you use a `using` block to make sure that <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> is called on the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> object when the using block is exited."},{"content":"Failure to commit or roll back pending transactions can significantly damage performance because the default time-out for the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> is one minute.","pos":[5609,5793],"source":" Failure to commit or roll back pending transactions can significantly damage performance because the default time-out for the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is one minute."},{"content":"If you do not use a <ph id=\"ph1\">`using`</ph> statement, you must perform all work in a <ph id=\"ph2\">`Try`</ph> block and explicitly call the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A&gt;</ph> method in the <ph id=\"ph4\">`Finally`</ph> block.","pos":[5794,5985],"source":" If you do not use a `using` statement, you must perform all work in a `Try` block and explicitly call the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Dispose%2A> method in the `Finally` block."},{"content":"If an exception occurs in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph>, the transaction is marked as inconsistent and is abandoned.","pos":[5992,6126],"source":"If an exception occurs in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope>, the transaction is marked as inconsistent and is abandoned."},{"content":"It will be rolled back when the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> is disposed.","pos":[6127,6215],"source":" It will be rolled back when the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is disposed."},{"content":"If no exception occurs, participating transactions commit.","pos":[6216,6274]},{"pos":[6282,6570],"content":"[!NOTE]\n The `TransactionScope` class creates a transaction with a <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.IsolationLevel%2A> of `Serializable` by default. Depending on your application, you might want to consider lowering the isolation level to avoid high contention in your application.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The `TransactionScope` class creates a transaction with a <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.IsolationLevel%2A> of `Serializable` by default. Depending on your application, you might want to consider lowering the isolation level to avoid high contention in your application.","pos":[9,286],"nodes":[{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`TransactionScope`</ph> class creates a transaction with a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.IsolationLevel%2A&gt;</ph> of <ph id=\"ph3\">`Serializable`</ph> by default.","pos":[0,144],"source":"The `TransactionScope` class creates a transaction with a <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction.IsolationLevel%2A> of `Serializable` by default."},{"content":"Depending on your application, you might want to consider lowering the isolation level to avoid high contention in your application.","pos":[145,277]}]}]},{"pos":[6578,7476],"content":"[!NOTE]\n We recommend that you perform only updates, inserts, and deletes within distributed transactions because they consume significant database resources. Select statements may lock database resources unnecessarily, and in some scenarios, you may have to use transactions for selects. Any non-database work should be done outside the scope of the transaction, unless it involves other transacted resource managers. Although an exception in the scope of the transaction prevents the transaction from committing, the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class has no provision for rolling back any changes your code has made outside the scope of the transaction itself. If you have to take some action when the transaction is rolled back, you must write your own implementation of the <xref:System.Transactions.IEnlistmentNotification> interface and explicitly enlist in the transaction.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"We recommend that you perform only updates, inserts, and deletes within distributed transactions because they consume significant database resources. Select statements may lock database resources unnecessarily, and in some scenarios, you may have to use transactions for selects. Any non-database work should be done outside the scope of the transaction, unless it involves other transacted resource managers. Although an exception in the scope of the transaction prevents the transaction from committing, the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class has no provision for rolling back any changes your code has made outside the scope of the transaction itself. If you have to take some action when the transaction is rolled back, you must write your own implementation of the <xref:System.Transactions.IEnlistmentNotification> interface and explicitly enlist in the transaction.","pos":[9,896],"nodes":[{"content":"We recommend that you perform only updates, inserts, and deletes within distributed transactions because they consume significant database resources.","pos":[0,149]},{"content":"Select statements may lock database resources unnecessarily, and in some scenarios, you may have to use transactions for selects.","pos":[150,279]},{"content":"Any non-database work should be done outside the scope of the transaction, unless it involves other transacted resource managers.","pos":[280,409]},{"content":"Although an exception in the scope of the transaction prevents the transaction from committing, the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> class has no provision for rolling back any changes your code has made outside the scope of the transaction itself.","pos":[410,669],"source":" Although an exception in the scope of the transaction prevents the transaction from committing, the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class has no provision for rolling back any changes your code has made outside the scope of the transaction itself."},{"content":"If you have to take some action when the transaction is rolled back, you must write your own implementation of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.IEnlistmentNotification&gt;</ph> interface and explicitly enlist in the transaction.","pos":[670,887],"source":" If you have to take some action when the transaction is rolled back, you must write your own implementation of the <xref:System.Transactions.IEnlistmentNotification> interface and explicitly enlist in the transaction."}]}]},{"pos":[7485,7492],"content":"Example","linkify":"Example","nodes":[{"content":"Example","pos":[0,7]}]},{"pos":[7496,7598],"content":"Working with <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph> requires that you have a reference to System.Transactions.dll.","source":"Working with <xref:System.Transactions> requires that you have a reference to System.Transactions.dll."},{"content":"The following function demonstrates how to create a promotable transaction against two different SQL Server instances, represented by two different <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection&gt;</ph> objects, which are wrapped in a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> block.","pos":[7605,7878],"source":"The following function demonstrates how to create a promotable transaction against two different SQL Server instances, represented by two different <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlConnection> objects, which are wrapped in a <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block."},{"content":"The code creates the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> block with a <ph id=\"ph2\">`using`</ph> statement and opens the first connection, which automatically enlists it in the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph>.","pos":[7879,8089],"source":" The code creates the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block with a `using` statement and opens the first connection, which automatically enlists it in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope>."},{"content":"The transaction is initially enlisted as a lightweight transaction, not a full distributed transaction.","pos":[8090,8193]},{"content":"The second connection is enlisted in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> only if the command in the first connection does not throw an exception.","pos":[8194,8351],"source":" The second connection is enlisted in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> only if the command in the first connection does not throw an exception."},{"content":"When the second connection is opened, the transaction is automatically promoted to a full distributed transaction.","pos":[8352,8466]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A&gt;</ph> method is invoked, which commits the transaction only if no exceptions have been thrown.","pos":[8467,8615],"source":" The <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.Complete%2A> method is invoked, which commits the transaction only if no exceptions have been thrown."},{"content":"If an exception has been thrown at any point in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> block, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Complete`</ph> will not be called, and the distributed transaction will roll back when the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope&gt;</ph> is disposed at the end of its <ph id=\"ph4\">`using`</ph> block.","pos":[8616,8894],"source":" If an exception has been thrown at any point in the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> block, `Complete` will not be called, and the distributed transaction will roll back when the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> is disposed at the end of its `using` block."},{"pos":[16954,16962],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[16966,17068],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Transactions and Concurrency<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/transactions-and-concurrency.md)</ept>","source":"[Transactions and Concurrency](../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/transactions-and-concurrency.md)"},{"pos":[17071,17175],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ADO.NET Managed Providers and DataSet Developer Center<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=217917)</ept>","source":"[ADO.NET Managed Providers and DataSet Developer Center](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=217917)"}]}