{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"deploying applications [.NET Framework], resources\"\n  - \"resource files, deploying\"\n  - \"hub-and-spoke resource deployment model\"\n  - \"resource files, packaging\"\n  - \"application resources, packaging\"\n  - \"public keys, obtaining\"\n  - \"satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"assemblies [.NET Framework], signing\"\n  - \"application resources, deploying\"\n  - \"Al.exe\"\n  - \"GAC (global assembly cache), satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"Assembly Linker\"\n  - \"directory locations for satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"global assembly cache, satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"packaging application resources\"\n  - \"compiling satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"re-signing assemblies\"\nms.assetid: 8d5c6044-2919-41d2-8321-274706b295ac\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"\n---\n# Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps\nResource files play a central role in localized applications. They enable an application to display strings, images, and other data in the user's own language and culture, and to provide alternate data if resources for the user's own language or culture are unavailable. The .NET Framework uses a hub-and-spoke model to locate and retrieve localized resources. The hub is the main assembly that contains the non-localizable executable code and the resources for a single culture, which is called the neutral or default culture. The default culture is the fallback culture for the application; it is used when no localized resources are available. You use the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute to designate the culture of the application's default culture. Each spoke connects to a satellite assembly that contains the resources for a single localized culture but does not contain any code. Because the satellite assemblies are not part of the main assembly, you can easily update or replace resources that correspond to a specific culture without replacing the main assembly for the application.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  The resources of an application's default culture can also be stored in a satellite assembly. To do this, you assign the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute a value of <xref:System.Resources.UltimateResourceFallbackLocation.Satellite?displayProperty=nameWithType>.  \n  \n## Satellite Assembly Name and Location  \n The hub-and-spoke model requires that you place resources in specific locations so that they can be easily located and used. If you do not compile and name resources as expected, or if you do not place them in the correct locations, the common language runtime will not be able to locate them and will use the resources of the default culture instead. The .NET Framework Resource Manager, represented by a <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> object, is used to automatically access localized resources. The Resource Manager requires the following:  \n  \n-   A single satellite assembly must include all the resources for a particular culture. In other words, you should compile multiple .txt or .resx files into a single binary .resources file.  \n  \n-   There must be a separate subdirectory in the application directory for each localized culture that stores that culture's resources. The subdirectory name must be the same as the culture name. Alternately, you can store your satellite assemblies in the global assembly cache. In this case, the culture information component of the assembly's strong name must indicate its culture. (See the [Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache](#SN) section later in this topic.)  \n  \n    > [!NOTE]\n    >  If your application includes resources for subcultures, place each subculture in a separate subdirectory under the application directory. Do not place subcultures in subdirectories under their main culture's directory.  \n  \n-   The satellite assembly must have the same name as the application, and must use the file name extension \".resources.dll\". For example, if an application is named Example.exe, the name of each satellite assembly should be Example.resources.dll. Note that the satellite assembly name does not indicate the culture of its resource files. However, the satellite assembly appears in a directory that does specify the culture.  \n  \n-   Information about the culture of the satellite assembly must be included in the assembly's metadata. To store the culture name in the satellite assembly's metadata, you specify the `/culture` option when you use [Assembly Linker](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to embed resources in the satellite assembly.  \n  \n The following illustration shows a sample directory structure and location requirements for applications that you are not installing in the [global assembly cache](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md). The items with .txt and .resources extensions will not ship with the final application. These are the intermediate resource files used to create the final satellite resource assemblies. In this example, you could substitute .resx files for the .txt files. For more information, see [Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md).  \n  \n ![Satellite assemblies](../../../docs/framework/resources/media/satelliteassemblydir.gif \"satelliteassemblydir\")  \nSatellite assembly directory  \n  \n## Compiling Satellite Assemblies  \n You use [Resource File Generator (Resgen.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile text files or XML (.resx) files that contain resources to binary .resources files. You then use [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to compile .resources files into satellite assemblies. Al.exe creates an assembly from the .resources files that you specify. Satellite assemblies can contain only resources; they cannot contain any executable code.  \n  \n The following Al.exe command creates a satellite assembly for the application `Example` from the German resources file strings.de.resources.  \n  \n```console\nal -target:lib -embed:strings.de.resources -culture:de -out:Example.resources.dll  \n```  \n  \n The following Al.exe command also creates a satellite assembly for the application `Example` from the file strings.de.resources. The **/template** option causes the satellite assembly to inherit all assembly metadata except for its culture information from the parent assembly (Example.dll).  \n  \n```console\nal -target:lib -embed:strings.de.resources -culture:de -out:Example.resources.dll -template:Example.dll  \n```  \n  \n The following table describes the Al.exe options used in these commands in more detail.  \n  \n|Option|Description|  \n|------------|-----------------|  \n|**-target:**lib|Specifies that your satellite assembly is compiled to a library (.dll) file. Because a satellite assembly does not contain executable code and is not an application's main assembly, you must save satellite assemblies as DLLs.|  \n|**-embed:**strings.de.resources|Specifies the name of the resource file to embed when Al.exe compiles the assembly. You can embed multiple .resources files in a satellite assembly, but if you are following the hub-and-spoke model, you must compile one satellite assembly for each culture. However, you can create separate .resources files for strings and objects.|  \n|**-culture:**de|Specifies the culture of the resource to compile. The common language runtime uses this information when it searches for the resources for a specified culture. If you omit this option, Al.exe will still compile the resource, but the runtime will not be able to find it when a user requests it.|  \n|**-out:**Example.resources.dll|Specifies the name of the output file. The name must follow the naming standard *baseName*.resources.*extension*, where *baseName* is the name of the main assembly and *extension* is a valid file name extension (such as .dll). Note that the runtime is not able to determine the culture of a satellite assembly based on its output file name; you must use the **/culture** option to specify it.|  \n|**-template:**Example.dll|Specifies an assembly from which the satellite assembly will inherit all assembly metadata except the culture field. This option affects satellite assemblies only if you specify an assembly that has a [strong name](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md).|  \n  \n For a complete list of options available with Al.exe, see [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md).  \n  \n## Satellite Assemblies: An Example  \n The following is a simple \"Hello world\" example that displays a message box containing a localized greeting. The example includes resources for the English (United States), French (France), and Russian (Russia) cultures, and its fallback culture is English. To create the example, do the following:  \n  \n1.  Create a resource file named Greeting.resx or Greeting.txt to contain the resource for the default culture. Store a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Hello world!\" in this file.  \n  \n2.  To indicate that English (en) is the application's default culture, add the following <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly.  \n  \n     [!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/cs/assemblyinfo.cs#2)]\n     [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/vb/assemblyinfo.vb#2)]  \n  \n3.  Add support for additional cultures (en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU) to the application as follows:  \n  \n    -   To support the en-US or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.en-US.resx or Greeting.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Hi world!\"  \n  \n    -   To support the fr-FR or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.fr-FR.resx or Greeting.fr-FR.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Salut tout le monde!\"  \n  \n    -   To support the ru-RU or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.ru-RU.resx or Greeting.ru-RU.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Всем привет!\"  \n  \n4.  Use [Resgen.exe](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file. The output is a set of files that have the same root file name as the .resx or .txt files, but a .resources extension. If you create the example with Visual Studio, the compilation process is handled automatically. If you aren't using Visual Studio, run the following commands to compile the .resx files into .resources files:  \n  \n    ```console\n    resgen Greeting.resx  \n    resgen Greeting.en-us.resx  \n    resgen Greeting.fr-FR.resx  \n    resgen Greeting.ru-RU.resx  \n    ```  \n  \n     If your resources are in text files instead of XML files, replace the .resx extension with .txt.  \n  \n5.  Compile the following source code along with the resources for the default culture into the application's main assembly:  \n  \n    > [!IMPORTANT]\n    >  If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to the following: `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Greetings\", typeof(Example).Assembly);`  \n  \n     [!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/cs/program.cs#1)]\n     [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/vb/module1.vb#1)]  \n  \n     If the application is named Example and you are compiling from the command line, the command for the C# compiler is:  \n  \n    ```console  \n    csc Example.cs -res:Greeting.resources  \n    ```  \n  \n     The corresponding Visual Basic compiler command is:  \n  \n    ```console  \n    vbc Example.vb -res:Greeting.resources  \n    ```  \n  \n6.  Create a subdirectory in the main application directory for each localized culture supported by the application. You should create an en-US, an fr-FR, and an ru-RU subdirectory. Visual Studio creates these subdirectories automatically as part of the compilation process.  \n  \n7.  Embed the individual culture-specific .resources files into satellite assemblies and save them to the appropriate directory. The command to do this for each .resources file is:  \n  \n    ```console\n    al -target:lib -embed:Greeting.culture.resources -culture:culture -out:culture\\Example.resources.dll  \n    ```  \n  \n     where *culture* is the name of the culture whose resources the satellite assembly contains. Visual Studio handles this process automatically.  \n  \n You can then run the example. It will randomly make one of the supported cultures the current culture and display a localized greeting.  \n  \n<a name=\"SN\"></a>   \n## Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache  \n Instead of installing assemblies in a local application subdirectory, you can install them in the global assembly cache. This is particularly useful if you have class libraries and class library resource assemblies that are used by multiple applications.  \n  \n Installing assemblies in the global assembly cache requires that they have strong names. Strong-named assemblies are signed with a valid public/private key pair. They contain version information that the runtime uses to determine which assembly to use to satisfy a binding request. For more information about strong names and versioning, see [Assembly Versioning](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/assembly-versioning.md). For more information about strong names, see [Strong-Named Assemblies](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md).  \n  \n When you are developing an application, it is unlikely that you will have access to the final public/private key pair. In order to install a satellite assembly in the global assembly cache and ensure that it works as expected, you can use a technique called delayed signing. When you delay sign an assembly, at build time you reserve space in the file for the strong name signature. The actual signing is delayed until later, when the final public/private key pair is available. For more information about delayed signing, see [Delay Signing an Assembly](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md).  \n  \n### Obtaining the Public Key  \n To delay sign an assembly, you must have access to the public key. You can either obtain the real public key from the organization in your company that will do the eventual signing, or create a public key by using the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md).  \n  \n The following Sn.exe command creates a test public/private key pair. The **–k** option specifies that Sn.exe should create a new key pair and save it in a file named TestKeyPair.snk.  \n  \n```console\nsn –k TestKeyPair.snk   \n```  \n  \n You can extract the public key from the file that contains the test key pair. The following command extracts the public key from TestKeyPair.snk and saves it in PublicKey.snk:  \n  \n```console\nsn –p TestKeyPair.snk PublicKey.snk  \n```  \n  \n### Delay Signing an Assembly  \n After you obtain or create the public key, you use the [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to compile the assembly and specify delayed signing.  \n  \n The following Al.exe command creates a strong-named satellite assembly for the application StringLibrary from the strings.ja.resources file:  \n  \n```console \nal -target:lib -embed:strings.ja.resources -culture:ja -out:StringLibrary.resources.dll -delay+ -keyfile:PublicKey.snk  \n```  \n  \n The **-delay+** option specifies that the Assembly Linker should delay sign the assembly. The **-keyfile** option specifies the name of the key file that contains the public key to use to delay sign the assembly.  \n  \n### Re-signing an Assembly  \n Before you deploy your application, you must re-sign the delay signed satellite assembly with the real key pair. You can do this by using Sn.exe.  \n  \n The following Sn.exe command signs StringLibrary.resources.dll with the key pair stored in the file RealKeyPair.snk. The **–R** option specifies that a previously signed or delay signed assembly is to be re-signed.  \n  \n```console\nsn –R StringLibrary.resources.dll RealKeyPair.snk   \n```  \n  \n### Installing a Satellite Assembly in the Global Assembly Cache  \n When the runtime searches for resources in the resource fallback process, it looks in the [global assembly cache](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md) first. (For more information, see the \"Resource Fallback Process\" section of the [Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md) topic.) As soon as a satellite assembly is signed with a strong name, it can be installed in the global assembly cache by using the [Global Assembly Cache Tool (Gacutil.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md).  \n  \n The following Gacutil.exe command installs StringLibrary.resources.dll in the global assembly cache:  \n  \n```console\ngacutil -i:StringLibrary.resources.dll  \n```  \n  \n The **/i** option specifies that Gacutil.exe should install the specified assembly into the global assembly cache. After the satellite assembly is installed in the cache, the resources it contains become available to all applications that are designed to use the satellite assembly.  \n  \n### Resources in the Global Assembly Cache: An Example  \n The following example uses a method in a .NET Framework class library to extract and return a localized greeting from a resource file. The library and its resources are registered in the global assembly cache. The example includes resources for the English (United States), French (France), Russian (Russia), and English cultures. English is the default culture; its resources are stored in the main assembly. The example initially delay signs the library and its satellite assemblies with a public key, then re-signs them with a public/private key pair. To create the example, do the following:  \n  \n1.  If you are not using Visual Studio, use the following [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) command to create a public/private key pair named ResKey.snk:  \n  \n    ```console\n    sn –k ResKey.snk  \n    ```  \n  \n     If you are using Visual Studio, use the **Signing** tab of the project **Properties** dialog box to generate the key file.  \n  \n2.  Use the following [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) command to create a public key file named PublicKey.snk:  \n  \n    ```console\n    sn –p ResKey.snk PublicKey.snk  \n    ```  \n  \n3.  Create a resource file named Strings.resx to contain the resource for the default culture. Store a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"How do you do?\" in that file.  \n  \n4.  To indicate that \"en\" is the application's default culture, add the following <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly:  \n  \n     [!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/stringlibrary.cs#2)]\n     [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/stringlibrary.vb#2)]  \n  \n5.  Add support for additional cultures (the en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU cultures) to the application as follows:  \n  \n    -   To support the \"en-US\" or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Strings.en-US.resx or Strings.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Hello!\".  \n  \n    -   To support the \"fr-FR\" or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Strings.fr-FR.resx or Strings.fr-FR.txt and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Bon jour!\"  \n  \n    -   To support the \"ru-RU\" or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Strings.ru-RU.resx or Strings.ru-RU.txt and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Привет!\"  \n  \n6.  Use [Resgen.exe](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file. The output is a set of files that have the same root file name as the .resx or .txt files, but a .resources extension. If you create the example with Visual Studio, the compilation process is handled automatically. If you aren't using Visual Studio, run the following command to compile the .resx files into .resources files:  \n  \n    ```console\n    resgen filename  \n    ```  \n  \n     where *filename* is the optional path, file name, and extension of the .resx or text file.  \n  \n7.  Compile the following source code for StringLibrary.vb or StringLibrary.cs along with the resources for the default culture into a delay signed library assembly named StringLibrary.dll:  \n  \n    > [!IMPORTANT]\n    >  If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Strings\",` `typeof(Example).Assembly);`.  \n  \n     [!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/stringlibrary.cs#1)]\n     [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/stringlibrary.vb#1)]  \n  \n     The command for the C# compiler is:  \n  \n    ```console\n    csc -t:library -resource:Strings.resources -delaysign+ -keyfile:publickey.snk StringLibrary.cs  \n    ```  \n  \n     The corresponding Visual Basic compiler command is:  \n  \n    ```console  \n    vbc -t:library -resource:Strings.resources -delaysign+ -keyfile:publickey.snk StringLibrary.vb  \n    ```  \n  \n8.  Create a subdirectory in the main application directory for each localized culture supported by the application. You should create an en-US, an fr-FR, and an ru-RU subdirectory. Visual Studio creates these subdirectories automatically as part of the compilation process. Because all satellite assemblies have the same file name, the subdirectories are used to store individual culture-specific satellite assemblies until they are signed with a public/private key pair.  \n  \n9. Embed the individual culture-specific .resources files into delay signed satellite assemblies and save them to the appropriate directory. The command to do this for each .resources file is:  \n  \n    ```console\n    al -target:lib -embed:Strings.culture.resources -culture:culture -out:culture\\StringLibrary.resources.dll -delay+ -keyfile:publickey.snk  \n    ```  \n  \n     where *culture* is the name of a culture. In this example, the culture names are en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU.  \n  \n10. Re-sign StringLibrary.dll by using the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) as follows:  \n  \n    ```console\n    sn –R StringLibrary.dll RealKeyPair.snk  \n    ```  \n  \n11. Re-sign the individual satellite assemblies. To do this, use the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) as follows for each satellite assembly:  \n  \n    ```console\n    sn –R StringLibrary.resources.dll RealKeyPair.snk  \n    ```  \n  \n12. Register StringLibrary.dll and each of its satellite assemblies in the global assembly cache by using the following command:  \n  \n    ```console\n    gacutil -i filename  \n    ```  \n  \n     where *filename* is the name of the file to register.  \n  \n13. If you are using Visual Studio, create a new **Console Application** project named `Example`, add a reference to StringLibrary.dll and the following source code to it, and compile.  \n  \n     [!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#3](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/example.cs#3)]\n     [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#3](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/example.vb#3)]  \n  \n     To compile from the command line, use the following command for the C# compiler:  \n  \n    ```console\n    csc Example.cs -r:StringLibrary.dll   \n    ```  \n  \n     The command line for the Visual Basic compiler is:  \n  \n    ```console\n    vbc Example.vb -r:StringLibrary.dll   \n    ```  \n  \n14. Run Example.exe.  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)\n- [Delay Signing an Assembly](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md)\n- [Al.exe (Assembly Linker)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)\n- [Sn.exe (Strong Name Tool)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)\n- [Gacutil.exe (Global Assembly Cache Tool)](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md)\n- [Resources in Desktop Apps](../../../docs/framework/resources/index.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,865],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"csharp\"\n  - \"vb\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"deploying applications [.NET Framework], resources\"\n  - \"resource files, deploying\"\n  - \"hub-and-spoke resource deployment model\"\n  - \"resource files, packaging\"\n  - \"application resources, packaging\"\n  - \"public keys, obtaining\"\n  - \"satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"assemblies [.NET Framework], signing\"\n  - \"application resources, deploying\"\n  - \"Al.exe\"\n  - \"GAC (global assembly cache), satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"Assembly Linker\"\n  - \"directory locations for satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"global assembly cache, satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"packaging application resources\"\n  - \"compiling satellite assemblies\"\n  - \"re-signing assemblies\"\nms.assetid: 8d5c6044-2919-41d2-8321-274706b295ac\nauthor: \"rpetrusha\"\nms.author: \"ronpet\"","nodes":[{"content":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","nodes":[{"pos":[0,46],"content":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","nodes":[{"content":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","pos":[0,46]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[872,918],"content":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","linkify":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","nodes":[{"content":"Creating Satellite Assemblies for Desktop Apps","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"Resource files play a central role in localized applications.","pos":[919,980]},{"content":"They enable an application to display strings, images, and other data in the user's own language and culture, and to provide alternate data if resources for the user's own language or culture are unavailable.","pos":[981,1189]},{"content":"The .NET Framework uses a hub-and-spoke model to locate and retrieve localized resources.","pos":[1190,1279]},{"content":"The hub is the main assembly that contains the non-localizable executable code and the resources for a single culture, which is called the neutral or default culture.","pos":[1280,1446]},{"content":"The default culture is the fallback culture for the application; it is used when no localized resources are available.","pos":[1447,1565]},{"content":"You use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute&gt;</ph> attribute to designate the culture of the application's default culture.","pos":[1566,1708],"source":" You use the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute to designate the culture of the application's default culture."},{"content":"Each spoke connects to a satellite assembly that contains the resources for a single localized culture but does not contain any code.","pos":[1709,1842]},{"content":"Because the satellite assemblies are not part of the main assembly, you can easily update or replace resources that correspond to a specific culture without replacing the main assembly for the application.","pos":[1843,2048]},{"pos":[2056,2363],"content":"[!NOTE]\n The resources of an application's default culture can also be stored in a satellite assembly. To do this, you assign the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute a value of <xref:System.Resources.UltimateResourceFallbackLocation.Satellite?displayProperty=nameWithType>.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The resources of an application's default culture can also be stored in a satellite assembly. To do this, you assign the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute a value of <xref:System.Resources.UltimateResourceFallbackLocation.Satellite?displayProperty=nameWithType>.","pos":[9,305],"nodes":[{"content":"The resources of an application's default culture can also be stored in a satellite assembly.","pos":[0,93]},{"content":"To do this, you assign the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute&gt;</ph> attribute a value of <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.UltimateResourceFallbackLocation.Satellite?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph>.","pos":[94,296],"source":" To do this, you assign the <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute> attribute a value of <xref:System.Resources.UltimateResourceFallbackLocation.Satellite?displayProperty=nameWithType>."}]}]},{"pos":[2372,2408],"content":"Satellite Assembly Name and Location","linkify":"Satellite Assembly Name and Location","nodes":[{"content":"Satellite Assembly Name and Location","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"The hub-and-spoke model requires that you place resources in specific locations so that they can be easily located and used.","pos":[2412,2536]},{"content":"If you do not compile and name resources as expected, or if you do not place them in the correct locations, the common language runtime will not be able to locate them and will use the resources of the default culture instead.","pos":[2537,2763]},{"content":"The .NET Framework Resource Manager, represented by a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager&gt;</ph> object, is used to automatically access localized resources.","pos":[2764,2918],"source":" The .NET Framework Resource Manager, represented by a <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> object, is used to automatically access localized resources."},{"content":"The Resource Manager requires the following:","pos":[2919,2963]},{"content":"A single satellite assembly must include all the resources for a particular culture.","pos":[2973,3057]},{"content":"In other words, you should compile multiple .txt or .resx files into a single binary .resources file.","pos":[3058,3159]},{"content":"There must be a separate subdirectory in the application directory for each localized culture that stores that culture's resources.","pos":[3169,3300]},{"content":"The subdirectory name must be the same as the culture name.","pos":[3301,3360]},{"content":"Alternately, you can store your satellite assemblies in the global assembly cache.","pos":[3361,3443]},{"content":"In this case, the culture information component of the assembly's strong name must indicate its culture.","pos":[3444,3548]},{"content":"(See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache<ept id=\"p1\">](#SN)</ept> section later in this topic.)","pos":[3549,3655],"source":" (See the [Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache](#SN) section later in this topic.)"},{"pos":[3667,3900],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf your application includes resources for subcultures, place each subculture in a separate subdirectory under the application directory. Do not place subcultures in subdirectories under their main culture's directory.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"If your application includes resources for subcultures, place each subculture in a separate subdirectory under the application directory. Do not place subcultures in subdirectories under their main culture's directory.","pos":[8,226],"nodes":[{"content":"If your application includes resources for subcultures, place each subculture in a separate subdirectory under the application directory.","pos":[0,137]},{"content":"Do not place subcultures in subdirectories under their main culture's directory.","pos":[138,218]}]}]},{"content":"The satellite assembly must have the same name as the application, and must use the file name extension \".resources.dll\".","pos":[3910,4031]},{"content":"For example, if an application is named Example.exe, the name of each satellite assembly should be Example.resources.dll.","pos":[4032,4153]},{"content":"Note that the satellite assembly name does not indicate the culture of its resource files.","pos":[4154,4244]},{"content":"However, the satellite assembly appears in a directory that does specify the culture.","pos":[4245,4330]},{"content":"Information about the culture of the satellite assembly must be included in the assembly's metadata.","pos":[4340,4440]},{"content":"To store the culture name in the satellite assembly's metadata, you specify the <ph id=\"ph1\">`/culture`</ph> option when you use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Linker<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)</ept> to embed resources in the satellite assembly.","pos":[4441,4672],"source":" To store the culture name in the satellite assembly's metadata, you specify the `/culture` option when you use [Assembly Linker](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to embed resources in the satellite assembly."},{"content":"The following illustration shows a sample directory structure and location requirements for applications that you are not installing in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>global assembly cache<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md)</ept>.","pos":[4679,4887],"source":"The following illustration shows a sample directory structure and location requirements for applications that you are not installing in the [global assembly cache](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md)."},{"content":"The items with .txt and .resources extensions will not ship with the final application.","pos":[4888,4975]},{"content":"These are the intermediate resource files used to create the final satellite resource assemblies.","pos":[4976,5073]},{"content":"In this example, you could substitute .resx files for the .txt files.","pos":[5074,5143]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Packaging and Deploying Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)</ept>.","pos":[5144,5294],"source":" For more information, see [Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">![</bpt>Satellite assemblies<ept id=\"p1\">]</ept><bpt id=\"p2\">(../../../docs/framework/resources/media/satelliteassemblydir.gif \"</bpt>satelliteassemblydir<ept id=\"p2\">\")</ept>","pos":[5301,5413],"source":"![Satellite assemblies](../../../docs/framework/resources/media/satelliteassemblydir.gif \"satelliteassemblydir\")"},{"content":"Satellite assembly directory","pos":[5416,5444]},{"pos":[5453,5483],"content":"Compiling Satellite Assemblies","linkify":"Compiling Satellite Assemblies","nodes":[{"content":"Compiling Satellite Assemblies","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"You use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resource File Generator (Resgen.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md)</ept> to compile text files or XML (.resx) files that contain resources to binary .resources files.","pos":[5487,5696],"source":"You use [Resource File Generator (Resgen.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile text files or XML (.resx) files that contain resources to binary .resources files."},{"content":"You then use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Linker (Al.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)</ept> to compile .resources files into satellite assemblies.","pos":[5697,5848],"source":" You then use [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to compile .resources files into satellite assemblies."},{"content":"Al.exe creates an assembly from the .resources files that you specify.","pos":[5849,5919]},{"content":"Satellite assemblies can contain only resources; they cannot contain any executable code.","pos":[5920,6009]},{"pos":[6016,6156],"content":"The following Al.exe command creates a satellite assembly for the application <ph id=\"ph1\">`Example`</ph> from the German resources file strings.de.resources.","source":"The following Al.exe command creates a satellite assembly for the application `Example` from the German resources file strings.de.resources."},{"content":"The following Al.exe command also creates a satellite assembly for the application <ph id=\"ph1\">`Example`</ph> from the file strings.de.resources.","pos":[6267,6395],"source":"The following Al.exe command also creates a satellite assembly for the application `Example` from the file strings.de.resources."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/template<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option causes the satellite assembly to inherit all assembly metadata except for its culture information from the parent assembly (Example.dll).","pos":[6396,6558],"source":" The **/template** option causes the satellite assembly to inherit all assembly metadata except for its culture information from the parent assembly (Example.dll)."},{"content":"The following table describes the Al.exe options used in these commands in more detail.","pos":[6691,6778]},{"content":"Option","pos":[6785,6791]},{"content":"Description","pos":[6792,6803]},{"pos":[6843,6858],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-target:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>lib","source":"**-target:**lib"},{"content":"Specifies that your satellite assembly is compiled to a library (.dll) file.","pos":[6859,6935]},{"content":"Because a satellite assembly does not contain executable code and is not an application's main assembly, you must save satellite assemblies as DLLs.","pos":[6936,7084]},{"pos":[7089,7120],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-embed:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>strings.de.resources","source":"**-embed:**strings.de.resources"},{"content":"Specifies the name of the resource file to embed when Al.exe compiles the assembly.","pos":[7121,7204]},{"content":"You can embed multiple .resources files in a satellite assembly, but if you are following the hub-and-spoke model, you must compile one satellite assembly for each culture.","pos":[7205,7377]},{"content":"However, you can create separate .resources files for strings and objects.","pos":[7378,7452]},{"pos":[7457,7472],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-culture:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>de","source":"**-culture:**de"},{"content":"Specifies the culture of the resource to compile.","pos":[7473,7522]},{"content":"The common language runtime uses this information when it searches for the resources for a specified culture.","pos":[7523,7632]},{"content":"If you omit this option, Al.exe will still compile the resource, but the runtime will not be able to find it when a user requests it.","pos":[7633,7766]},{"pos":[7771,7801],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-out:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>Example.resources.dll","source":"**-out:**Example.resources.dll"},{"content":"Specifies the name of the output file.","pos":[7802,7840]},{"content":"The name must follow the naming standard <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>baseName<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.resources.<bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>extension<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>, where <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>baseName<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> is the name of the main assembly and <bpt id=\"p4\">*</bpt>extension<ept id=\"p4\">*</ept> is a valid file name extension (such as .dll).","pos":[7841,8028],"source":" The name must follow the naming standard *baseName*.resources.*extension*, where *baseName* is the name of the main assembly and *extension* is a valid file name extension (such as .dll)."},{"content":"Note that the runtime is not able to determine the culture of a satellite assembly based on its output file name; you must use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/culture<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to specify it.","pos":[8029,8194],"source":" Note that the runtime is not able to determine the culture of a satellite assembly based on its output file name; you must use the **/culture** option to specify it."},{"pos":[8199,8224],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-template:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>Example.dll","source":"**-template:**Example.dll"},{"content":"Specifies an assembly from which the satellite assembly will inherit all assembly metadata except the culture field.","pos":[8225,8341]},{"content":"This option affects satellite assemblies only if you specify an assembly that has a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>strong name<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md)</ept>.","pos":[8342,8504],"source":" This option affects satellite assemblies only if you specify an assembly that has a [strong name](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md)."},{"pos":[8512,8654],"content":"For a complete list of options available with Al.exe, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Linker (Al.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)</ept>.","source":"For a complete list of options available with Al.exe, see [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)."},{"pos":[8663,8695],"content":"Satellite Assemblies: An Example","linkify":"Satellite Assemblies: An Example","nodes":[{"content":"Satellite Assemblies: An Example","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"The following is a simple \"Hello world\" example that displays a message box containing a localized greeting.","pos":[8699,8807]},{"content":"The example includes resources for the English (United States), French (France), and Russian (Russia) cultures, and its fallback culture is English.","pos":[8808,8956]},{"content":"To create the example, do the following:","pos":[8957,8997]},{"content":"Create a resource file named Greeting.resx or Greeting.txt to contain the resource for the default culture.","pos":[9007,9114]},{"content":"Store a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`HelloString`</ph> whose value is \"Hello world!\"","pos":[9115,9186],"source":" Store a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Hello world!\""},{"content":"in this file.","pos":[9187,9200]},{"pos":[9210,9523],"content":"To indicate that English (en) is the application's default culture, add the following <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly.","source":"To indicate that English (en) is the application's default culture, add the following <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly."},{"pos":[9534,9837],"content":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/cs/assemblyinfo.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/vb/assemblyinfo.vb#2)]","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[]},{"content":"Add support for additional cultures (en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU) to the application as follows:","pos":[9847,9939]},{"pos":[9953,10160],"content":"To support the en-US or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.en-US.resx or Greeting.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`HelloString`</ph> whose value is \"Hi world!\"","source":"To support the en-US or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.en-US.resx or Greeting.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Hi world!\""},{"pos":[10174,10384],"content":"To support the fr-FR or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.fr-FR.resx or Greeting.fr-FR.txt, and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`HelloString`</ph> whose value is \"Salut tout le monde!\"","source":"To support the fr-FR or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.fr-FR.resx or Greeting.fr-FR.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Salut tout le monde!\""},{"pos":[10398,10601],"content":"To support the ru-RU or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.ru-RU.resx or Greeting.ru-RU.txt, and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`HelloString`</ph> whose value is \"Всем привет!\"","source":"To support the ru-RU or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Greeting.ru-RU.resx or Greeting.ru-RU.txt, and store in it a single string named `HelloString` whose value is \"Всем привет!\""},{"content":"Use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resgen.exe<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md)</ept> to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file.","pos":[10611,10767],"source":"Use [Resgen.exe](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file."},{"content":"The output is a set of files that have the same root file name as the .resx or .txt files, but a .resources extension.","pos":[10768,10886]},{"content":"If you create the example with Visual Studio, the compilation process is handled automatically.","pos":[10887,10982]},{"content":"If you aren't using Visual Studio, run the following commands to compile the .resx files into .resources files:","pos":[10983,11094]},{"content":"If your resources are in text files instead of XML files, replace the .resx extension with .txt.","pos":[11259,11355]},{"content":"Compile the following source code along with the resources for the default culture into the application's main assembly:","pos":[11365,11485]},{"pos":[11497,11792],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nIf you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to the following: `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Greetings\", typeof(Example).Assembly);`","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager&gt;</ph> class constructor to the following: <ph id=\"ph2\">`ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Greetings\", typeof(Example).Assembly);`</ph>","pos":[13,288],"source":"If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to the following: `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Greetings\", typeof(Example).Assembly);`"}]},{"pos":[11803,12096],"content":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/cs/program.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Locating#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.locating/vb/module1.vb#1)]","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[]},{"content":"If the application is named Example and you are compiling from the command line, the command for the C# compiler is:","pos":[12107,12223]},{"content":"The corresponding Visual Basic compiler command is:","pos":[12309,12360]},{"content":"Create a subdirectory in the main application directory for each localized culture supported by the application.","pos":[12445,12557]},{"content":"You should create an en-US, an fr-FR, and an ru-RU subdirectory.","pos":[12558,12622]},{"content":"Visual Studio creates these subdirectories automatically as part of the compilation process.","pos":[12623,12715]},{"content":"Embed the individual culture-specific .resources files into satellite assemblies and save them to the appropriate directory.","pos":[12725,12849]},{"content":"The command to do this for each .resources file is:","pos":[12850,12901]},{"content":"where <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>culture<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the name of the culture whose resources the satellite assembly contains.","pos":[13047,13138],"source":"where *culture* is the name of the culture whose resources the satellite assembly contains."},{"content":"Visual Studio handles this process automatically.","pos":[13139,13188]},{"content":"You can then run the example.","pos":[13195,13224]},{"content":"It will randomly make one of the supported cultures the current culture and display a localized greeting.","pos":[13225,13330]},{"pos":[13360,13420],"content":"Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache","linkify":"Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache","nodes":[{"content":"Installing Satellite Assemblies in the Global Assembly Cache","pos":[0,60]}]},{"content":"Instead of installing assemblies in a local application subdirectory, you can install them in the global assembly cache.","pos":[13424,13544]},{"content":"This is particularly useful if you have class libraries and class library resource assemblies that are used by multiple applications.","pos":[13545,13678]},{"content":"Installing assemblies in the global assembly cache requires that they have strong names.","pos":[13685,13773]},{"content":"Strong-named assemblies are signed with a valid public/private key pair.","pos":[13774,13846]},{"content":"They contain version information that the runtime uses to determine which assembly to use to satisfy a binding request.","pos":[13847,13966]},{"content":"For more information about strong names and versioning, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Versioning<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/assembly-versioning.md)</ept>.","pos":[13967,14109],"source":" For more information about strong names and versioning, see [Assembly Versioning](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/assembly-versioning.md)."},{"content":"For more information about strong names, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong-Named Assemblies<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md)</ept>.","pos":[14110,14245],"source":" For more information about strong names, see [Strong-Named Assemblies](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/strong-named-assemblies.md)."},{"content":"When you are developing an application, it is unlikely that you will have access to the final public/private key pair.","pos":[14252,14370]},{"content":"In order to install a satellite assembly in the global assembly cache and ensure that it works as expected, you can use a technique called delayed signing.","pos":[14371,14526]},{"content":"When you delay sign an assembly, at build time you reserve space in the file for the strong name signature.","pos":[14527,14634]},{"content":"The actual signing is delayed until later, when the final public/private key pair is available.","pos":[14635,14730]},{"content":"For more information about delayed signing, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Delay Signing an Assembly<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md)</ept>.","pos":[14731,14867],"source":" For more information about delayed signing, see [Delay Signing an Assembly](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md)."},{"pos":[14877,14901],"content":"Obtaining the Public Key","linkify":"Obtaining the Public Key","nodes":[{"content":"Obtaining the Public Key","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"To delay sign an assembly, you must have access to the public key.","pos":[14905,14971]},{"content":"You can either obtain the real public key from the organization in your company that will do the eventual signing, or create a public key by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept>.","pos":[14972,15209],"source":" You can either obtain the real public key from the organization in your company that will do the eventual signing, or create a public key by using the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)."},{"content":"The following Sn.exe command creates a test public/private key pair.","pos":[15216,15284]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>–k<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option specifies that Sn.exe should create a new key pair and save it in a file named TestKeyPair.snk.","pos":[15285,15398],"source":" The **–k** option specifies that Sn.exe should create a new key pair and save it in a file named TestKeyPair.snk."},{"content":"You can extract the public key from the file that contains the test key pair.","pos":[15450,15527]},{"content":"The following command extracts the public key from TestKeyPair.snk and saves it in PublicKey.snk:","pos":[15528,15625]},{"pos":[15693,15718],"content":"Delay Signing an Assembly","linkify":"Delay Signing an Assembly","nodes":[{"content":"Delay Signing an Assembly","pos":[0,25]}]},{"pos":[15722,15913],"content":"After you obtain or create the public key, you use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Assembly Linker (Al.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)</ept> to compile the assembly and specify delayed signing.","source":"After you obtain or create the public key, you use the [Assembly Linker (Al.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md) to compile the assembly and specify delayed signing."},{"content":"The following Al.exe command creates a strong-named satellite assembly for the application StringLibrary from the strings.ja.resources file:","pos":[15920,16060]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-delay+<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option specifies that the Assembly Linker should delay sign the assembly.","pos":[16209,16298],"source":"The **-delay+** option specifies that the Assembly Linker should delay sign the assembly."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-keyfile<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option specifies the name of the key file that contains the public key to use to delay sign the assembly.","pos":[16299,16421],"source":" The **-keyfile** option specifies the name of the key file that contains the public key to use to delay sign the assembly."},{"pos":[16431,16453],"content":"Re-signing an Assembly","linkify":"Re-signing an Assembly","nodes":[{"content":"Re-signing an Assembly","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"Before you deploy your application, you must re-sign the delay signed satellite assembly with the real key pair.","pos":[16457,16569]},{"content":"You can do this by using Sn.exe.","pos":[16570,16602]},{"content":"The following Sn.exe command signs StringLibrary.resources.dll with the key pair stored in the file RealKeyPair.snk.","pos":[16609,16725]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>–R<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option specifies that a previously signed or delay signed assembly is to be re-signed.","pos":[16726,16823],"source":" The **–R** option specifies that a previously signed or delay signed assembly is to be re-signed."},{"pos":[16906,16966],"content":"Installing a Satellite Assembly in the Global Assembly Cache","linkify":"Installing a Satellite Assembly in the Global Assembly Cache","nodes":[{"content":"Installing a Satellite Assembly in the Global Assembly Cache","pos":[0,60]}]},{"content":"When the runtime searches for resources in the resource fallback process, it looks in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>global assembly cache<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md)</ept> first.","pos":[16970,17134],"source":"When the runtime searches for resources in the resource fallback process, it looks in the [global assembly cache](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/gac.md) first."},{"content":"(For more information, see the \"Resource Fallback Process\" section of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Packaging and Deploying Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)</ept> topic.) As soon as a satellite assembly is signed with a strong name, it can be installed in the global assembly cache by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Global Assembly Cache Tool (Gacutil.exe)<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md)</ept>.","pos":[17135,17563],"source":" (For more information, see the \"Resource Fallback Process\" section of the [Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md) topic.) As soon as a satellite assembly is signed with a strong name, it can be installed in the global assembly cache by using the [Global Assembly Cache Tool (Gacutil.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md)."},{"content":"The following Gacutil.exe command installs StringLibrary.resources.dll in the global assembly cache:","pos":[17570,17670]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/i<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option specifies that Gacutil.exe should install the specified assembly into the global assembly cache.","pos":[17738,17852],"source":"The **/i** option specifies that Gacutil.exe should install the specified assembly into the global assembly cache."},{"content":"After the satellite assembly is installed in the cache, the resources it contains become available to all applications that are designed to use the satellite assembly.","pos":[17853,18020]},{"pos":[18030,18080],"content":"Resources in the Global Assembly Cache: An Example","linkify":"Resources in the Global Assembly Cache: An Example","nodes":[{"content":"Resources in the Global Assembly Cache: An Example","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"The following example uses a method in a .NET Framework class library to extract and return a localized greeting from a resource file.","pos":[18084,18218]},{"content":"The library and its resources are registered in the global assembly cache.","pos":[18219,18293]},{"content":"The example includes resources for the English (United States), French (France), Russian (Russia), and English cultures.","pos":[18294,18414]},{"content":"English is the default culture; its resources are stored in the main assembly.","pos":[18415,18493]},{"content":"The example initially delay signs the library and its satellite assemblies with a public key, then re-signs them with a public/private key pair.","pos":[18494,18638]},{"content":"To create the example, do the following:","pos":[18639,18679]},{"pos":[18689,18890],"content":"If you are not using Visual Studio, use the following <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept> command to create a public/private key pair named ResKey.snk:","source":"If you are not using Visual Studio, use the following [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) command to create a public/private key pair named ResKey.snk:"},{"pos":[18952,19074],"content":"If you are using Visual Studio, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Signing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the project <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> dialog box to generate the key file.","source":"If you are using Visual Studio, use the **Signing** tab of the project **Properties** dialog box to generate the key file."},{"pos":[19084,19244],"content":"Use the following <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept> command to create a public key file named PublicKey.snk:","source":"Use the following [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) command to create a public key file named PublicKey.snk:"},{"content":"Create a resource file named Strings.resx to contain the resource for the default culture.","pos":[19319,19409]},{"content":"Store a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Greeting`</ph> whose value is \"How do you do?\"","pos":[19410,19480],"source":" Store a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"How do you do?\""},{"content":"in that file.","pos":[19481,19494]},{"pos":[19504,19809],"content":"To indicate that \"en\" is the application's default culture, add the following <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly:","source":"To indicate that \"en\" is the application's default culture, add the following <xref:System.Resources.NeutralResourcesLanguageAttribute?displayProperty=nameWithType> attribute to the application's AssemblyInfo file or to the main source code file that will be compiled into the application's main assembly:"},{"pos":[19820,20133],"content":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#2](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/stringlibrary.cs#2)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#2](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/stringlibrary.vb#2)]","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[]},{"content":"Add support for additional cultures (the en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU cultures) to the application as follows:","pos":[20143,20248]},{"pos":[20262,20464],"content":"To support the \"en-US\" or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Strings.en-US.resx or Strings.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Greeting`</ph> whose value is \"Hello!\".","source":"To support the \"en-US\" or English (United States) culture, create a resource file named Strings.en-US.resx or Strings.en-US.txt, and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Hello!\"."},{"pos":[20478,20673],"content":"To support the \"fr-FR\" or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Strings.fr-FR.resx or Strings.fr-FR.txt and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Greeting`</ph> whose value is \"Bon jour!\"","source":"To support the \"fr-FR\" or French (France) culture, create a resource file named Strings.fr-FR.resx or Strings.fr-FR.txt and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Bon jour!\""},{"pos":[20687,20881],"content":"To support the \"ru-RU\" or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Strings.ru-RU.resx or Strings.ru-RU.txt and store in it a single string named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Greeting`</ph> whose value is \"Привет!\"","source":"To support the \"ru-RU\" or Russian (Russia) culture, create a resource file named Strings.ru-RU.resx or Strings.ru-RU.txt and store in it a single string named `Greeting` whose value is \"Привет!\""},{"content":"Use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resgen.exe<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md)</ept> to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file.","pos":[20891,21047],"source":"Use [Resgen.exe](../../../docs/framework/tools/resgen-exe-resource-file-generator.md) to compile each text or XML resource file to a binary .resources file."},{"content":"The output is a set of files that have the same root file name as the .resx or .txt files, but a .resources extension.","pos":[21048,21166]},{"content":"If you create the example with Visual Studio, the compilation process is handled automatically.","pos":[21167,21262]},{"content":"If you aren't using Visual Studio, run the following command to compile the .resx files into .resources files:","pos":[21263,21373]},{"pos":[21434,21524],"content":"where <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>filename<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the optional path, file name, and extension of the .resx or text file.","source":"where *filename* is the optional path, file name, and extension of the .resx or text file."},{"content":"Compile the following source code for StringLibrary.vb or StringLibrary.cs along with the resources for the default culture into a delay signed library assembly named StringLibrary.dll:","pos":[21534,21719]},{"pos":[21731,22012],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nIf you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Strings\",` `typeof(Example).Assembly);`.","leadings":["","    >  "],"nodes":[{"content":"If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager&gt;</ph> class constructor to <ph id=\"ph2\">`ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Strings\",`</ph> <ph id=\"ph3\">`typeof(Example).Assembly);`</ph>.","pos":[13,274],"source":"If you are using the command line rather than Visual Studio to create the example, you should modify the call to the <xref:System.Resources.ResourceManager> class constructor to `ResourceManager rm = new ResourceManager(\"Strings\",` `typeof(Example).Assembly);`."}]},{"pos":[22023,22336],"content":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#1](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/stringlibrary.cs#1)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#1](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/stringlibrary.vb#1)]","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[]},{"content":"The command for the C# compiler is:","pos":[22347,22382]},{"content":"The corresponding Visual Basic compiler command is:","pos":[22522,22573]},{"content":"Create a subdirectory in the main application directory for each localized culture supported by the application.","pos":[22714,22826]},{"content":"You should create an en-US, an fr-FR, and an ru-RU subdirectory.","pos":[22827,22891]},{"content":"Visual Studio creates these subdirectories automatically as part of the compilation process.","pos":[22892,22984]},{"content":"Because all satellite assemblies have the same file name, the subdirectories are used to store individual culture-specific satellite assemblies until they are signed with a public/private key pair.","pos":[22985,23182]},{"content":"Embed the individual culture-specific .resources files into delay signed satellite assemblies and save them to the appropriate directory.","pos":[23191,23328]},{"content":"The command to do this for each .resources file is:","pos":[23329,23380]},{"content":"where <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>culture<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the name of a culture.","pos":[23562,23603],"source":"where *culture* is the name of a culture."},{"content":"In this example, the culture names are en-US, fr-FR, and ru-RU.","pos":[23604,23667]},{"pos":[23677,23813],"content":"Re-sign StringLibrary.dll by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept> as follows:","source":"Re-sign StringLibrary.dll by using the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) as follows:"},{"content":"Re-sign the individual satellite assemblies.","pos":[23897,23941]},{"content":"To do this, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept> as follows for each satellite assembly:","pos":[23942,24087],"source":" To do this, use the [Strong Name Tool (Sn.exe)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md) as follows for each satellite assembly:"},{"content":"Register StringLibrary.dll and each of its satellite assemblies in the global assembly cache by using the following command:","pos":[24181,24305]},{"pos":[24370,24423],"content":"where <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>filename<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the name of the file to register.","source":"where *filename* is the name of the file to register."},{"pos":[24433,24613],"content":"If you are using Visual Studio, create a new <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Console Application<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> project named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Example`</ph>, add a reference to StringLibrary.dll and the following source code to it, and compile.","source":"If you are using Visual Studio, create a new **Console Application** project named `Example`, add a reference to StringLibrary.dll and the following source code to it, and compile."},{"pos":[24624,24925],"content":"[!code-csharp[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#3](../../../samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/cs/example.cs#3)]\n [!code-vb[Conceptual.Resources.Satellites#3](../../../samples/snippets/visualbasic/VS_Snippets_CLR/conceptual.resources.satellites/vb/example.vb#3)]","leadings":["","    "],"nodes":[]},{"content":"To compile from the command line, use the following command for the C# compiler:","pos":[24936,25016]},{"content":"The command line for the Visual Basic compiler is:","pos":[25098,25148]},{"content":"Run Example.exe.","pos":[25229,25245]},{"pos":[25254,25262],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[25266,25389],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Packaging and Deploying Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)</ept>","source":"[Packaging and Deploying Resources](../../../docs/framework/resources/packaging-and-deploying-resources-in-desktop-apps.md)"},{"pos":[25392,25479],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Delay Signing an Assembly<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md)</ept>","source":"[Delay Signing an Assembly](../../../docs/framework/app-domains/delay-sign-assembly.md)"},{"pos":[25482,25565],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Al.exe (Assembly Linker)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)</ept>","source":"[Al.exe (Assembly Linker)](../../../docs/framework/tools/al-exe-assembly-linker.md)"},{"pos":[25568,25653],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sn.exe (Strong Name Tool)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)</ept>","source":"[Sn.exe (Strong Name Tool)](../../../docs/framework/tools/sn-exe-strong-name-tool.md)"},{"pos":[25656,25753],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Gacutil.exe (Global Assembly Cache Tool)<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md)</ept>","source":"[Gacutil.exe (Global Assembly Cache Tool)](../../../docs/framework/tools/gacutil-exe-gac-tool.md)"},{"pos":[25756,25827],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resources in Desktop Apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/framework/resources/index.md)</ept>","source":"[Resources in Desktop Apps](../../../docs/framework/resources/index.md)"}]}