{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 84758642-9b72-4447-86f9-f831fef46962\n---\n# Security Considerations (Entity Framework)\nThis topic describes security considerations that are specific to developing, deploying, and running [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] applications. You should also follow recommendations for creating secure [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] applications. For more information, see [Security Overview](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/security-overview.md).  \n  \n## General Security Considerations  \n The following security considerations apply to all applications that use the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)].  \n  \n#### Use only trusted data source providers.  \n To communicate with the data source, a provider must do the following:  \n  \n-   Receive the connection string from the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)].  \n  \n-   Translate the command tree to the data source's native query language.  \n  \n-   Assemble and return result sets.  \n  \n During the logon operation, information that is based on the user password is passed to the server through the network libraries of the underlying data source. A malicious provider can steal user credentials, generate malicious queries, or tamper with the result set.  \n  \n#### Encrypt your connection to protect sensitive data.  \n The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not directly handle data encryption. If users access data over a public network, your application should establish an encrypted connection to the data source to increase security. For more information, see the security-related documentation for your data source. For a SQL Server data source, see [Encrypting Connections to SQL Server](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=119544).  \n  \n#### Secure the connection string.  \n Protecting access to your data source is one of the most important goals when securing an application. A connection string presents a potential vulnerability if it is not secured or if it is improperly constructed. When you store connection information in plain text or persist it in memory, you risk compromising your entire system. The following are the recommended methods for securing connection strings:  \n  \n-   Use Windows Authentication with a SQL Server data source.  \n  \n     When you use Windows Authentication to connect to a SQL Server data source, the connection string does not contain logon and password information.  \n  \n-   Encrypt configuration file sections using protected configuration.  \n  \n     ASP.NET provides a feature called protected configuration that enables you to encrypt sensitive information in a configuration file. Although primarily designed for ASP.NET, you can also use protected configuration to encrypt sections of configuration files in Windows applications. For a detailed description of the new protected configuration capabilities, see [Encrypting Configuration Information Using Protected Configuration](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/aspnet/53tyfkaw(v=vs.100)).  \n  \n-   Store connection strings in secured configuration files.  \n  \n     You should never embed connection strings in your source code. You can store connection strings in configuration files, which eliminates the need to embed them in your application's code. By default, the Entity Data Model Wizard stores connection strings in the application configuration file. You must secure this file to prevent unauthorized access.  \n  \n-   Use connection string builders when dynamically creating connections.  \n  \n     If you must construct connection strings at runtime, use the <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnectionStringBuilder> class. This string builder class helps prevent connection string injection attacks by validating and escaping invalid input information. For more information, see [How to: Build an EntityConnection Connection String](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/how-to-build-an-entityconnection-connection-string.md). Also use the appropriate string builder class to construct the data source connection string that is part of the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] connection string. For information about connection string builders for ADO.NET providers, see [Connection String Builders](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/connection-string-builders.md).  \n  \n For more information, see [Protecting Connection Information](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/protecting-connection-information.md).  \n  \n#### Do not expose an EntityConnection to untrusted users.  \n An <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> object exposes the connection string of the underlying connection. A user with access to an <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> object can also change the <xref:System.Data.ConnectionState> of the underlying connection. The <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> class is not thread safe.  \n  \n#### Do not pass connections outside the security context.  \n After a connection has been established, you must not pass it outside the security context. For example, one thread with permission to open a connection should not store the connection in a global location. If the connection is available in a global location, then another malicious thread can use the open connection without having that permission explicitly granted to it.  \n  \n#### Be aware that logon information and passwords may be visible in a memory dump.  \n When data source logon and password information is supplied in the connection string, this information is maintained in memory until garbage collection reclaims the resources. This makes it impossible to determine when a password string is no longer in memory. If an application crashes, a memory dump file may contain sensitive security information, and the user running the application and any user with administrative access to the computer can view the memory dump file. Use Windows Authentication for connections to Microsoft SQL Server.  \n  \n#### Grant users only the necessary permissions in the data source.  \n A data source administrator should grant only the necessary permissions to users. Even though [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] does not support DML statements that modify data, such as INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE, users can still access the connection to the data source. A malicious user could use this connection to execute DML statements in the native language of the data source.  \n  \n#### Run applications with the minimum permissions.  \n When you allow a managed application to run with full-trust permission, the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] does not limit the application's access to your computer. This may enable a security vulnerability in your application to compromise the entire system. To use code access security and other security mechanisms in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)], you should run applications by using partial-trust permissions and with the minimum set of permissions that are needed to enable the application to function. The following code access permissions are the minimum permissions your [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application needs:  \n  \n-   <xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.Write> to open the specified metadata files or <xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.PathDiscovery> to search a directory for metadata files.  \n  \n-   <xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermissionFlag.RestrictedMemberAccess> to support LINQ to Entities queries.  \n  \n-   <xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.PermissionState.Unrestricted> to enlist in a <xref:System.Transactions><xref:System.Transactions.Transaction>.  \n  \n-   <xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermissionFlag.SerializationFormatter> to serialize exceptions by using the <xref:System.Runtime.Serialization.ISerializable> interface.  \n  \n-   Permission to open a database connection and execute commands against the database, such as <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlClientPermission> for a SQL Server database.  \n  \n For more information, see [Code Access Security and ADO.NET](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/code-access-security.md).  \n  \n#### Do not install untrusted applications.  \n The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not enforce any security permissions and will invoke any user-supplied data object code in process regardless of whether it is trusted or not. Ensure that authentication and authorization of the client is performed by the data store and by your application.  \n  \n#### Restrict access to all configuration files.  \n An administrator must restrict write access to all files that specify configuration for an application, including to enterprisesec.config, security.config, machine.conf, and the application configuration file \\<*application*>.exe.config.  \n  \n The provider invariant name is modifiable in the app.config. The client application must take responsibility for accessing the underlying provider through the standard provider factory model by using a strong name.  \n  \n#### Restrict permissions to the model and mapping files.  \n An administrator must restrict write access to the model and mapping files (.edmx, .csdl, .ssdl, and .msl) to only users who modify the model or mappings. The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] only requires read access to these files at run time. An administrator should also restrict access to object layer and pre-compiled view source code files that are generated by the [!INCLUDE[adonet_edm](../../../../../includes/adonet-edm-md.md)] tools.  \n  \n## Security Considerations for Queries  \n The following security considerations apply when querying a conceptual model. These considerations apply to [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries using EntityClient and to object queries using LINQ, [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)], and query builder methods.  \n  \n#### Prevent SQL injection attacks.  \n Applications frequently take external input (from a user or another external agent) and perform actions based on that input. Any input that is directly or indirectly derived from the user or an external agent might have content that uses the syntax of the target language in order to perform unauthorized actions. When the target language is a Structured Query Language (SQL), such as [!INCLUDE[tsql](../../../../../includes/tsql-md.md)], this manipulation is known as a SQL injection attack. A malicious user can inject commands directly into the query and drop a database table, cause a denial of service, or otherwise change the nature of the operation being performed.  \n  \n-   [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] injection attacks:  \n  \n     SQL injection attacks can be performed in [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] by supplying malicious input to values that are used in a query predicate and in parameter names. To avoid the risk of SQL injection, you should never combine user input with [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] command text.  \n  \n     [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries accept parameters everywhere that literals are accepted. You should use parameterized queries instead of injecting literals from an external agent directly into the query. You should also consider using [query builder methods](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb896238(v=vs.100)) to safely construct Entity SQL.  \n  \n-   [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] injection attacks:  \n  \n     Although query composition is possible in [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)], it is performed through the object model API. Unlike [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries, [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] queries are not composed by using string manipulation or concatenation, and they are not susceptible to traditional SQL injection attacks.  \n  \n#### Prevent very large result sets.  \n A very large result set could cause the client system to shut down if the client is performing operations that consume resources proportional to the size of the result set. Unexpectedly large result sets can occur under the following conditions:  \n  \n-   In queries against a large database that do not include appropriate filter conditions.  \n  \n-   In queries that create Cartesian joins on the server.  \n  \n-   In nested [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries.  \n  \n When accepting user input, you must make sure that the input cannot cause result sets to become larger than what the system can handle. You can also use the <xref:System.Linq.Queryable.Take%2A> method in [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] or the [LIMIT](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/language-reference/limit-entity-sql.md) operator in [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] to limit the size of the result set.  \n  \n#### Avoid Returning IQueryable Results When Exposing Methods to Potentially Untrusted Callers.  \n Avoid returning <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> types from methods that are exposed to potentially untrusted callers for the following reasons:  \n  \n-   A consumer of a query that exposes an <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> type could call methods on the result that expose secure data or increase the size of the result set. For example, consider the following method signature:  \n  \n    ```  \n    public IQueryable<Customer> GetCustomer(int customerId)  \n    ```  \n  \n     A consumer of this query could call `.Include(\"Orders\")` on the returned `IQueryable<Customer>` to retrieve data that the query did not intend to expose. This can be avoided by changing the return type of the method to <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable%601> and calling a method (such as `.ToList()`) that materializes the results.  \n  \n-   Because <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> queries are executed when the results are iterated over, a consumer of a query that exposes an <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> type could catch exceptions that are thrown. Exceptions could contain information not intended for the consumer.  \n  \n## Security Considerations for Entities  \n The following security considerations apply when generating and working with entity types.  \n  \n#### Do not share an ObjectContext across application domains.  \n Sharing an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> with more than one application domain may expose information in the connection string. Instead, you should transfer serialized objects or object graphs to the other application domain and then attach those objects to an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> in that application domain. For more information, see [Serializing Objects](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb738446(v=vs.100)).  \n  \n#### Prevent type safety violations.  \n If type safety is violated, the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] cannot guarantee the integrity of data in objects. Type safety violations could occur if you allow untrusted applications to run with full-trust code access security.  \n  \n#### Handle exceptions.  \n Access methods and properties of an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> within a try-catch block. Catching exceptions prevents unhandled exceptions from exposing entries in the <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectStateManager> or model information (such as table names) to users of your application.  \n  \n## Security Considerations for ASP.NET Applications  \n The following should be considered when you work with paths in [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)] applications.  \n  \n#### Verify whether your host performs path checks.  \n When the `|DataDirectory|` (enclosed in pipe symbols) substitution string is used, [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] verifies that the resolved path is supported. For example, \"..\" is not allowed behind `DataDirectory`. That same check for resolving the Web application root operator (`~`) is performed by the process hosting [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)]. IIS performs this check; however, hosts other than IIS may not verify that the resolved path is supported. You should know the behavior of the host on which you deploy an [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application.  \n  \n#### Do not make assumptions about resolved path names.  \n Although the values to which the root operator (`~`) and the `DataDirectory` substitution string resolve should remain constant during the application's runtime, the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not restrict the host from modifying these values.  \n  \n#### Verify the path length before deployment.  \n Before deploying an [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application, you should ensure that the values of the root operator (~) and `DataDirectory` substitution string do not exceed the limits of the path length in the operating system. [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] data providers do not ensure that the path length is within valid limits.  \n  \n## Security Considerations for ADO.NET Metadata  \n The following security considerations apply when generating and working with model and mapping files.  \n  \n#### Do not expose sensitive information through logging.  \n [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] metadata service components do not log any private information. If there are results that cannot be returned because of access restrictions, database management systems and file systems should return zero results instead of raising an exception that could contain sensitive information.  \n  \n#### Do not accept MetadataWorkspace objects from untrusted sources.  \n Applications should not accept instances of the <xref:System.Data.Metadata.Edm.MetadataWorkspace> class from untrusted sources. Instead, you should explicitly construct and populate a workspace from such a source.  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Securing ADO.NET Applications](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/securing-ado-net-applications.md)\n- [Deployment Considerations](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/deployment-considerations.md)\n- [Migration Considerations](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/migration-considerations.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,126],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.assetid: 84758642-9b72-4447-86f9-f831fef46962","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","nodes":[{"pos":[0,42],"content":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","pos":[0,42]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[133,175],"content":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","linkify":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations (Entity Framework)","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"This topic describes security considerations that are specific to developing, deploying, and running <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> applications.","pos":[176,353],"source":"This topic describes security considerations that are specific to developing, deploying, and running [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] applications."},{"content":"You should also follow recommendations for creating secure <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> applications.","pos":[354,493],"source":" You should also follow recommendations for creating secure [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] applications."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Security Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/security-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[494,604],"source":" For more information, see [Security Overview](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/security-overview.md)."},{"pos":[613,644],"content":"General Security Considerations","linkify":"General Security Considerations","nodes":[{"content":"General Security Considerations","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[648,788],"content":"The following security considerations apply to all applications that use the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph>.","source":"The following security considerations apply to all applications that use the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]."},{"pos":[799,838],"content":"Use only trusted data source providers.","linkify":"Use only trusted data source providers.","nodes":[{"content":"Use only trusted data source providers.","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"To communicate with the data source, a provider must do the following:","pos":[842,912]},{"pos":[922,1024],"content":"Receive the connection string from the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph>.","source":"Receive the connection string from the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]."},{"content":"Translate the command tree to the data source's native query language.","pos":[1034,1104]},{"content":"Assemble and return result sets.","pos":[1114,1146]},{"content":"During the logon operation, information that is based on the user password is passed to the server through the network libraries of the underlying data source.","pos":[1153,1312]},{"content":"A malicious provider can steal user credentials, generate malicious queries, or tamper with the result set.","pos":[1313,1420]},{"pos":[1431,1481],"content":"Encrypt your connection to protect sensitive data.","linkify":"Encrypt your connection to protect sensitive data.","nodes":[{"content":"Encrypt your connection to protect sensitive data.","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> does not directly handle data encryption.","pos":[1485,1593],"source":"The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not directly handle data encryption."},{"content":"If users access data over a public network, your application should establish an encrypted connection to the data source to increase security.","pos":[1594,1736]},{"content":"For more information, see the security-related documentation for your data source.","pos":[1737,1819]},{"content":"For a SQL Server data source, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Encrypting Connections to SQL Server<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=119544)</ept>.","pos":[1820,1941],"source":" For a SQL Server data source, see [Encrypting Connections to SQL Server](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=119544)."},{"pos":[1952,1981],"content":"Secure the connection string.","linkify":"Secure the connection string.","nodes":[{"content":"Secure the connection string.","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"Protecting access to your data source is one of the most important goals when securing an application.","pos":[1985,2087]},{"content":"A connection string presents a potential vulnerability if it is not secured or if it is improperly constructed.","pos":[2088,2199]},{"content":"When you store connection information in plain text or persist it in memory, you risk compromising your entire system.","pos":[2200,2318]},{"content":"The following are the recommended methods for securing connection strings:","pos":[2319,2393]},{"content":"Use Windows Authentication with a SQL Server data source.","pos":[2403,2460]},{"content":"When you use Windows Authentication to connect to a SQL Server data source, the connection string does not contain logon and password information.","pos":[2471,2617]},{"content":"Encrypt configuration file sections using protected configuration.","pos":[2627,2693]},{"content":"ASP.NET provides a feature called protected configuration that enables you to encrypt sensitive information in a configuration file.","pos":[2704,2836]},{"content":"Although primarily designed for ASP.NET, you can also use protected configuration to encrypt sections of configuration files in Windows applications.","pos":[2837,2986]},{"content":"For a detailed description of the new protected configuration capabilities, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Encrypting Configuration Information Using Protected Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/aspnet/53tyfkaw(v=vs.100))</ept>.","pos":[2987,3208],"source":" For a detailed description of the new protected configuration capabilities, see [Encrypting Configuration Information Using Protected Configuration](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/aspnet/53tyfkaw(v=vs.100))."},{"content":"Store connection strings in secured configuration files.","pos":[3218,3274]},{"content":"You should never embed connection strings in your source code.","pos":[3285,3347]},{"content":"You can store connection strings in configuration files, which eliminates the need to embed them in your application's code.","pos":[3348,3472]},{"content":"By default, the Entity Data Model Wizard stores connection strings in the application configuration file.","pos":[3473,3578]},{"content":"You must secure this file to prevent unauthorized access.","pos":[3579,3636]},{"content":"Use connection string builders when dynamically creating connections.","pos":[3646,3715]},{"content":"If you must construct connection strings at runtime, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnectionStringBuilder&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[3726,3855],"source":"If you must construct connection strings at runtime, use the <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnectionStringBuilder> class."},{"content":"This string builder class helps prevent connection string injection attacks by validating and escaping invalid input information.","pos":[3856,3985]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Build an EntityConnection Connection String<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/how-to-build-an-entityconnection-connection-string.md)</ept>.","pos":[3986,4166],"source":" For more information, see [How to: Build an EntityConnection Connection String](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/how-to-build-an-entityconnection-connection-string.md)."},{"content":"Also use the appropriate string builder class to construct the data source connection string that is part of the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> connection string.","pos":[4167,4361],"source":" Also use the appropriate string builder class to construct the data source connection string that is part of the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] connection string."},{"content":"For information about connection string builders for ADO.NET providers, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Connection String Builders<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/connection-string-builders.md)</ept>.","pos":[4362,4540],"source":" For information about connection string builders for ADO.NET providers, see [Connection String Builders](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/connection-string-builders.md)."},{"pos":[4547,4689],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Protecting Connection Information<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/protecting-connection-information.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Protecting Connection Information](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/protecting-connection-information.md)."},{"pos":[4700,4753],"content":"Do not expose an EntityConnection to untrusted users.","linkify":"Do not expose an EntityConnection to untrusted users.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not expose an EntityConnection to untrusted users.","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"An <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection&gt;</ph> object exposes the connection string of the underlying connection.","pos":[4757,4875],"source":"An <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> object exposes the connection string of the underlying connection."},{"content":"A user with access to an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection&gt;</ph> object can also change the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.ConnectionState&gt;</ph> of the underlying connection.","pos":[4876,5041],"source":" A user with access to an <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> object can also change the <xref:System.Data.ConnectionState> of the underlying connection."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection&gt;</ph> class is not thread safe.","pos":[5042,5120],"source":" The <xref:System.Data.EntityClient.EntityConnection> class is not thread safe."},{"pos":[5131,5184],"content":"Do not pass connections outside the security context.","linkify":"Do not pass connections outside the security context.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not pass connections outside the security context.","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"After a connection has been established, you must not pass it outside the security context.","pos":[5188,5279]},{"content":"For example, one thread with permission to open a connection should not store the connection in a global location.","pos":[5280,5394]},{"content":"If the connection is available in a global location, then another malicious thread can use the open connection without having that permission explicitly granted to it.","pos":[5395,5562]},{"pos":[5573,5651],"content":"Be aware that logon information and passwords may be visible in a memory dump.","linkify":"Be aware that logon information and passwords may be visible in a memory dump.","nodes":[{"content":"Be aware that logon information and passwords may be visible in a memory dump.","pos":[0,78]}]},{"content":"When data source logon and password information is supplied in the connection string, this information is maintained in memory until garbage collection reclaims the resources.","pos":[5655,5830]},{"content":"This makes it impossible to determine when a password string is no longer in memory.","pos":[5831,5915]},{"content":"If an application crashes, a memory dump file may contain sensitive security information, and the user running the application and any user with administrative access to the computer can view the memory dump file.","pos":[5916,6129]},{"content":"Use Windows Authentication for connections to Microsoft SQL Server.","pos":[6130,6197]},{"pos":[6208,6270],"content":"Grant users only the necessary permissions in the data source.","linkify":"Grant users only the necessary permissions in the data source.","nodes":[{"content":"Grant users only the necessary permissions in the data source.","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"A data source administrator should grant only the necessary permissions to users.","pos":[6274,6355]},{"content":"Even though <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> does not support DML statements that modify data, such as INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE, users can still access the connection to the data source.","pos":[6356,6563],"source":" Even though [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] does not support DML statements that modify data, such as INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE, users can still access the connection to the data source."},{"content":"A malicious user could use this connection to execute DML statements in the native language of the data source.","pos":[6564,6675]},{"pos":[6686,6732],"content":"Run applications with the minimum permissions.","linkify":"Run applications with the minimum permissions.","nodes":[{"content":"Run applications with the minimum permissions.","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"When you allow a managed application to run with full-trust permission, the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph> does not limit the application's access to your computer.","pos":[6736,6936],"source":"When you allow a managed application to run with full-trust permission, the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)] does not limit the application's access to your computer."},{"content":"This may enable a security vulnerability in your application to compromise the entire system.","pos":[6937,7030]},{"content":"To use code access security and other security mechanisms in the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)]</ph>, you should run applications by using partial-trust permissions and with the minimum set of permissions that are needed to enable the application to function.","pos":[7031,7321],"source":" To use code access security and other security mechanisms in the [!INCLUDE[dnprdnshort](../../../../../includes/dnprdnshort-md.md)], you should run applications by using partial-trust permissions and with the minimum set of permissions that are needed to enable the application to function."},{"content":"The following code access permissions are the minimum permissions your <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> application needs:","pos":[7322,7474],"source":" The following code access permissions are the minimum permissions your [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application needs:"},{"pos":[7484,7754],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermission&gt;</ph>: <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.Write&gt;</ph> to open the specified metadata files or <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.PathDiscovery&gt;</ph> to search a directory for metadata files.","source":"<xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.Write> to open the specified metadata files or <xref:System.Security.Permissions.FileIOPermissionAccess.PathDiscovery> to search a directory for metadata files."},{"pos":[7764,7940],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermission&gt;</ph>: <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermissionFlag.RestrictedMemberAccess&gt;</ph> to support LINQ to Entities queries.","source":"<xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.ReflectionPermissionFlag.RestrictedMemberAccess> to support LINQ to Entities queries."},{"pos":[7950,8155],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission&gt;</ph>: <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.PermissionState.Unrestricted&gt;</ph> to enlist in a <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Transactions.Transaction&gt;</ph>.","source":"<xref:System.Transactions.DistributedTransactionPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.PermissionState.Unrestricted> to enlist in a <xref:System.Transactions><xref:System.Transactions.Transaction>."},{"pos":[8165,8398],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermission&gt;</ph>: <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermissionFlag.SerializationFormatter&gt;</ph> to serialize exceptions by using the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Runtime.Serialization.ISerializable&gt;</ph> interface.","source":"<xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermission>: <xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityPermissionFlag.SerializationFormatter> to serialize exceptions by using the <xref:System.Runtime.Serialization.ISerializable> interface."},{"pos":[8408,8575],"content":"Permission to open a database connection and execute commands against the database, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlClientPermission&gt;</ph> for a SQL Server database.","source":"Permission to open a database connection and execute commands against the database, such as <xref:System.Data.SqlClient.SqlClientPermission> for a SQL Server database."},{"pos":[8582,8710],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Code Access Security and ADO.NET<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/code-access-security.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Code Access Security and ADO.NET](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/code-access-security.md)."},{"pos":[8721,8759],"content":"Do not install untrusted applications.","linkify":"Do not install untrusted applications.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not install untrusted applications.","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> does not enforce any security permissions and will invoke any user-supplied data object code in process regardless of whether it is trusted or not.","pos":[8763,8977],"source":"The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not enforce any security permissions and will invoke any user-supplied data object code in process regardless of whether it is trusted or not."},{"content":"Ensure that authentication and authorization of the client is performed by the data store and by your application.","pos":[8978,9092]},{"pos":[9103,9146],"content":"Restrict access to all configuration files.","linkify":"Restrict access to all configuration files.","nodes":[{"content":"Restrict access to all configuration files.","pos":[0,43]}]},{"pos":[9150,9387],"content":"An administrator must restrict write access to all files that specify configuration for an application, including to enterprisesec.config, security.config, machine.conf, and the application configuration file <ph id=\"ph1\">\\&lt;</ph><bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>application<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>&gt;.exe.config.","source":"An administrator must restrict write access to all files that specify configuration for an application, including to enterprisesec.config, security.config, machine.conf, and the application configuration file \\<*application*>.exe.config."},{"content":"The provider invariant name is modifiable in the app.config. The client application must take responsibility for accessing the underlying provider through the standard provider factory model by using a strong name.","pos":[9394,9608]},{"pos":[9619,9671],"content":"Restrict permissions to the model and mapping files.","linkify":"Restrict permissions to the model and mapping files.","nodes":[{"content":"Restrict permissions to the model and mapping files.","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"An administrator must restrict write access to the model and mapping files (.edmx, .csdl, .ssdl, and .msl) to only users who modify the model or mappings.","pos":[9675,9829]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> only requires read access to these files at run time.","pos":[9830,9950],"source":" The [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] only requires read access to these files at run time."},{"content":"An administrator should also restrict access to object layer and pre-compiled view source code files that are generated by the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_edm](../../../../../includes/adonet-edm-md.md)]</ph> tools.","pos":[9951,10149],"source":" An administrator should also restrict access to object layer and pre-compiled view source code files that are generated by the [!INCLUDE[adonet_edm](../../../../../includes/adonet-edm-md.md)] tools."},{"pos":[10158,10193],"content":"Security Considerations for Queries","linkify":"Security Considerations for Queries","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations for Queries","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"The following security considerations apply when querying a conceptual model.","pos":[10197,10274]},{"content":"These considerations apply to <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> queries using EntityClient and to object queries using LINQ, <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph>, and query builder methods.","pos":[10275,10499],"source":" These considerations apply to [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries using EntityClient and to object queries using LINQ, [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)], and query builder methods."},{"pos":[10510,10540],"content":"Prevent SQL injection attacks.","linkify":"Prevent SQL injection attacks.","nodes":[{"content":"Prevent SQL injection attacks.","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"Applications frequently take external input (from a user or another external agent) and perform actions based on that input.","pos":[10544,10668]},{"content":"Any input that is directly or indirectly derived from the user or an external agent might have content that uses the syntax of the target language in order to perform unauthorized actions.","pos":[10669,10857]},{"content":"When the target language is a Structured Query Language (SQL), such as <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[tsql](../../../../../includes/tsql-md.md)]</ph>, this manipulation is known as a SQL injection attack.","pos":[10858,11036],"source":" When the target language is a Structured Query Language (SQL), such as [!INCLUDE[tsql](../../../../../includes/tsql-md.md)], this manipulation is known as a SQL injection attack."},{"content":"A malicious user can inject commands directly into the query and drop a database table, cause a denial of service, or otherwise change the nature of the operation being performed.","pos":[11037,11216]},{"pos":[11226,11297],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> injection attacks:","source":"[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] injection attacks:"},{"content":"SQL injection attacks can be performed in <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> by supplying malicious input to values that are used in a query predicate and in parameter names.","pos":[11308,11500],"source":"SQL injection attacks can be performed in [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] by supplying malicious input to values that are used in a query predicate and in parameter names."},{"content":"To avoid the risk of SQL injection, you should never combine user input with <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> command text.","pos":[11501,11644],"source":" To avoid the risk of SQL injection, you should never combine user input with [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] command text."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> queries accept parameters everywhere that literals are accepted.","pos":[11655,11772],"source":"[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries accept parameters everywhere that literals are accepted."},{"content":"You should use parameterized queries instead of injecting literals from an external agent directly into the query.","pos":[11773,11887]},{"content":"You should also consider using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>query builder methods<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb896238(v=vs.100))</ept> to safely construct Entity SQL.","pos":[11888,12063],"source":" You should also consider using [query builder methods](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb896238(v=vs.100)) to safely construct Entity SQL."},{"pos":[12073,12162],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)]</ph> injection attacks:","source":"[!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] injection attacks:"},{"content":"Although query composition is possible in <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)]</ph>, it is performed through the object model API.","pos":[12173,12332],"source":"Although query composition is possible in [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)], it is performed through the object model API."},{"content":"Unlike <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> queries, <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)]</ph> queries are not composed by using string manipulation or concatenation, and they are not susceptible to traditional SQL injection attacks.","pos":[12333,12611],"source":" Unlike [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries, [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] queries are not composed by using string manipulation or concatenation, and they are not susceptible to traditional SQL injection attacks."},{"pos":[12622,12653],"content":"Prevent very large result sets.","linkify":"Prevent very large result sets.","nodes":[{"content":"Prevent very large result sets.","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"A very large result set could cause the client system to shut down if the client is performing operations that consume resources proportional to the size of the result set.","pos":[12657,12829]},{"content":"Unexpectedly large result sets can occur under the following conditions:","pos":[12830,12902]},{"content":"In queries against a large database that do not include appropriate filter conditions.","pos":[12912,12998]},{"content":"In queries that create Cartesian joins on the server.","pos":[13008,13061]},{"pos":[13071,13142],"content":"In nested <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> queries.","source":"In nested [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] queries."},{"content":"When accepting user input, you must make sure that the input cannot cause result sets to become larger than what the system can handle.","pos":[13149,13284]},{"content":"You can also use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Linq.Queryable.Take%2A&gt;</ph> method in <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)]</ph> or the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>LIMIT<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/language-reference/limit-entity-sql.md)</ept> operator in <ph id=\"ph3\">[!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)]</ph> to limit the size of the result set.","pos":[13285,13625],"source":" You can also use the <xref:System.Linq.Queryable.Take%2A> method in [!INCLUDE[linq_entities](../../../../../includes/linq-entities-md.md)] or the [LIMIT](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/language-reference/limit-entity-sql.md) operator in [!INCLUDE[esql](../../../../../includes/esql-md.md)] to limit the size of the result set."},{"pos":[13636,13726],"content":"Avoid Returning IQueryable Results When Exposing Methods to Potentially Untrusted Callers.","linkify":"Avoid Returning IQueryable Results When Exposing Methods to Potentially Untrusted Callers.","nodes":[{"content":"Avoid Returning IQueryable Results When Exposing Methods to Potentially Untrusted Callers.","pos":[0,90]}]},{"pos":[13730,13875],"content":"Avoid returning <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601&gt;</ph> types from methods that are exposed to potentially untrusted callers for the following reasons:","source":"Avoid returning <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> types from methods that are exposed to potentially untrusted callers for the following reasons:"},{"content":"A consumer of a query that exposes an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601&gt;</ph> type could call methods on the result that expose secure data or increase the size of the result set.","pos":[13885,14058],"source":"A consumer of a query that exposes an <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> type could call methods on the result that expose secure data or increase the size of the result set."},{"content":"For example, consider the following method signature:","pos":[14059,14112]},{"content":"A consumer of this query could call <ph id=\"ph1\">`.Include(\"Orders\")`</ph> on the returned <ph id=\"ph2\">`IQueryable&lt;Customer&gt;`</ph> to retrieve data that the query did not intend to expose.","pos":[14208,14361],"source":"A consumer of this query could call `.Include(\"Orders\")` on the returned `IQueryable<Customer>` to retrieve data that the query did not intend to expose."},{"content":"This can be avoided by changing the return type of the method to <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable%601&gt;</ph> and calling a method (such as <ph id=\"ph2\">`.ToList()`</ph>) that materializes the results.","pos":[14362,14550],"source":" This can be avoided by changing the return type of the method to <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable%601> and calling a method (such as `.ToList()`) that materializes the results."},{"content":"Because <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601&gt;</ph> queries are executed when the results are iterated over, a consumer of a query that exposes an <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601&gt;</ph> type could catch exceptions that are thrown.","pos":[14560,14775],"source":"Because <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> queries are executed when the results are iterated over, a consumer of a query that exposes an <xref:System.Linq.IQueryable%601> type could catch exceptions that are thrown."},{"content":"Exceptions could contain information not intended for the consumer.","pos":[14776,14843]},{"pos":[14852,14888],"content":"Security Considerations for Entities","linkify":"Security Considerations for Entities","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations for Entities","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"The following security considerations apply when generating and working with entity types.","pos":[14892,14982]},{"pos":[14993,15050],"content":"Do not share an ObjectContext across application domains.","linkify":"Do not share an ObjectContext across application domains.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not share an ObjectContext across application domains.","pos":[0,57]}]},{"content":"Sharing an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext&gt;</ph> with more than one application domain may expose information in the connection string.","pos":[15054,15192],"source":"Sharing an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> with more than one application domain may expose information in the connection string."},{"content":"Instead, you should transfer serialized objects or object graphs to the other application domain and then attach those objects to an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext&gt;</ph> in that application domain.","pos":[15193,15394],"source":" Instead, you should transfer serialized objects or object graphs to the other application domain and then attach those objects to an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> in that application domain."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Serializing Objects<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb738446(v=vs.100))</ept>.","pos":[15395,15532],"source":" For more information, see [Serializing Objects](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-4.0/bb738446(v=vs.100))."},{"pos":[15543,15574],"content":"Prevent type safety violations.","linkify":"Prevent type safety violations.","nodes":[{"content":"Prevent type safety violations.","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"If type safety is violated, the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> cannot guarantee the integrity of data in objects.","pos":[15578,15723],"source":"If type safety is violated, the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] cannot guarantee the integrity of data in objects."},{"content":"Type safety violations could occur if you allow untrusted applications to run with full-trust code access security.","pos":[15724,15839]},{"pos":[15850,15868],"content":"Handle exceptions.","linkify":"Handle exceptions.","nodes":[{"content":"Handle exceptions.","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Access methods and properties of an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext&gt;</ph> within a try-catch block.","pos":[15872,15974],"source":"Access methods and properties of an <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectContext> within a try-catch block."},{"content":"Catching exceptions prevents unhandled exceptions from exposing entries in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectStateManager&gt;</ph> or model information (such as table names) to users of your application.","pos":[15975,16172],"source":" Catching exceptions prevents unhandled exceptions from exposing entries in the <xref:System.Data.Objects.ObjectStateManager> or model information (such as table names) to users of your application."},{"pos":[16181,16229],"content":"Security Considerations for ASP.NET Applications","linkify":"Security Considerations for ASP.NET Applications","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations for ASP.NET Applications","pos":[0,48]}]},{"pos":[16233,16370],"content":"The following should be considered when you work with paths in <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)]</ph> applications.","source":"The following should be considered when you work with paths in [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)] applications."},{"pos":[16381,16427],"content":"Verify whether your host performs path checks.","linkify":"Verify whether your host performs path checks.","nodes":[{"content":"Verify whether your host performs path checks.","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"When the <ph id=\"ph1\">`|DataDirectory|`</ph> (enclosed in pipe symbols) substitution string is used, <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph> verifies that the resolved path is supported.","pos":[16431,16620],"source":"When the `|DataDirectory|` (enclosed in pipe symbols) substitution string is used, [!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] verifies that the resolved path is supported."},{"content":"For example, \"..\" is not allowed behind <ph id=\"ph1\">`DataDirectory`</ph>.","pos":[16621,16677],"source":" For example, \"..\" is not allowed behind `DataDirectory`."},{"content":"That same check for resolving the Web application root operator (<ph id=\"ph1\">`~`</ph>) is performed by the process hosting <ph id=\"ph2\">[!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)]</ph>.","pos":[16678,16845],"source":" That same check for resolving the Web application root operator (`~`) is performed by the process hosting [!INCLUDE[vstecasp](../../../../../includes/vstecasp-md.md)]."},{"content":"IIS performs this check; however, hosts other than IIS may not verify that the resolved path is supported.","pos":[16846,16952]},{"content":"You should know the behavior of the host on which you deploy an <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> application.","pos":[16953,17092],"source":" You should know the behavior of the host on which you deploy an [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application."},{"pos":[17103,17153],"content":"Do not make assumptions about resolved path names.","linkify":"Do not make assumptions about resolved path names.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not make assumptions about resolved path names.","pos":[0,50]}]},{"pos":[17157,17441],"content":"Although the values to which the root operator (<ph id=\"ph1\">`~`</ph>) and the <ph id=\"ph2\">`DataDirectory`</ph> substitution string resolve should remain constant during the application's runtime, the <ph id=\"ph3\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> does not restrict the host from modifying these values.","source":"Although the values to which the root operator (`~`) and the `DataDirectory` substitution string resolve should remain constant during the application's runtime, the [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] does not restrict the host from modifying these values."},{"pos":[17452,17493],"content":"Verify the path length before deployment.","linkify":"Verify the path length before deployment.","nodes":[{"content":"Verify the path length before deployment.","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"Before deploying an <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)]</ph> application, you should ensure that the values of the root operator (~) and <ph id=\"ph2\">`DataDirectory`</ph> substitution string do not exceed the limits of the path length in the operating system.","pos":[17497,17760],"source":"Before deploying an [!INCLUDE[adonet_ef](../../../../../includes/adonet-ef-md.md)] application, you should ensure that the values of the root operator (~) and `DataDirectory` substitution string do not exceed the limits of the path length in the operating system."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph> data providers do not ensure that the path length is within valid limits.","pos":[17761,17895],"source":"[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] data providers do not ensure that the path length is within valid limits."},{"pos":[17904,17948],"content":"Security Considerations for ADO.NET Metadata","linkify":"Security Considerations for ADO.NET Metadata","nodes":[{"content":"Security Considerations for ADO.NET Metadata","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"The following security considerations apply when generating and working with model and mapping files.","pos":[17952,18053]},{"pos":[18064,18116],"content":"Do not expose sensitive information through logging.","linkify":"Do not expose sensitive information through logging.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not expose sensitive information through logging.","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)]</ph> metadata service components do not log any private information.","pos":[18120,18244],"source":"[!INCLUDE[vstecado](../../../../../includes/vstecado-md.md)] metadata service components do not log any private information."},{"content":"If there are results that cannot be returned because of access restrictions, database management systems and file systems should return zero results instead of raising an exception that could contain sensitive information.","pos":[18245,18467]},{"pos":[18478,18541],"content":"Do not accept MetadataWorkspace objects from untrusted sources.","linkify":"Do not accept MetadataWorkspace objects from untrusted sources.","nodes":[{"content":"Do not accept MetadataWorkspace objects from untrusted sources.","pos":[0,63]}]},{"content":"Applications should not accept instances of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Metadata.Edm.MetadataWorkspace&gt;</ph> class from untrusted sources.","pos":[18545,18672],"source":"Applications should not accept instances of the <xref:System.Data.Metadata.Edm.MetadataWorkspace> class from untrusted sources."},{"content":"Instead, you should explicitly construct and populate a workspace from such a source.","pos":[18673,18758]},{"pos":[18767,18775],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[18779,18886],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Securing ADO.NET Applications<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/securing-ado-net-applications.md)</ept>","source":"[Securing ADO.NET Applications](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/securing-ado-net-applications.md)"},{"pos":[18889,18991],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deployment Considerations<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/deployment-considerations.md)</ept>","source":"[Deployment Considerations](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/deployment-considerations.md)"},{"pos":[18994,19094],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Migration Considerations<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/migration-considerations.md)</ept>","source":"[Migration Considerations](../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/ef/migration-considerations.md)"}]}