{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Arrays in Visual Basic\"\nms.date: 12/06/2017\nf1_keywords:\n  - \"vb.Array\"\nhelpviewer_keywords:\n  - \"arrays [Visual Basic]\"\n  - \"Visual Basic, arrays\"\nms.assetid: dbf29737-b589-4443-bee6-a27588d9c67e\n---\n\n# Arrays in Visual Basic\n\nAn array is a set of values, which are termed *elements*, that are logically related to each other. For example, an array may consist of the number of students in each grade in a grammar school; each element of the array is the number of students in a single grade. Similarly, an array may consist of a student's grades for a class; each element of the array is a single grade.\n\nIt is possible individual variables to store each of our data items. For example, if our application analyzes student grades, we can use a separate variable for each student's grade, such as `englishGrade1`, `englishGrade2`, etc. This approach has three major limitations:\n\n- We have to know at design time exactly how many grades we have to handle.\n- Handling large numbers of grades quickly becomes unwieldy. This in turn makes an application much more likely to have serious bugs.\n- It is difficult to maintain. Each new grade that we add requires that the application be modified, recompiled, and redeployed.\n\nBy using an array, you can refer to these related values by the same name, and use a number that’s called an *index* or *subscript* to identify an individual element based on its position in the array. The indexes of an array range from 0 to one less than the total number of elements in the array. When you use Visual Basic syntax to define the size of an array, you specify its highest index, not the total number of elements in the array. You can work with the array as a unit, and the ability to iterate its elements frees you from needing to know exactly how many elements it contains at design time.\n\nSome quick examples before explanation:\n\n```vb\n' Declare a single-dimension array of 5 numbers.\nDim numbers(4) As Integer\n\n'Declare a single-dimension array and set its 4 values.\nDim numbers = New Integer() {1, 2, 4, 8}\n\n' Change the size of an existing array to 16 elements and retain the current values.\nReDim Preserve numbers(15)\n\n' Redefine the size of an existing array and reset the values.\nReDim numbers(15)\n\n' Declare a 6 x 6 multidimensional array.\nDim matrix(5, 5) As Double\n\n' Declare a 4 x 3 multidimensional array and set array element values.\nDim matrix = New Integer(3, 2) {{1, 2, 3}, {2, 3, 4}, {3, 4, 5}, {4, 5, 6}}\n\n' Declare a jagged array\nDim sales()() As Double = New Double(11)() {}\n```\n\n## Array elements in a simple array\n\nLet's create an array named `students` to store the number of students in each grade in a grammar school. The indexes of the elements range from 0 through 6. Using this array is simpler than declaring seven variables.\n\nThe following illustration shows the `students` array. For each element of the array:\n\n- The index of the element represents the grade (index 0 represents kindergarten).\n\n- The value that’s contained in the element represents the number of students in that grade.\n\n![Diagram showing an array of the numbers of students](./media/index/students-array-elements.gif)\n\nThe following example contains the Visual Basic code that creates and uses the array:\n\n[!code-vb[simple-array](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/simple-array.vb)]\n\nThe example does three things:\n\n- It declares a `students` array with seven elements. The number `6` in the array declaration indicates the last index in the array; it is one less than the number of elements in the array.\n- It assigns values to each element in the array. Array elements are accessed by using the array name and including the index of the individual element in parentheses.\n- It lists each value of the array. The example uses a [`For`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement to access each element of the array by its index number.\n\nThe `students` array in the preceding example is a one-dimensional array because it uses one index. An array that uses more than one index or subscript is called *multidimensional*. For more information, see the rest of this article and [Array Dimensions in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md).\n\n## Creating an array\n\nYou can define the size of an array in several ways:\n\n- You can specify the size when the array is declared:\n\n  [!code-vb[creating1](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#1)]\n\n- You can use a `New` clause to supply the size of an array when it’s created:\n\n  [!code-vb[creating2](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#2)]\n\nIf you have an existing array, you can redefine its size by using the [`ReDim`](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement. You can specify that the `ReDim` statement keep the values that are in the array, or you can specify that it create an empty array. The following example shows different uses of the `ReDim` statement to modify the size of an existing array.\n\n[!code-vb[redimensioning](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#3)]\n\nFor more information, see the [ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md).\n\n## Storing values in an array\n\nYou can access each location in an array by using an index of type `Integer`. You can store and retrieve values in an array by referencing each array location by using its index enclosed in parentheses. Indexes for multidimensional arrays are separated by commas (,). You need one index for each array dimension.\n\nThe following example shows some statements that store and retrieve values in arrays.\n\n[!code-vb[store-and-retrieve](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/store-and-retrieve.vb)]\n\n## Populating an array with array literals\n\nBy using an array literal, you can populate an array with an initial set of values at the same time that you create it. An array literal consists of a list of comma-separated values that are enclosed in braces (`{}`).\n\nWhen you create an array by using an array literal, you can either supply the array type or use type inference to determine the array type. The following example shows both options.\n\n[!code-vb[create-with-literals](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#4)]\n\nWhen you use type inference, the type of the array is determined by the *dominant type* in the list of literal values. The dominant type is the type to which all other types in the array can widen. If this unique type can’t be determined, the dominant type is the unique type to which all other types in the array can narrow. If neither of these unique types can be determined, the dominant type is `Object`. For example, if the list of values that’s supplied to the array literal contains values of type `Integer`, `Long`, and `Double`, the resulting array is of type `Double`. Because `Integer` and `Long` widen only to `Double`, `Double` is the dominant type. For more information, see [Widening and Narrowing Conversions](../../language-features/data-types/widening-and-narrowing-conversions.md).\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> You can use type inference only for arrays that are defined as local variables in a type member. If an explicit type definition is absent, arrays defined with array literals at the class level are of type `Object[]`. For more information, see [Local type inference](../variables/local-type-inference.md).\n\nNote that the previous example defines `values` as an array of type `Double` even though all the array literals are of type `Integer`. You can create this array because the values in the array literal can widen to `Double` values.\n\nYou can also create and populate a multidimensional array by using *nested array literals*. Nested array literals must have a number of dimensions that’s consistent with the resulting array. The following example creates a two-dimensional array of integers by using nested array literals.\n\n[!code-vb[nested-array-literals](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#5)]\n\nWhen using nested array literals to create and populate an array, an error occurs if the number of elements in the nested array literals don't match. An error also occurs if you explicitly declare the array variable to have a different number of dimensions than the array literals.\n\nJust as you can for one-dimensional arrays, you can rely on type inference when creating a multidimensional array with nested array literals. The inferred type is the dominant type for all the values in all the array literals for all nesting level. The following example creates a two-dimensional array of type `Double[,]` from values that are of type `Integer` and `Double`.\n\n[!code-vb[nested-type-inference](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/create-array.vb#6)]\n\nFor additional examples, see [How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md).\n\n## Iterating through an array\n\nWhen you iterate through an array, you access each element in the array from the lowest index to the highest or from the highest to the lowest. Typically, use either the [For...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) or the [For Each...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md) to iterate through the elements of an array. When you don't know the upper bounds of the array, you can call the <xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to get the highest value of the index. Although lowest index value is almost always 0, you can call the <xref:System.Array.GetLowerBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to get the lowest value of the index.\n\nThe following example iterates through a one-dimensional array by using the [`For...Next`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement.\n\n[!code-vb[iterate-one-dimensional-array](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/iterate1d.vb)]\n\nThe following example iterates through a multidimensional array by using a [`For...Next`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement. The <xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A> method has a parameter that specifies the dimension. `GetUpperBound(0)` returns the highest index of the first dimension, and `GetUpperBound(1)` returns the highest index of the second dimension.\n\n[!code-vb[iterate-two-dimensional-array](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/iterate2d.vb)]\n\nThe following example uses a [For Each...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md)to iterate through a one-dimensional array and a two-dimensional array.\n\n[!code-vb[iterate-for-each-next](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/iterate-for-each-next.vb)]\n\n## Array size\n\nThe size of an array is the product of the lengths of all its dimensions. It represents the total number of elements currently contained in the array.  For example, the following example declares a 2-dimensional array with four elements in each dimension. As the output from the example shows, the array's size is 16 (or (3 + 1) * (3 + 1).\n\n[!code-vb[array-size](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/array-size.vb)]\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> This discussion of array size does not apply to jagged arrays. For information on jagged arrays and determining the size of a jagged array, see the [Jagged arrays](#jagged-arrays) section.\n\nYou can find the size of an array by using the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property. You can find the length of each dimension of a multidimensional array by using the <xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\nYou can resize an array variable by assigning a new array object to it or by using the [`ReDim` Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement. The following example uses the `ReDim` statement to change a 100-element array to a 51-element array.\n\n[!code-vb[resize-an-array](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/array-size2.vb)]\n\nThere are several things to keep in mind when dealing with the size of an array.\n\n|||\n|---|---|\n|Dimension Length|The index of each dimension is 0-based, which means it ranges from 0 to its upper bound. Therefore, the length of a given dimension is one greater than the declared upper bound of that dimension.|\n|Length Limits|The length of every dimension of an array is limited to the maximum value of the `Integer` data type, which is <xref:System.Int32.MaxValue?displayProperty=nameWithType> or (2 ^ 31) - 1. However, the total size of an array is also limited by the memory available on your system. If you attempt to initialize an array that exceeds the amount of available memory, the runtime throws an <xref:System.OutOfMemoryException>.|\n|Size and Element Size|An array's size is independent of the data type of its elements. The size always represents the total number of elements, not the number of bytes that they consume in memory.|\n|Memory Consumption|It is not safe to make any assumptions regarding how an array is stored in memory. Storage varies on platforms of different data widths, so the same array can consume more memory on a 64-bit system than on a 32-bit system. Depending on system configuration when you initialize an array, the common language runtime (CLR) can assign storage either to pack elements as close together as possible, or to align them all on natural hardware boundaries. Also, an array requires a storage overhead for its control information, and this overhead increases with each added dimension.|\n\n## The array type\n\nEvery array has a data type, which differs from the data type of its elements. There is no single data type for all arrays. Instead, the data type of an array is determined by the number of dimensions, or *rank*, of the array, and the data type of the elements in the array. Two array variables are of the same data type only when they have the same rank and their elements have the same data type. The lengths of the dimensions of an array do not influence the array data type.\n\nEvery array inherits from the <xref:System.Array?displayProperty=nameWithType> class, and you can declare a variable to be of type `Array`, but you cannot create an array of type `Array`. For example, although the following code declares the `arr` variable to be of type `Array` and calls the <xref:System.Array.CreateInstance%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to instantiate the array, the array's type proves to be Object[].\n\n[!code-vb[array-class](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/array-class.vb)]\n\nAlso, the [ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) cannot operate on a variable declared as type `Array`. For these reasons, and for type safety, it is advisable to declare every array as a specific type.\n\nYou can find out the data type of either an array or its elements in several ways.\n\n- You can call the <xref:System.Object.GetType%2A> method on the variable to get a <xref:System.Type> object that represents the run-time type of the variable. The <xref:System.Type> object holds extensive information in its properties and methods.\n- You can pass the variable to the <xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.TypeName%2A> function to get a `String` with the name of run-time type.\n\nThe following example calls the both the `GetType` method and the `TypeName` function to determine the type of an array. The array type is `Byte(,)`. Note that the <xref:System.Type.BaseType%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property also indicates that the base type of the byte array is the <xref:System.Array> class.\n\n[!code-vb[array-type](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/array-type.vb)]\n\n## Arrays as return values and parameters\n\nTo return an array from a `Function` procedure, specify the array data type and the number of dimensions as the return type of the [Function Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/function-statement.md). Within the function, declare a local array variable with same data type and number of dimensions. In the [Return Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/return-statement.md), include the local array variable without parentheses.\n\nTo specify an array as a parameter to a `Sub` or `Function` procedure, define the parameter as an array with a specified data type and number of dimensions. In the call to the procedure, pass an array variable with the same data type and number of dimensions.\n\nIn the following example, the `GetNumbers` function returns an `Integer()`, a one-dimensional array of type `Integer`. The `ShowNumbers` procedure accepts an `Integer()` argument.\n\n[!code-vb[return-value-and-params](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/return-values-and-params.vb)]\n\nIn the following example, the `GetNumbersMultiDim` function returns an `Integer(,)`, a two-dimensional array of type `Integer`.  The `ShowNumbersMultiDim` procedure accepts an `Integer(,)` argument.\n\n[!code-vb[multidimensional-return-value](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/return-values-and-params-2d.vb)]\n\n## Jagged arrays\n\nSometimes the data structure in your application is two-dimensional but not rectangular. For example, you might use an array to store data about the high temperature of each day of the month. The first dimension of the array represents the month, but the second dimension represents the number of days, and the number of days in a month is not uniform. A *jagged array*, which is also called an *array of arrays*, is designed for such scenarios. A jagged array is an array whose elements are also arrays. A jagged array and each element in a jagged array can have one or more dimensions.\n\nThe following example uses an array of months, each element of which is an array of days. The example uses a jagged array because different months have different numbers of days.  The example shows how to create a jagged array, assign values to it, and retrieve and display its values.\n\n[!code-vb[jagged-arrays](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/jagged.vb)]\n\nThe previous example assigns values to the jagged array on an element-by-element basis by using a `For...Next` loop. You can also assign values to the elements of a jagged array by using nested array literals. However, the attempt to use nested array literals (for example, `Dim valuesjagged = {{1, 2}, {2, 3, 4}}`) generates compiler error [BC30568](../../../,,/../misc/bc30568.md). To correct the error, enclose the inner array literals in parentheses. The parentheses force the array literal expression to be evaluated, and the resulting values are used with the outer array literal, as the following example shows.\n\n[!code-vb[jagged-array-initialization](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/jagged-assign.vb)]\n\nA jagged array is a one-dimensional array whose elements contain arrays. Therefore, the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property and the `Array.GetLength(0)` method return the number of elements in the one-dimensional array, and `Array.GetLength(1)` throws an <xref:System.IndexOutOfRangeException> because a jagged array is not multidimensional. You determine the number of elements in each subarray by retrieving the value of each subarray's <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property. The following example illustrates how to determine the number of elements in a jagged array.\n\n[!code-vb[jagged-array-size](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/jagged-length.vb)]\n\n## Zero-length arrays\n\nVisual Basic differentiates between a uninitialized array (an array whose value is `Nothing`) and a *zero-length array* or empty array (an array that has no elements.) An uninitialized array is one that has not been dimensioned or had any values assigned to it. For example:\n\n```vb\nDim arr() As String\n```\n\nA zero-length array is declared with a dimension of -1. For example:\n\n```vb\nDim arrZ(-1) As String\n```\n\nYou might need to create a zero-length array under the following circumstances:\n\n- Without risking a <xref:System.NullReferenceException> exception, your code must access members of the <xref:System.Array> class, such as <xref:System.Array.Length%2A> or <xref:System.Array.Rank%2A>, or call a Visual Basic function such as <xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.UBound%2A>.\n\n- You want to keep your code simple by not having to check for `Nothing` as a special case.\n\n- Your code interacts with an application programming interface (API) that either requires you to pass a zero-length array to one or more procedures or returns a zero-length array from one or more procedures.\n\n## Splitting an array\n\nIn some cases, you may need to split a single array into multiple arrays. This involves identifying the point or points at which the array is to be split, and then spitting the array into two or more separate arrays.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> This section does not discuss splitting a single string into a string array based on some delimiter. For information on splitting a string, see the <xref:System.String.Split%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\nThe most common criteria for splitting an array are:\n\n- The number of elements in the array. For example, you might want to split an array of more than a specified number of elements into a number of approximately equal parts. For this purpose, you can use the value returned by either the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> or <xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\n- The value of an element, which serves as a delimiter that indicates where the array should be split. You can search for a specific value by calling the <xref:System.Array.FindIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> and <xref:System.Array.FindLastIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> methods.\n\nOnce you've determined the index or indexes at which the array should be split, you can then create the individual arrays by calling the <xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\nThe following example splits an array into two arrays of approximately equal size. (If the total number of array elements is odd, the first array has one more element than the second.)\n\n[!code-vb[splitting-an-array-by-length](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/split1.vb)]\n\nThe following example splits a string array into two arrays based on the presence of an element whose value is \"zzz\", which serves as the array delimiter. The new arrays do not include the element that contains the delimiter.\n\n[!code-vb[splitting-an-array-by-delimiter](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/split2.vb)]\n\n## Joining arrays\n\nYou can also combine a number of arrays into a single larger array. To do this, you also use the <xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> This section does not discuss joining a string array into a single string. For information on joining a string array, see the <xref:System.String.Join%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.\n\nBefore copying the elements of each array into the new array, you must first ensure that you have initialized the array so that it is large enough to accommodate the new array. You can do this in one of two ways:\n\n- Use the [`ReDim Preserve`](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement to dynamically expand the array before adding new elements to it. This is the easiest technique, but it can result in performance degradation and excessive memory consumption when you are copying large arrays.\n- Calculate the total number of elements needed for the new large array, then add the elements of each source array to it.\n\nThe following example uses the second approach to add four arrays with ten elements each to a single array.\n\n[!code-vb[joining-an-array](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/join.vb)]\n\nSince in this case the source arrays are all small, we can also dynamically expand the array as we add the elements of each new array to it. The following example does that.\n\n[!code-vb[joining-an-array-dynamically](~/samples/snippets/visualbasic/programming-guide/language-features/arrays/join2.vb)]\n\n## Collections as an alternative to arrays\n\nArrays are most useful for creating and working with a fixed number of strongly typed objects. Collections provide a more flexible way to work with groups of objects. Unlike arrays, which require that you explicitly change the size of an array with the [`ReDim` Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md), collections grow and shrink dynamically as the needs of an application change.\n\nWhen you use `ReDim` to redimension an array, Visual Basic creates a new array and releases the previous one. This takes execution time. Therefore, if the number of items you are working with changes frequently, or you cannot predict the maximum number of items you need, you'll usually obtain better performance by using a collection.\n\nFor some collections, you can assign a key to any object that you put into the collection so that you can quickly retrieve the object by using the key.\n\nIf your collection contains elements of only one data type, you can use one of the classes in the <xref:System.Collections.Generic?displayProperty=nameWithType> namespace. A generic collection enforces type safety so that no other data type can be added to it.\n\nFor more information about collections, see [Collections](../../concepts/collections.md).\n\n## Related topics\n\n|Term|Definition|\n|----------|----------------|\n|[Array Dimensions in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md)|Explains rank and dimensions in arrays.|\n|[How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md)|Describes how to populate arrays with initial values.|\n|[How to: Sort An Array in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-sort-an-array.md)|Shows how to sort the elements of an array alphabetically.|\n|[How to: Assign One Array to Another Array](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-assign-one-array-to-another-array.md)|Describes the rules and steps for assigning an array to another array variable.|\n|[Troubleshooting Arrays](../../language-features/arrays/troubleshooting-arrays.md)|Discusses some common problems that arise when working with arrays.|\n\n## See also\n\n- <xref:System.Array?displayProperty=nameWithType>\n- [Dim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/dim-statement.md)\n- [ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,208],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Arrays in Visual Basic\"\nms.date: 12/06/2017\nf1_keywords:\n  - \"vb.Array\"\nhelpviewer_keywords:\n  - \"arrays [Visual Basic]\"\n  - \"Visual Basic, arrays\"\nms.assetid: dbf29737-b589-4443-bee6-a27588d9c67e","nodes":[{"content":"Arrays in Visual Basic","nodes":[{"pos":[0,22],"content":"Arrays in Visual Basic","nodes":[{"content":"Arrays in Visual Basic","pos":[0,22]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[216,238],"content":"Arrays in Visual Basic","linkify":"Arrays in Visual Basic","nodes":[{"content":"Arrays in Visual Basic","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"An array is a set of values, which are termed <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>elements<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, that are logically related to each other.","pos":[240,339],"source":"An array is a set of values, which are termed *elements*, that are logically related to each other."},{"content":"For example, an array may consist of the number of students in each grade in a grammar school; each element of the array is the number of students in a single grade.","pos":[340,505]},{"content":"Similarly, an array may consist of a student's grades for a class; each element of the array is a single grade.","pos":[506,617]},{"content":"It is possible individual variables to store each of our data items.","pos":[619,687]},{"content":"For example, if our application analyzes student grades, we can use a separate variable for each student's grade, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`englishGrade1`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`englishGrade2`</ph>, etc. This approach has three major limitations:","pos":[688,891],"source":" For example, if our application analyzes student grades, we can use a separate variable for each student's grade, such as `englishGrade1`, `englishGrade2`, etc. This approach has three major limitations:"},{"content":"We have to know at design time exactly how many grades we have to handle.","pos":[895,968]},{"content":"Handling large numbers of grades quickly becomes unwieldy.","pos":[971,1029]},{"content":"This in turn makes an application much more likely to have serious bugs.","pos":[1030,1102]},{"content":"It is difficult to maintain.","pos":[1105,1133]},{"content":"Each new grade that we add requires that the application be modified, recompiled, and redeployed.","pos":[1134,1231]},{"content":"By using an array, you can refer to these related values by the same name, and use a number that’s called an <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>index<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>subscript<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> to identify an individual element based on its position in the array.","pos":[1233,1434],"source":"By using an array, you can refer to these related values by the same name, and use a number that’s called an *index* or *subscript* to identify an individual element based on its position in the array."},{"content":"The indexes of an array range from 0 to one less than the total number of elements in the array.","pos":[1435,1531]},{"content":"When you use Visual Basic syntax to define the size of an array, you specify its highest index, not the total number of elements in the array.","pos":[1532,1674]},{"content":"You can work with the array as a unit, and the ability to iterate its elements frees you from needing to know exactly how many elements it contains at design time.","pos":[1675,1838]},{"content":"Some quick examples before explanation:","pos":[1840,1879]},{"pos":[2553,2585],"content":"Array elements in a simple array","linkify":"Array elements in a simple array","nodes":[{"content":"Array elements in a simple array","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"Let's create an array named <ph id=\"ph1\">`students`</ph> to store the number of students in each grade in a grammar school.","pos":[2587,2692],"source":"Let's create an array named `students` to store the number of students in each grade in a grammar school."},{"content":"The indexes of the elements range from 0 through 6.","pos":[2693,2744]},{"content":"Using this array is simpler than declaring seven variables.","pos":[2745,2804]},{"content":"The following illustration shows the <ph id=\"ph1\">`students`</ph> array.","pos":[2806,2860],"source":"The following illustration shows the `students` array."},{"content":"For each element of the array:","pos":[2861,2891]},{"content":"The index of the element represents the grade (index 0 represents kindergarten).","pos":[2895,2975]},{"content":"The value that’s contained in the element represents the number of students in that grade.","pos":[2979,3069]},{"content":"Diagram showing an array of the numbers of students","pos":[3073,3124]},{"content":"The following example contains the Visual Basic code that creates and uses the array:","pos":[3170,3255]},{"content":"The example does three things:","pos":[3374,3404]},{"content":"It declares a <ph id=\"ph1\">`students`</ph> array with seven elements.","pos":[3408,3459],"source":"It declares a `students` array with seven elements."},{"content":"The number <ph id=\"ph1\">`6`</ph> in the array declaration indicates the last index in the array; it is one less than the number of elements in the array.","pos":[3460,3595],"source":" The number `6` in the array declaration indicates the last index in the array; it is one less than the number of elements in the array."},{"content":"It assigns values to each element in the array.","pos":[3598,3645]},{"content":"Array elements are accessed by using the array name and including the index of the individual element in parentheses.","pos":[3646,3763]},{"content":"It lists each value of the array.","pos":[3766,3799]},{"content":"The example uses a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`For`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md)</ept> statement to access each element of the array by its index number.","pos":[3800,3955],"source":" The example uses a [`For`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement to access each element of the array by its index number."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`students`</ph> array in the preceding example is a one-dimensional array because it uses one index.","pos":[3957,4056],"source":"The `students` array in the preceding example is a one-dimensional array because it uses one index."},{"content":"An array that uses more than one index or subscript is called <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>multidimensional<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[4057,4138],"source":" An array that uses more than one index or subscript is called *multidimensional*."},{"content":"For more information, see the rest of this article and <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Array Dimensions in Visual Basic<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md)</ept>.","pos":[4139,4281],"source":" For more information, see the rest of this article and [Array Dimensions in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md)."},{"pos":[4286,4303],"content":"Creating an array","linkify":"Creating an array","nodes":[{"content":"Creating an array","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"You can define the size of an array in several ways:","pos":[4305,4357]},{"content":"You can specify the size when the array is declared:","pos":[4361,4413]},{"pos":[4535,4611],"content":"You can use a <ph id=\"ph1\">`New`</ph> clause to supply the size of an array when it’s created:","source":"You can use a `New` clause to supply the size of an array when it’s created:"},{"content":"If you have an existing array, you can redefine its size by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept> statement.","pos":[4731,4880],"source":"If you have an existing array, you can redefine its size by using the [`ReDim`](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement."},{"content":"You can specify that the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> statement keep the values that are in the array, or you can specify that it create an empty array.","pos":[4881,5012],"source":" You can specify that the `ReDim` statement keep the values that are in the array, or you can specify that it create an empty array."},{"content":"The following example shows different uses of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> statement to modify the size of an existing array.","pos":[5013,5121],"source":" The following example shows different uses of the `ReDim` statement to modify the size of an existing array."},{"pos":[5244,5351],"content":"For more information, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ReDim Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see the [ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)."},{"pos":[5356,5382],"content":"Storing values in an array","linkify":"Storing values in an array","nodes":[{"content":"Storing values in an array","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"You can access each location in an array by using an index of type <ph id=\"ph1\">`Integer`</ph>.","pos":[5384,5461],"source":"You can access each location in an array by using an index of type `Integer`."},{"content":"You can store and retrieve values in an array by referencing each array location by using its index enclosed in parentheses.","pos":[5462,5586]},{"content":"Indexes for multidimensional arrays are separated by commas (,).","pos":[5587,5651]},{"content":"You need one index for each array dimension.","pos":[5652,5696]},{"content":"The following example shows some statements that store and retrieve values in arrays.","pos":[5698,5783]},{"pos":[5917,5956],"content":"Populating an array with array literals","linkify":"Populating an array with array literals","nodes":[{"content":"Populating an array with array literals","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"By using an array literal, you can populate an array with an initial set of values at the same time that you create it.","pos":[5958,6077]},{"content":"An array literal consists of a list of comma-separated values that are enclosed in braces (<ph id=\"ph1\">`{}`</ph>).","pos":[6078,6175],"source":" An array literal consists of a list of comma-separated values that are enclosed in braces (`{}`)."},{"content":"When you create an array by using an array literal, you can either supply the array type or use type inference to determine the array type.","pos":[6177,6316]},{"content":"The following example shows both options.","pos":[6317,6358]},{"content":"When you use type inference, the type of the array is determined by the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>dominant type<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> in the list of literal values.","pos":[6487,6605],"source":"When you use type inference, the type of the array is determined by the *dominant type* in the list of literal values."},{"content":"The dominant type is the type to which all other types in the array can widen.","pos":[6606,6684]},{"content":"If this unique type can’t be determined, the dominant type is the unique type to which all other types in the array can narrow.","pos":[6685,6812]},{"content":"If neither of these unique types can be determined, the dominant type is <ph id=\"ph1\">`Object`</ph>.","pos":[6813,6895],"source":" If neither of these unique types can be determined, the dominant type is `Object`."},{"content":"For example, if the list of values that’s supplied to the array literal contains values of type <ph id=\"ph1\">`Integer`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Long`</ph>, and <ph id=\"ph3\">`Double`</ph>, the resulting array is of type <ph id=\"ph4\">`Double`</ph>.","pos":[6896,7065],"source":" For example, if the list of values that’s supplied to the array literal contains values of type `Integer`, `Long`, and `Double`, the resulting array is of type `Double`."},{"content":"Because <ph id=\"ph1\">`Integer`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`Long`</ph> widen only to <ph id=\"ph3\">`Double`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph4\">`Double`</ph> is the dominant type.","pos":[7066,7149],"source":" Because `Integer` and `Long` widen only to `Double`, `Double` is the dominant type."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Widening and Narrowing Conversions<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/data-types/widening-and-narrowing-conversions.md)</ept>.","pos":[7150,7287],"source":" For more information, see [Widening and Narrowing Conversions](../../language-features/data-types/widening-and-narrowing-conversions.md)."},{"pos":[7291,7605],"content":"[!NOTE]\nYou can use type inference only for arrays that are defined as local variables in a type member. If an explicit type definition is absent, arrays defined with array literals at the class level are of type `Object[]`. For more information, see [Local type inference](../variables/local-type-inference.md).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"You can use type inference only for arrays that are defined as local variables in a type member. If an explicit type definition is absent, arrays defined with array literals at the class level are of type `Object[]`. For more information, see [Local type inference](../variables/local-type-inference.md).","pos":[8,312],"nodes":[{"content":"You can use type inference only for arrays that are defined as local variables in a type member.","pos":[0,96]},{"content":"If an explicit type definition is absent, arrays defined with array literals at the class level are of type <ph id=\"ph1\">`Object[]`</ph>.","pos":[97,216],"source":" If an explicit type definition is absent, arrays defined with array literals at the class level are of type `Object[]`."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Local type inference<ept id=\"p1\">](../variables/local-type-inference.md)</ept>.","pos":[217,304],"source":" For more information, see [Local type inference](../variables/local-type-inference.md)."}]}]},{"content":"Note that the previous example defines <ph id=\"ph1\">`values`</ph> as an array of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`Double`</ph> even though all the array literals are of type <ph id=\"ph3\">`Integer`</ph>.","pos":[7607,7741],"source":"Note that the previous example defines `values` as an array of type `Double` even though all the array literals are of type `Integer`."},{"content":"You can create this array because the values in the array literal can widen to <ph id=\"ph1\">`Double`</ph> values.","pos":[7742,7837],"source":" You can create this array because the values in the array literal can widen to `Double` values."},{"content":"You can also create and populate a multidimensional array by using <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>nested array literals<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[7839,7930],"source":"You can also create and populate a multidimensional array by using *nested array literals*."},{"content":"Nested array literals must have a number of dimensions that’s consistent with the resulting array.","pos":[7931,8029]},{"content":"The following example creates a two-dimensional array of integers by using nested array literals.","pos":[8030,8127]},{"content":"When using nested array literals to create and populate an array, an error occurs if the number of elements in the nested array literals don't match.","pos":[8257,8406]},{"content":"An error also occurs if you explicitly declare the array variable to have a different number of dimensions than the array literals.","pos":[8407,8538]},{"content":"Just as you can for one-dimensional arrays, you can rely on type inference when creating a multidimensional array with nested array literals.","pos":[8540,8681]},{"content":"The inferred type is the dominant type for all the values in all the array literals for all nesting level.","pos":[8682,8788]},{"content":"The following example creates a two-dimensional array of type <ph id=\"ph1\">`Double[,]`</ph> from values that are of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`Integer`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">`Double`</ph>.","pos":[8789,8915],"source":" The following example creates a two-dimensional array of type `Double[,]` from values that are of type `Integer` and `Double`."},{"pos":[9045,9200],"content":"For additional examples, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md)</ept>.","source":"For additional examples, see [How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md)."},{"pos":[9205,9231],"content":"Iterating through an array","linkify":"Iterating through an array","nodes":[{"content":"Iterating through an array","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"When you iterate through an array, you access each element in the array from the lowest index to the highest or from the highest to the lowest.","pos":[9233,9376]},{"content":"Typically, use either the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>For...Next Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>For Each...Next Statement<ept id=\"p2\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md)</ept> to iterate through the elements of an array.","pos":[9377,9634],"source":" Typically, use either the [For...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) or the [For Each...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md) to iterate through the elements of an array."},{"content":"When you don't know the upper bounds of the array, you can call the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method to get the highest value of the index.","pos":[9635,9814],"source":" When you don't know the upper bounds of the array, you can call the <xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to get the highest value of the index."},{"content":"Although lowest index value is almost always 0, you can call the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.GetLowerBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method to get the lowest value of the index.","pos":[9815,9990],"source":" Although lowest index value is almost always 0, you can call the <xref:System.Array.GetLowerBound%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to get the lowest value of the index."},{"pos":[9992,10155],"content":"The following example iterates through a one-dimensional array by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`For...Next`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md)</ept> statement.","source":"The following example iterates through a one-dimensional array by using the [`For...Next`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement."},{"content":"The following example iterates through a multidimensional array by using a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`For...Next`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md)</ept> statement.","pos":[10288,10450],"source":"The following example iterates through a multidimensional array by using a [`For...Next`](../../../language-reference/statements/for-next-statement.md) statement."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A&gt;</ph> method has a parameter that specifies the dimension.","pos":[10451,10544],"source":" The <xref:System.Array.GetUpperBound%2A> method has a parameter that specifies the dimension."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`GetUpperBound(0)`</ph> returns the highest index of the first dimension, and <ph id=\"ph2\">`GetUpperBound(1)`</ph> returns the highest index of the second dimension.","pos":[10545,10687],"source":"`GetUpperBound(0)` returns the highest index of the first dimension, and `GetUpperBound(1)` returns the highest index of the second dimension."},{"pos":[10820,11014],"content":"The following example uses a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>For Each...Next Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md)</ept>to iterate through a one-dimensional array and a two-dimensional array.","source":"The following example uses a [For Each...Next Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/for-each-next-statement.md)to iterate through a one-dimensional array and a two-dimensional array."},{"pos":[11154,11164],"content":"Array size","linkify":"Array size","nodes":[{"content":"Array size","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"The size of an array is the product of the lengths of all its dimensions.","pos":[11166,11239]},{"content":"It represents the total number of elements currently contained in the array.","pos":[11240,11316]},{"content":"For example, the following example declares a 2-dimensional array with four elements in each dimension.","pos":[11318,11421]},{"content":"As the output from the example shows, the array's size is 16 (or (3 + 1) * (3 + 1).","pos":[11422,11505]},{"pos":[11622,11820],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis discussion of array size does not apply to jagged arrays. For information on jagged arrays and determining the size of a jagged array, see the [Jagged arrays](#jagged-arrays) section.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This discussion of array size does not apply to jagged arrays. For information on jagged arrays and determining the size of a jagged array, see the [Jagged arrays](#jagged-arrays) section.","pos":[8,196],"nodes":[{"content":"This discussion of array size does not apply to jagged arrays.","pos":[0,62]},{"content":"For information on jagged arrays and determining the size of a jagged array, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Jagged arrays<ept id=\"p1\">](#jagged-arrays)</ept> section.","pos":[63,188],"source":" For information on jagged arrays and determining the size of a jagged array, see the [Jagged arrays](#jagged-arrays) section."}]}]},{"content":"You can find the size of an array by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[11822,11937],"source":"You can find the size of an array by using the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property."},{"content":"You can find the length of each dimension of a multidimensional array by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[11938,12090],"source":" You can find the length of each dimension of a multidimensional array by using the <xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."},{"content":"You can resize an array variable by assigning a new array object to it or by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept> statement.","pos":[12092,12268],"source":"You can resize an array variable by assigning a new array object to it or by using the [`ReDim` Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement."},{"content":"The following example uses the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> statement to change a 100-element array to a 51-element array.","pos":[12269,12370],"source":" The following example uses the `ReDim` statement to change a 100-element array to a 51-element array."},{"content":"There are several things to keep in mind when dealing with the size of an array.","pos":[12491,12571]},{"content":"Dimension Length","pos":[12588,12604]},{"content":"The index of each dimension is 0-based, which means it ranges from 0 to its upper bound.","pos":[12605,12693]},{"content":"Therefore, the length of a given dimension is one greater than the declared upper bound of that dimension.","pos":[12694,12800]},{"content":"Length Limits","pos":[12803,12816]},{"content":"The length of every dimension of an array is limited to the maximum value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Integer`</ph> data type, which is <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Int32.MaxValue?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> or (2 ^ 31) - 1.","pos":[12817,13002],"source":"The length of every dimension of an array is limited to the maximum value of the `Integer` data type, which is <xref:System.Int32.MaxValue?displayProperty=nameWithType> or (2 ^ 31) - 1."},{"content":"However, the total size of an array is also limited by the memory available on your system.","pos":[13003,13094]},{"content":"If you attempt to initialize an array that exceeds the amount of available memory, the runtime throws an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.OutOfMemoryException&gt;</ph>.","pos":[13095,13235],"source":" If you attempt to initialize an array that exceeds the amount of available memory, the runtime throws an <xref:System.OutOfMemoryException>."},{"content":"Size and Element Size","pos":[13238,13259]},{"content":"An array's size is independent of the data type of its elements.","pos":[13260,13324]},{"content":"The size always represents the total number of elements, not the number of bytes that they consume in memory.","pos":[13325,13434]},{"content":"Memory Consumption","pos":[13437,13455]},{"content":"It is not safe to make any assumptions regarding how an array is stored in memory.","pos":[13456,13538]},{"content":"Storage varies on platforms of different data widths, so the same array can consume more memory on a 64-bit system than on a 32-bit system.","pos":[13539,13678]},{"content":"Depending on system configuration when you initialize an array, the common language runtime (CLR) can assign storage either to pack elements as close together as possible, or to align them all on natural hardware boundaries.","pos":[13679,13903]},{"content":"Also, an array requires a storage overhead for its control information, and this overhead increases with each added dimension.","pos":[13904,14030]},{"pos":[14036,14050],"content":"The array type","linkify":"The array type","nodes":[{"content":"The array type","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Every array has a data type, which differs from the data type of its elements.","pos":[14052,14130]},{"content":"There is no single data type for all arrays.","pos":[14131,14175]},{"content":"Instead, the data type of an array is determined by the number of dimensions, or <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>rank<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, of the array, and the data type of the elements in the array.","pos":[14176,14326],"source":" Instead, the data type of an array is determined by the number of dimensions, or *rank*, of the array, and the data type of the elements in the array."},{"content":"Two array variables are of the same data type only when they have the same rank and their elements have the same data type.","pos":[14327,14450]},{"content":"The lengths of the dimensions of an array do not influence the array data type.","pos":[14451,14530]},{"content":"Every array inherits from the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> class, and you can declare a variable to be of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`Array`</ph>, but you cannot create an array of type <ph id=\"ph3\">`Array`</ph>.","pos":[14532,14719],"source":"Every array inherits from the <xref:System.Array?displayProperty=nameWithType> class, and you can declare a variable to be of type `Array`, but you cannot create an array of type `Array`."},{"content":"For example, although the following code declares the <ph id=\"ph1\">`arr`</ph> variable to be of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`Array`</ph> and calls the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Array.CreateInstance%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method to instantiate the array, the array's type proves to be Object[].","pos":[14720,14964],"source":" For example, although the following code declares the `arr` variable to be of type `Array` and calls the <xref:System.Array.CreateInstance%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method to instantiate the array, the array's type proves to be Object[]."},{"content":"Also, the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ReDim Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept> cannot operate on a variable declared as type <ph id=\"ph1\">`Array`</ph>.","pos":[15081,15222],"source":"Also, the [ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) cannot operate on a variable declared as type `Array`."},{"content":"For these reasons, and for type safety, it is advisable to declare every array as a specific type.","pos":[15223,15321]},{"content":"You can find out the data type of either an array or its elements in several ways.","pos":[15323,15405]},{"content":"You can call the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Object.GetType%2A&gt;</ph> method on the variable to get a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Type&gt;</ph> object that represents the run-time type of the variable.","pos":[15409,15566],"source":"You can call the <xref:System.Object.GetType%2A> method on the variable to get a <xref:System.Type> object that represents the run-time type of the variable."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Type&gt;</ph> object holds extensive information in its properties and methods.","pos":[15567,15655],"source":" The <xref:System.Type> object holds extensive information in its properties and methods."},{"pos":[15658,15802],"content":"You can pass the variable to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.TypeName%2A&gt;</ph> function to get a <ph id=\"ph2\">`String`</ph> with the name of run-time type.","source":"You can pass the variable to the <xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.TypeName%2A> function to get a `String` with the name of run-time type."},{"content":"The following example calls the both the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetType`</ph> method and the <ph id=\"ph2\">`TypeName`</ph> function to determine the type of an array.","pos":[15804,15924],"source":"The following example calls the both the `GetType` method and the `TypeName` function to determine the type of an array."},{"content":"The array type is <ph id=\"ph1\">`Byte(,)`</ph>.","pos":[15925,15953],"source":" The array type is `Byte(,)`."},{"content":"Note that the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Type.BaseType%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> property also indicates that the base type of the byte array is the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Array&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[15954,16122],"source":" Note that the <xref:System.Type.BaseType%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property also indicates that the base type of the byte array is the <xref:System.Array> class."},{"pos":[16240,16278],"content":"Arrays as return values and parameters","linkify":"Arrays as return values and parameters","nodes":[{"content":"Arrays as return values and parameters","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"To return an array from a <ph id=\"ph1\">`Function`</ph> procedure, specify the array data type and the number of dimensions as the return type of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Function Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/function-statement.md)</ept>.","pos":[16280,16494],"source":"To return an array from a `Function` procedure, specify the array data type and the number of dimensions as the return type of the [Function Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/function-statement.md)."},{"content":"Within the function, declare a local array variable with same data type and number of dimensions.","pos":[16495,16592]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Return Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/return-statement.md)</ept>, include the local array variable without parentheses.","pos":[16593,16733],"source":" In the [Return Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/return-statement.md), include the local array variable without parentheses."},{"content":"To specify an array as a parameter to a <ph id=\"ph1\">`Sub`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`Function`</ph> procedure, define the parameter as an array with a specified data type and number of dimensions.","pos":[16735,16891],"source":"To specify an array as a parameter to a `Sub` or `Function` procedure, define the parameter as an array with a specified data type and number of dimensions."},{"content":"In the call to the procedure, pass an array variable with the same data type and number of dimensions.","pos":[16892,16994]},{"content":"In the following example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetNumbers`</ph> function returns an <ph id=\"ph2\">`Integer()`</ph>, a one-dimensional array of type <ph id=\"ph3\">`Integer`</ph>.","pos":[16996,17114],"source":"In the following example, the `GetNumbers` function returns an `Integer()`, a one-dimensional array of type `Integer`."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ShowNumbers`</ph> procedure accepts an <ph id=\"ph2\">`Integer()`</ph> argument.","pos":[17115,17175],"source":" The `ShowNumbers` procedure accepts an `Integer()` argument."},{"content":"In the following example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetNumbersMultiDim`</ph> function returns an <ph id=\"ph2\">`Integer(,)`</ph>, a two-dimensional array of type <ph id=\"ph3\">`Integer`</ph>.","pos":[17317,17444],"source":"In the following example, the `GetNumbersMultiDim` function returns an `Integer(,)`, a two-dimensional array of type `Integer`."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ShowNumbersMultiDim`</ph> procedure accepts an <ph id=\"ph2\">`Integer(,)`</ph> argument.","pos":[17446,17515],"source":"  The `ShowNumbersMultiDim` procedure accepts an `Integer(,)` argument."},{"pos":[17669,17682],"content":"Jagged arrays","linkify":"Jagged arrays","nodes":[{"content":"Jagged arrays","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Sometimes the data structure in your application is two-dimensional but not rectangular.","pos":[17684,17772]},{"content":"For example, you might use an array to store data about the high temperature of each day of the month.","pos":[17773,17875]},{"content":"The first dimension of the array represents the month, but the second dimension represents the number of days, and the number of days in a month is not uniform.","pos":[17876,18036]},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>jagged array<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, which is also called an <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>array of arrays<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>, is designed for such scenarios.","pos":[18037,18129],"source":" A *jagged array*, which is also called an *array of arrays*, is designed for such scenarios."},{"content":"A jagged array is an array whose elements are also arrays.","pos":[18130,18188]},{"content":"A jagged array and each element in a jagged array can have one or more dimensions.","pos":[18189,18271]},{"content":"The following example uses an array of months, each element of which is an array of days.","pos":[18273,18362]},{"content":"The example uses a jagged array because different months have different numbers of days.","pos":[18363,18451]},{"content":"The example shows how to create a jagged array, assign values to it, and retrieve and display its values.","pos":[18453,18558]},{"content":"The previous example assigns values to the jagged array on an element-by-element basis by using a <ph id=\"ph1\">`For...Next`</ph> loop.","pos":[18672,18788],"source":"The previous example assigns values to the jagged array on an element-by-element basis by using a `For...Next` loop."},{"content":"You can also assign values to the elements of a jagged array by using nested array literals.","pos":[18789,18881]},{"content":"However, the attempt to use nested array literals (for example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`Dim valuesjagged = {{1, 2}, {2, 3, 4}}`</ph>) generates compiler error <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>BC30568<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../,,/../misc/bc30568.md)</ept>.","pos":[18882,19055],"source":" However, the attempt to use nested array literals (for example, `Dim valuesjagged = {{1, 2}, {2, 3, 4}}`) generates compiler error [BC30568](../../../,,/../misc/bc30568.md)."},{"content":"To correct the error, enclose the inner array literals in parentheses.","pos":[19056,19126]},{"content":"The parentheses force the array literal expression to be evaluated, and the resulting values are used with the outer array literal, as the following example shows.","pos":[19127,19290]},{"content":"A jagged array is a one-dimensional array whose elements contain arrays.","pos":[19425,19497]},{"content":"Therefore, the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> property and the <ph id=\"ph2\">`Array.GetLength(0)`</ph> method return the number of elements in the one-dimensional array, and <ph id=\"ph3\">`Array.GetLength(1)`</ph> throws an <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.IndexOutOfRangeException&gt;</ph> because a jagged array is not multidimensional.","pos":[19498,19798],"source":" Therefore, the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property and the `Array.GetLength(0)` method return the number of elements in the one-dimensional array, and `Array.GetLength(1)` throws an <xref:System.IndexOutOfRangeException> because a jagged array is not multidimensional."},{"content":"You determine the number of elements in each subarray by retrieving the value of each subarray's <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[19799,19964],"source":" You determine the number of elements in each subarray by retrieving the value of each subarray's <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> property."},{"content":"The following example illustrates how to determine the number of elements in a jagged array.","pos":[19965,20057]},{"pos":[20185,20203],"content":"Zero-length arrays","linkify":"Zero-length arrays","nodes":[{"content":"Zero-length arrays","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Visual Basic differentiates between a uninitialized array (an array whose value is <ph id=\"ph1\">`Nothing`</ph>) and a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>zero-length array<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or empty array (an array that has no elements.) An uninitialized array is one that has not been dimensioned or had any values assigned to it.","pos":[20205,20466],"source":"Visual Basic differentiates between a uninitialized array (an array whose value is `Nothing`) and a *zero-length array* or empty array (an array that has no elements.) An uninitialized array is one that has not been dimensioned or had any values assigned to it."},{"content":"For example:","pos":[20467,20479]},{"content":"A zero-length array is declared with a dimension of -1.","pos":[20512,20567]},{"content":"For example:","pos":[20568,20580]},{"content":"You might need to create a zero-length array under the following circumstances:","pos":[20616,20695]},{"pos":[20699,20990],"content":"Without risking a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.NullReferenceException&gt;</ph> exception, your code must access members of the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Array&gt;</ph> class, such as <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Length%2A&gt;</ph> or <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Rank%2A&gt;</ph>, or call a Visual Basic function such as <ph id=\"ph5\">&lt;xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.UBound%2A&gt;</ph>.","source":"Without risking a <xref:System.NullReferenceException> exception, your code must access members of the <xref:System.Array> class, such as <xref:System.Array.Length%2A> or <xref:System.Array.Rank%2A>, or call a Visual Basic function such as <xref:Microsoft.VisualBasic.Information.UBound%2A>."},{"pos":[20994,21083],"content":"You want to keep your code simple by not having to check for <ph id=\"ph1\">`Nothing`</ph> as a special case.","source":"You want to keep your code simple by not having to check for `Nothing` as a special case."},{"content":"Your code interacts with an application programming interface (API) that either requires you to pass a zero-length array to one or more procedures or returns a zero-length array from one or more procedures.","pos":[21087,21293]},{"pos":[21298,21316],"content":"Splitting an array","linkify":"Splitting an array","nodes":[{"content":"Splitting an array","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"In some cases, you may need to split a single array into multiple arrays.","pos":[21318,21391]},{"content":"This involves identifying the point or points at which the array is to be split, and then spitting the array into two or more separate arrays.","pos":[21392,21534]},{"pos":[21538,21762],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis section does not discuss splitting a single string into a string array based on some delimiter. For information on splitting a string, see the <xref:System.String.Split%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not discuss splitting a single string into a string array based on some delimiter. For information on splitting a string, see the <xref:System.String.Split%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.","pos":[8,222],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not discuss splitting a single string into a string array based on some delimiter.","pos":[0,100]},{"content":"For information on splitting a string, see the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.String.Split%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[101,214],"source":" For information on splitting a string, see the <xref:System.String.Split%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."}]}]},{"content":"The most common criteria for splitting an array are:","pos":[21764,21816]},{"content":"The number of elements in the array.","pos":[21820,21856]},{"content":"For example, you might want to split an array of more than a specified number of elements into a number of approximately equal parts.","pos":[21857,21990]},{"content":"For this purpose, you can use the value returned by either the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[21991,22185],"source":" For this purpose, you can use the value returned by either the <xref:System.Array.Length%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> or <xref:System.Array.GetLength%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."},{"content":"The value of an element, which serves as a delimiter that indicates where the array should be split.","pos":[22189,22289]},{"content":"You can search for a specific value by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.FindIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Array.FindLastIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> methods.","pos":[22290,22481],"source":" You can search for a specific value by calling the <xref:System.Array.FindIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> and <xref:System.Array.FindLastIndex%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> methods."},{"pos":[22483,22684],"content":"Once you've determined the index or indexes at which the array should be split, you can then create the individual arrays by calling the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","source":"Once you've determined the index or indexes at which the array should be split, you can then create the individual arrays by calling the <xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."},{"content":"The following example splits an array into two arrays of approximately equal size.","pos":[22686,22768]},{"content":"(If the total number of array elements is odd, the first array has one more element than the second.)","pos":[22769,22870]},{"content":"The following example splits a string array into two arrays based on the presence of an element whose value is \"zzz\", which serves as the array delimiter.","pos":[22999,23153]},{"content":"The new arrays do not include the element that contains the delimiter.","pos":[23154,23224]},{"pos":[23359,23373],"content":"Joining arrays","linkify":"Joining arrays","nodes":[{"content":"Joining arrays","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"You can also combine a number of arrays into a single larger array.","pos":[23375,23442]},{"content":"To do this, you also use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[23443,23536],"source":" To do this, you also use the <xref:System.Array.Copy%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."},{"pos":[23540,23741],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis section does not discuss joining a string array into a single string. For information on joining a string array, see the <xref:System.String.Join%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not discuss joining a string array into a single string. For information on joining a string array, see the <xref:System.String.Join%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method.","pos":[8,199],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not discuss joining a string array into a single string.","pos":[0,74]},{"content":"For information on joining a string array, see the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.String.Join%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> method.","pos":[75,191],"source":" For information on joining a string array, see the <xref:System.String.Join%2A?displayProperty=nameWithType> method."}]}]},{"content":"Before copying the elements of each array into the new array, you must first ensure that you have initialized the array so that it is large enough to accommodate the new array.","pos":[23743,23919]},{"content":"You can do this in one of two ways:","pos":[23920,23955]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim Preserve`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept> statement to dynamically expand the array before adding new elements to it.","pos":[23959,24120],"source":"Use the [`ReDim Preserve`](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md) statement to dynamically expand the array before adding new elements to it."},{"content":"This is the easiest technique, but it can result in performance degradation and excessive memory consumption when you are copying large arrays.","pos":[24121,24264]},{"content":"Calculate the total number of elements needed for the new large array, then add the elements of each source array to it.","pos":[24267,24387]},{"content":"The following example uses the second approach to add four arrays with ten elements each to a single array.","pos":[24389,24496]},{"content":"Since in this case the source arrays are all small, we can also dynamically expand the array as we add the elements of each new array to it.","pos":[24611,24751]},{"content":"The following example does that.","pos":[24752,24784]},{"pos":[24915,24954],"content":"Collections as an alternative to arrays","linkify":"Collections as an alternative to arrays","nodes":[{"content":"Collections as an alternative to arrays","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"Arrays are most useful for creating and working with a fixed number of strongly typed objects.","pos":[24956,25050]},{"content":"Collections provide a more flexible way to work with groups of objects.","pos":[25051,25122]},{"content":"Unlike arrays, which require that you explicitly change the size of an array with the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept>, collections grow and shrink dynamically as the needs of an application change.","pos":[25123,25367],"source":" Unlike arrays, which require that you explicitly change the size of an array with the [`ReDim` Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md), collections grow and shrink dynamically as the needs of an application change."},{"content":"When you use <ph id=\"ph1\">`ReDim`</ph> to redimension an array, Visual Basic creates a new array and releases the previous one.","pos":[25369,25478],"source":"When you use `ReDim` to redimension an array, Visual Basic creates a new array and releases the previous one."},{"content":"This takes execution time.","pos":[25479,25505]},{"content":"Therefore, if the number of items you are working with changes frequently, or you cannot predict the maximum number of items you need, you'll usually obtain better performance by using a collection.","pos":[25506,25704]},{"content":"For some collections, you can assign a key to any object that you put into the collection so that you can quickly retrieve the object by using the key.","pos":[25706,25857]},{"content":"If your collection contains elements of only one data type, you can use one of the classes in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.Generic?displayProperty=nameWithType&gt;</ph> namespace.","pos":[25859,26030],"source":"If your collection contains elements of only one data type, you can use one of the classes in the <xref:System.Collections.Generic?displayProperty=nameWithType> namespace."},{"content":"A generic collection enforces type safety so that no other data type can be added to it.","pos":[26031,26119]},{"pos":[26121,26210],"content":"For more information about collections, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Collections<ept id=\"p1\">](../../concepts/collections.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information about collections, see [Collections](../../concepts/collections.md)."},{"pos":[26215,26229],"content":"Related topics","linkify":"Related topics","nodes":[{"content":"Related topics","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Term","pos":[26232,26236]},{"content":"Definition","pos":[26237,26247]},{"pos":[26280,26366],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Array Dimensions in Visual Basic<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md)</ept>","source":"[Array Dimensions in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/array-dimensions.md)"},{"content":"Explains rank and dimensions in arrays.","pos":[26367,26406]},{"pos":[26409,26534],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md)</ept>","source":"[How to: Initialize an Array Variable in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-initialize-an-array-variable.md)"},{"content":"Describes how to populate arrays with initial values.","pos":[26535,26588]},{"pos":[26591,26686],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Sort An Array in Visual Basic<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-sort-an-array.md)</ept>","source":"[How to: Sort An Array in Visual Basic](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-sort-an-array.md)"},{"content":"Shows how to sort the elements of an array alphabetically.","pos":[26687,26745]},{"pos":[26748,26867],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Assign One Array to Another Array<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-assign-one-array-to-another-array.md)</ept>","source":"[How to: Assign One Array to Another Array](../../language-features/arrays/how-to-assign-one-array-to-another-array.md)"},{"content":"Describes the rules and steps for assigning an array to another array variable.","pos":[26868,26947]},{"pos":[26950,27032],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Troubleshooting Arrays<ept id=\"p1\">](../../language-features/arrays/troubleshooting-arrays.md)</ept>","source":"[Troubleshooting Arrays](../../language-features/arrays/troubleshooting-arrays.md)"},{"content":"Discusses some common problems that arise when working with arrays.","pos":[27033,27100]},{"pos":[27106,27114],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[27169,27241],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dim Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/dim-statement.md)</ept>","source":"[Dim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/dim-statement.md)"},{"pos":[27244,27320],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ReDim Statement<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)</ept>","source":"[ReDim Statement](../../../language-reference/statements/redim-statement.md)"}]}