{"content":"---\ntitle: \"MSMQ Integration Transport | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-clr\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nms.assetid: 2bf9893a-fbd1-41fc-b6de-a41a44279936\ncaps.latest.revision: 5\nauthor: \"Erikre\"\nms.author: \"erikre\"\nmanager: \"erikre\"\n---\n# MSMQ Integration Transport\nThis topic lists all exceptions generated by the MSMQ Integration Transport.  \n  \n## Exception List  \n  \n|Resource Code|Resource String|  \n|-------------------|---------------------|  \n|MessageSizeMustBeInIntegerRange|This factory buffers messages, so the message sizes must be in the range of an integer value.|  \n|MsmqByteArrayBodyExpected|A mismatch occurred between the specified serialization format and the body of the MSMQ message. The message cannot be sent or received. The serialization format ByteArray requires the body of the MSMQ message to be of type byte[].|  \n|MsmqCannotDeserializeActiveXMessage|An ActiveX serialization error occurred. The message cannot be sent or received. The specified variant type for the body does not match the actual MSMQ message body.|  \n|MsmqCannotUseBodyTypeWithActiveXSerialization|The properties of the message are mismatched. The message cannot be sent or received. The BodyType message property cannot be specified if the ActiveX serialization format is used.|  \n|MsmqInvalidServiceOperationForMsmqIntegrationBinding|The MsmqIntegrationBinding validation failed. The service endpoint cannot be started. The specified binding does not support the method signature for the specified service operation in the specified contract. Correct the service operation to use the MsmqIntegrationBinding.|  \n|MsmqInvalidTypeDeserialization|The ActiveX serialization failed because the serialization format cannot be recognized. The message cannot be sent or received.|  \n|MsmqInvalidTypeSerialization|The variant type is not recognized. The ActiveX serialization failed. The message cannot be sent or received. The specified variant type is not supported.|  \n|MsmqStreamBodyExpected|Mismatch between serialization format and body content. Message cannot be sent or received. Only a body of type stream can be sent or received using the stream serialization mode.|","nodes":[{"pos":[12,55],"content":"MSMQ Integration Transport | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"MSMQ Integration Transport | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,43]}]},{"pos":[353,379],"content":"MSMQ Integration Transport","linkify":"MSMQ Integration Transport","nodes":[{"content":"MSMQ Integration Transport","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"This topic lists all exceptions generated by the MSMQ Integration Transport.","pos":[380,456]},{"pos":[465,479],"content":"Exception List","linkify":"Exception List","nodes":[{"content":"Exception List","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Resource Code","pos":[486,499]},{"content":"Resource String","pos":[500,515]},{"content":"MessageSizeMustBeInIntegerRange","pos":[566,597]},{"content":"This factory buffers messages, so the message sizes must be in the range of an integer value.","pos":[598,691]},{"content":"MsmqByteArrayBodyExpected","pos":[696,721]},{"content":"A mismatch occurred between the specified serialization format and the body of the MSMQ message.","pos":[722,818]},{"content":"The message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[819,858]},{"content":"The serialization format ByteArray requires the body of the MSMQ message to be of type byte[].","pos":[859,953]},{"content":"MsmqCannotDeserializeActiveXMessage","pos":[958,993]},{"content":"An ActiveX serialization error occurred.","pos":[994,1034]},{"content":"The message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[1035,1074]},{"content":"The specified variant type for the body does not match the actual MSMQ message body.","pos":[1075,1159]},{"content":"MsmqCannotUseBodyTypeWithActiveXSerialization","pos":[1164,1209]},{"content":"The properties of the message are mismatched.","pos":[1210,1255]},{"content":"The message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[1256,1295]},{"content":"The BodyType message property cannot be specified if the ActiveX serialization format is used.","pos":[1296,1390]},{"content":"MsmqInvalidServiceOperationForMsmqIntegrationBinding","pos":[1395,1447]},{"content":"The MsmqIntegrationBinding validation failed.","pos":[1448,1493]},{"content":"The service endpoint cannot be started.","pos":[1494,1533]},{"content":"The specified binding does not support the method signature for the specified service operation in the specified contract.","pos":[1534,1656]},{"content":"Correct the service operation to use the MsmqIntegrationBinding.","pos":[1657,1721]},{"content":"MsmqInvalidTypeDeserialization","pos":[1726,1756]},{"content":"The ActiveX serialization failed because the serialization format cannot be recognized.","pos":[1757,1844]},{"content":"The message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[1845,1884]},{"content":"MsmqInvalidTypeSerialization","pos":[1889,1917]},{"content":"The variant type is not recognized.","pos":[1918,1953]},{"content":"The ActiveX serialization failed.","pos":[1954,1987]},{"content":"The message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[1988,2027]},{"content":"The specified variant type is not supported.","pos":[2028,2072]},{"content":"MsmqStreamBodyExpected","pos":[2077,2099]},{"content":"Mismatch between serialization format and body content.","pos":[2100,2155]},{"content":"Message cannot be sent or received.","pos":[2156,2191]},{"content":"Only a body of type stream can be sent or received using the stream serialization mode.","pos":[2192,2279]}]}