{"content":"---\ntitle: .NET Core SDK Overview\ndescription: Find out about the .NET Core SDK, which is a set of libraries and tools used to create .NET Core projects.\nms.date: 06/20/2016\nms.technology: dotnet-cli\n---\n# .NET Core SDK Overview\n\n.NET Core Software Development Kit (SDK) is a set of libraries and tools that allow developers to create .NET Core applications\nand libraries. This is the package that developers will most likely acquire. \n\nIt contains the following components:\n\n1. The .NET Core Command Line Tools that are used to build applications\n2. .NET Core (libraries and runtime) that allow applications to both be built and run\n3. The `dotnet` driver for running the [CLI commands](tools/index.md) as well as running applications\n\n## Acquiring the .NET Core SDK\nAs with any tooling, the first thing is to get the tools to your machine. Depending on your scenario, you can either \nuse the native installers to install the SDK or use the installation shell script.\n\nThe native installers are primarily meant for developer's machines. The SDK is distributed using each supported platform's \nnative install mechanism, for instance DEB packages on Ubuntu or MSI bundles on Windows. These installers will install \nand set up the environment as needed for the user to use the SDK immediately after the install. However, they also \nrequire administrative privileges on the machine. You can view the installation instructions on the\n[.NET Core installation guide](https://aka.ms/dotnetcoregs).\n\nInstall scripts, on the other hand, do not require administrative privileges. However, they will also not install any \nprerequisites on the machine; you need to install all of the prerequisites manually. The scripts are meant mostly for \nsetting up build servers or when you wish to install the tools without admin privileges (do note the prerequisites \ncaveat above). You can find more information on the [install script reference topic](tools/dotnet-install-script.md). If you are \ninterested in how to set up SDK on your CI build server you can take a look at the [SDK with CI servers](tools/using-ci-with-cli.md) \ndocument.\n\nBy default, the SDK will install in a \"side-by-side\" (SxS) manner. This means that multiple versions of the CLI tools \ncan coexist at any given time on a single machine. How the correct version gets used is explained in more detail in \nthe [driver section](tools/index.md#driver) of .NET Core Command Line Tools topic.","nodes":[{"pos":[4,199],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: .NET Core SDK Overview\ndescription: Find out about the .NET Core SDK, which is a set of libraries and tools used to create .NET Core projects.\nms.date: 06/20/2016\nms.technology: dotnet-cli","nodes":[{"content":".NET Core SDK Overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,22],"content":".NET Core SDK Overview","nodes":[{"content":".NET Core SDK Overview","pos":[0,22]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false},{"content":"Find out about the .NET Core SDK, which is a set of libraries and tools used to create .NET Core projects.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,106],"content":"Find out about the .NET Core SDK, which is a set of libraries and tools used to create .NET Core projects.","nodes":[{"content":"Find out about the .NET Core SDK, which is a set of libraries and tools used to create .NET Core projects.","pos":[0,106]}]}],"path":["description"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[206,228],"content":".NET Core SDK Overview","linkify":".NET Core SDK Overview","nodes":[{"content":".NET Core SDK Overview","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":".NET Core Software Development Kit (SDK) is a set of libraries and tools that allow developers to create .NET Core applications and libraries.","pos":[230,372],"source":".NET Core Software Development Kit (SDK) is a set of libraries and tools that allow developers to create .NET Core applications\nand libraries."},{"content":"This is the package that developers will most likely acquire.","pos":[373,434]},{"content":"It contains the following components:","pos":[437,474]},{"content":"The .NET Core Command Line Tools that are used to build applications","pos":[479,547]},{"content":".NET Core (libraries and runtime) that allow applications to both be built and run","pos":[551,633]},{"pos":[637,735],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`dotnet`</ph> driver for running the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>CLI commands<ept id=\"p1\">](tools/index.md)</ept> as well as running applications","source":"The `dotnet` driver for running the [CLI commands](tools/index.md) as well as running applications"},{"pos":[740,767],"content":"Acquiring the .NET Core SDK","linkify":"Acquiring the .NET Core SDK","nodes":[{"content":"Acquiring the .NET Core SDK","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"As with any tooling, the first thing is to get the tools to your machine.","pos":[768,841]},{"content":"Depending on your scenario, you can either use the native installers to install the SDK or use the installation shell script.","pos":[842,968],"source":" Depending on your scenario, you can either \nuse the native installers to install the SDK or use the installation shell script."},{"content":"The native installers are primarily meant for developer's machines.","pos":[970,1037]},{"content":"The SDK is distributed using each supported platform's native install mechanism, for instance DEB packages on Ubuntu or MSI bundles on Windows.","pos":[1038,1182],"source":" The SDK is distributed using each supported platform's \nnative install mechanism, for instance DEB packages on Ubuntu or MSI bundles on Windows."},{"content":"These installers will install and set up the environment as needed for the user to use the SDK immediately after the install.","pos":[1183,1309],"source":" These installers will install \nand set up the environment as needed for the user to use the SDK immediately after the install."},{"content":"However, they also require administrative privileges on the machine.","pos":[1310,1379],"source":" However, they also \nrequire administrative privileges on the machine."},{"content":"You can view the installation instructions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>.NET Core installation guide<ept id=\"p1\">](https://aka.ms/dotnetcoregs)</ept>.","pos":[1380,1490],"source":" You can view the installation instructions on the\n[.NET Core installation guide](https://aka.ms/dotnetcoregs)."},{"content":"Install scripts, on the other hand, do not require administrative privileges.","pos":[1492,1569]},{"content":"However, they will also not install any prerequisites on the machine; you need to install all of the prerequisites manually.","pos":[1570,1695],"source":" However, they will also not install any \nprerequisites on the machine; you need to install all of the prerequisites manually."},{"content":"The scripts are meant mostly for setting up build servers or when you wish to install the tools without admin privileges (do note the prerequisites caveat above).","pos":[1696,1860],"source":" The scripts are meant mostly for \nsetting up build servers or when you wish to install the tools without admin privileges (do note the prerequisites \ncaveat above)."},{"content":"You can find more information on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>install script reference topic<ept id=\"p1\">](tools/dotnet-install-script.md)</ept>.","pos":[1861,1963],"source":" You can find more information on the [install script reference topic](tools/dotnet-install-script.md)."},{"content":"If you are interested in how to set up SDK on your CI build server you can take a look at the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SDK with CI servers<ept id=\"p1\">](tools/using-ci-with-cli.md)</ept> document.","pos":[1964,2119],"source":" If you are \ninterested in how to set up SDK on your CI build server you can take a look at the [SDK with CI servers](tools/using-ci-with-cli.md) \ndocument."},{"content":"By default, the SDK will install in a \"side-by-side\" (SxS) manner.","pos":[2121,2187]},{"content":"This means that multiple versions of the CLI tools can coexist at any given time on a single machine.","pos":[2188,2290],"source":" This means that multiple versions of the CLI tools \ncan coexist at any given time on a single machine."},{"content":"How the correct version gets used is explained in more detail in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>driver section<ept id=\"p1\">](tools/index.md#driver)</ept> of .NET Core Command Line Tools topic.","pos":[2291,2439],"source":" How the correct version gets used is explained in more detail in \nthe [driver section](tools/index.md#driver) of .NET Core Command Line Tools topic."}]}