{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL) | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-ado\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nms.assetid: c3133d53-83ed-4a4d-af8b-82edcf3831db\ncaps.latest.revision: 2\nauthor: \"JennieHubbard\"\nms.author: \"jhubbard\"\nmanager: \"jhubbard\"\n---\n# Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL)\nWhen you serialize entity objects such as Customers or Orders to a client over a network, those entities are detached from their data context. The data context no longer tracks their changes or their associations with other objects. This is not an issue as long as the clients are only reading the data. It is also relatively simple to enable clients to add new rows to a database. However, if your application requires that clients be able to update or delete data, then you must attach the entities to a new data context before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A?displayProperty=fullName>. In addition, if you are using an optimistic concurrency check with original values, then you will also need a way to provide the database both the original entity and the entity as modified. The `Attach` methods are provided to enable you to put entities into a new data context after they have been detached.  \n  \n Even if you are serializing proxy objects in place of the [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] entities, you still have to construct an entity on the data access layer (DAL), and attach it to a new <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext?displayProperty=fullName>, in order to submit the data to the database.  \n  \n [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] is completely indifferent about how entities are serialized. For more information about how to use the [!INCLUDE[vs_ordesigner_long](../../../../../../includes/vs-ordesigner-long-md.md)] and SQLMetal tools to generate classes that are serializable by using Windows Communication Foundation (WCF), see [How to: Make Entities Serializable](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-make-entities-serializable.md).  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Only call the `Attach` methods on new or deserialized entities. The only way for an entity to be detached from its original data context is for it to be serialized. If you try to attach an undetached entity to a new data context, and that entity still has deferred loaders from its previous data context, [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] will thrown an exception. An entity with deferred loaders from two different data contexts could cause unwanted results when you perform insert, update, and delete operations on that entity. For more information about deferred loaders, see [Deferred versus Immediate Loading](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/deferred-versus-immediate-loading.md).  \n  \n## Retrieving Data  \n  \n### Client Method Call  \n The following examples show a sample method call to the DAL from a Windows Forms client. In this example, the DAL is implemented as a Windows Service Library:  \n  \n```vb  \nPrivate Function GetProdsByCat_Click(ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e _  \n    As EventArgs)  \n  \n    ' Create the WCF client proxy.  \n    Dim proxy As New NorthwindServiceReference.Service1Client  \n  \n    ' Call the method on the service.  \n    Dim products As NorthwindServiceReference.Product() = _  \n        proxy.GetProductsByCategory(1)  \n  \n    ' If the database uses original values for concurrency checks,  \n    ' the client needs to store them and pass them back to the  \n    ' middle tier along with the new values when updating data.  \n  \n    For Each v As NorthwindClient1.NorthwindServiceReference.Product _  \n        In products  \n        ' Persist to a List(Of Product) declared at class scope.  \n        ' Additional change-tracking logic is the responsibility  \n        ' of the presentation tier and/or middle tier.  \n        originalProducts.Add(v)  \n    Next  \n  \n    ' (Not shown) Bind the products list to a control  \n    ' and/or perform whatever processing is necessary.  \nEnd Function  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \nprivate void GetProdsByCat_Click(object sender, EventArgs e)  \n{  \n    // Create the WCF client proxy.  \n    NorthwindServiceReference.Service1Client proxy =   \n    new NorthwindClient.NorthwindServiceReference.Service1Client();  \n  \n    // Call the method on the service.  \n    NorthwindServiceReference.Product[] products =   \n    proxy.GetProductsByCategory(1);  \n  \n    // If the database uses original values for concurrency checks,   \n    // the client needs to store them and pass them back to the   \n    // middle tier along with the new values when updating data.  \n    foreach (var v in products)  \n    {  \n        // Persist to a list<Product> declared at class scope.  \n        // Additional change-tracking logic is the responsibility  \n        // of the presentation tier and/or middle tier.  \n        originalProducts.Add(v);  \n    }  \n  \n    // (Not shown) Bind the products list to a control  \n    // and/or perform whatever processing is necessary.  \n    }  \n```  \n  \n### Middle Tier Implementation  \n The following example shows an implementation of the interface method on the middle tier. The following are the two main points to note:  \n  \n-   The <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> is declared at method scope.  \n  \n-   The method returns an <xref:System.Collections.IEnumerable> collection of the actual results. The serializer will execute the query to send the results back to the client/presentation tier. To access the query results locally on the middle tier, you can force execution by calling `ToList` or `ToArray` on the query variable. You can then return that list or array as an `IEnumerable`.  \n  \n```vb  \nPublic Function GetProductsByCategory(ByVal categoryID As Integer) _  \n    As IEnumerable(Of Product)  \n  \n    Dim db As New NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString)  \n    Dim productQuery = _  \n    From prod In db.Products _  \n    Where prod.CategoryID = categoryID _  \n    Select prod  \n  \n    Return productQuery.AsEnumerable()  \n  \nEnd Function  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \npublic IEnumerable<Product> GetProductsByCategory(int categoryID)  \n{  \n    NorthwindClasses1DataContext db =   \n    new NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString);  \n  \n    IEnumerable<Product> productQuery =  \n    from prod in db.Products  \n    where prod.CategoryID == categoryID  \n    select prod;  \n  \n    return productQuery.AsEnumerable();   \n}  \n```  \n  \n An instance of a data context should have a lifetime of one \"unit of work.\" In a loosely-coupled environment, a unit of work is typically small, perhaps one optimistic transaction, including a single call to `SubmitChanges`. Therefore, the data context is created and disposed at method scope. If the unit of work includes calls to business rules logic, then generally you will want to keep the `DataContext` instance for that whole operation. In any case, `DataContext` instances are not intended to be kept alive for long periods of time across arbitrary numbers of transactions.  \n  \n This method will return Product objects but not the collection of Order_Detail objects that are associated with each Product. Use the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataLoadOptions> object to change this default behavior. For more information, see [How to: Control How Much Related Data Is Retrieved](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-control-how-much-related-data-is-retrieved.md).  \n  \n## Inserting Data  \n To insert a new object, the presentation tier just calls the relevant method on the middle tier interface, and passes in the new object to insert. In some cases, it may be more efficient for the client to pass in only some values and have the middle tier construct the full object.  \n  \n### Middle Tier Implementation  \n On the middle tier, a new <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> is created, the object is attached to the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> by using the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A> method, and the object is inserted when <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A> is called. Exceptions, callbacks, and error conditions can be handled just as in any other Web service scenario.  \n  \n```vb  \n' No call to Attach is necessary for inserts.  \nPublic Sub InsertOrder(ByVal o As Order)  \n  \n    Dim db As New NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString)  \n    db.Orders.InsertOnSubmit(o)  \n  \n    ' Exception handling not shown.  \n    db.SubmitChanges()  \n  \nEnd Sub  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \n// No call to Attach is necessary for inserts.  \n    public void InsertOrder(Order o)  \n    {  \n        NorthwindClasses1DataContext db = new NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString);  \n        db.Orders.InsertOnSubmit(o);  \n  \n        // Exception handling not shown.  \n        db.SubmitChanges();  \n    }  \n```  \n  \n## Deleting Data  \n To delete an existing object from the database, the presentation tier calls the relevant method on the middle tier interface, and passes in its copy that includes original values of the object to be deleted.  \n  \n Delete operations involve optimistic concurrency checks, and the object to be deleted must first be attached to the new data context. In this example, the `Boolean` parameter is set to `false` to indicate that the object does not have a timestamp (RowVersion). If your database table does generate timestamps for each record, then concurrency checks are much simpler, especially for the client. Just pass in either the original or modified object and set the `Boolean` parameter to `true`. In any case, on the middle tier it is typically necessary to catch the <xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException>. For more information about how to handle optimistic concurrency conflicts, see [Optimistic Concurrency: Overview](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md).  \n  \n When deleting entities that have foreign key constraints on associated tables, you must first delete all the objects in its <xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601> collections.  \n  \n```vb  \n' Attach is necessary for deletes.  \nPublic Sub DeleteOrder(ByVal order As Order)  \n    Dim db As New NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString)  \n  \n    db.Orders.Attach(order, False)  \n    ' This will throw an exception if the order has order details.  \n    db.Orders.DeleteOnSubmit(order)  \n  \n    Try  \n        ' ConflictMode is an optional parameter.  \n        db.SubmitChanges(ConflictMode.ContinueOnConflict)  \n  \n    Catch ex As ChangeConflictException  \n        ' Get conflict information, and take actions  \n        ' that are appropriate for your application.  \n        ' See MSDN Article \"How to: Manage Change  \n        ' Conflicts (LINQ to SQL).  \n  \n    End Try  \nEnd Sub  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \n// Attach is necessary for deletes.  \npublic void DeleteOrder(Order order)  \n{  \n    NorthwindClasses1DataContext db = new NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString);  \n  \n    db.Orders.Attach(order, false);  \n    // This will throw an exception if the order has order details.  \n    db.Orders.DeleteOnSubmit(order);  \n    try  \n    {  \n        // ConflictMode is an optional parameter.  \n        db.SubmitChanges(ConflictMode.ContinueOnConflict);  \n    }  \n    catch (ChangeConflictException e)  \n    {  \n       // Get conflict information, and take actions  \n       // that are appropriate for your application.  \n       // See MSDN Article How to: Manage Change Conflicts (LINQ to SQL).  \n    }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n## Updating Data  \n [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] supports updates in these scenarios involving optimistic concurrency:  \n  \n-   Optimistic concurrency based on timestamps or RowVersion numbers.  \n  \n-   Optimistic concurrency based on original values of a subset of entity properties.  \n  \n-   Optimistic concurrency based on the complete original and modified entities.  \n  \n You can also perform updates or deletes on an entity together with its relations, for example a Customer and a collection of its associated Order objects. When you make modifications on the client to a graph of entity objects and their child (`EntitySet`) collections, and the optimistic concurrency checks require original values, the client must provide those original values for each entity and <xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601> object. If you want to enable clients to make a set of related updates, deletes, and insertions in a single method call, you must provide the client a way to indicate what type of operation to perform on each entity. On the middle tier, you then must call the appropriate <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A> method and then <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.InsertOnSubmit%2A>, <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.DeleteAllOnSubmit%2A>, or <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A> (without `Attach`, for insertions) for each entity before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A>. Do not retrieve data from the database as a way to obtain original values before you try updates.  \n  \n For more information about optimistic concurrency, see [Optimistic Concurrency: Overview](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md). For detailed information about resolving optimistic concurrency change conflicts, see [How to: Manage Change Conflicts](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-manage-change-conflicts.md).  \n  \n The following examples demonstrate each scenario:  \n  \n### Optimistic concurrency with timestamps  \n  \n```vb  \n' Assume that \"customer\" has been sent by client.  \n' Attach with \"true\" to say this is a modified entity  \n' and it can be checked for optimistic concurrency  \n' because it has a column that is marked with the  \n' \"RowVersion\" attribute.  \n  \ndb.Customers.Attach(customer, True)  \n  \nTry  \n    ' Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n    ' in call to SubmitChanges.  \n    db.SubmitChanges()  \nCatch ex As ChangeConflictException  \n    ' Handle conflict based on options provided.  \n    ' See MSDN article \"How to: Manage Change  \n    ' Conflicts (LINQ to SQL)\".  \nEnd Try  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \n// Assume that \"customer\" has been sent by client.  \n// Attach with \"true\" to say this is a modified entity  \n// and it can be checked for optimistic concurrency because  \n//  it has a column that is marked with \"RowVersion\" attribute  \ndb.Customers.Attach(customer, true)  \ntry  \n{  \n    // Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n    // in call to SubmitChanges.  \n    db.SubmitChanges();  \n}  \ncatch(ChangeConflictException e)  \n{  \n    // Handle conflict based on options provided  \n    // See MSDN article How to: Manage Change Conflicts (LINQ to SQL).  \n}  \n```  \n  \n### With Subset of Original Values  \n In this approach, the client returns the complete serialized object, together with the values to be modified.  \n  \n```vb  \nPublic Sub UpdateProductInventory(ByVal p As Product, ByVal _  \n    unitsInStock As Short?, ByVal unitsOnOrder As Short?)  \n  \n    Using db As New NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString)  \n        ' p is the original unmodified product  \n        ' that was obtained from the database.  \n        ' The client kept a copy and returns it now.  \n        db.Products.Attach(p, False)  \n  \n        ' Now that the original values are in the data context,  \n        ' apply the changes.  \n        p.UnitsInStock = unitsInStock  \n        p.UnitsOnOrder = unitsOnOrder  \n  \n        Try  \n            ' Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n            ' in call to SubmitChanges.  \n            db.SubmitChanges()  \n  \n        Catch ex As Exception  \n            ' Handle conflict based on options provided.  \n            ' See MSDN article \"How to: Manage Change Conflicts  \n            ' (LINQ to SQL)\".  \n        End Try  \n    End Using  \nEnd Sub  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \npublic void UpdateProductInventory(Product p, short? unitsInStock, short? unitsOnOrder)  \n{  \n    using (NorthwindClasses1DataContext db = new NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString))  \n    {  \n        // p is the original unmodified product  \n        // that was obtained from the database.  \n        // The client kept a copy and returns it now.  \n        db.Products.Attach(p, false);  \n  \n        // Now that the original values are in the data context, apply the changes.  \n        p.UnitsInStock = unitsInStock;  \n        p.UnitsOnOrder = unitsOnOrder;  \n        try  \n        {  \n             // Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n             // in call to SubmitChanges.  \n             db.SubmitChanges();  \n        }  \n        catch (ChangeConflictException e)  \n        {  \n            // Handle conflict based on provided options.  \n            // See MSDN article How to: Manage Change Conflicts  \n            // (LINQ to SQL).  \n        }  \n    }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n### With Complete Entities  \n  \n```vb  \nPublic Sub UpdateProductInfo(ByVal newProd As Product, ByVal _  \n    originalProd As Product)  \n  \n    Using db As New NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString)  \n        db.Products.Attach(newProd, originalProd)  \n  \n        Try  \n            ' Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n            ' in call to SubmitChanges.  \n            db.SubmitChanges()  \n  \n        Catch ex As Exception  \n            ' Handle potential change conflicgt in whatever way  \n            ' is appropriate for your application.  \n            ' For more information, see the MSDN article  \n            ' \"How to: Manage Change Conflicts (LINQ to  \n            ' SQL)\".  \n        End Try  \n  \n    End Using  \nEnd Sub  \n```  \n  \n```csharp  \npublic void UpdateProductInfo(Product newProd, Product originalProd)  \n{  \n     using (NorthwindClasses1DataContext db = new  \n        NorthwindClasses1DataContext(connectionString))  \n     {  \n         db.Products.Attach(newProd, originalProd);  \n         try  \n         {  \n               // Optional: Specify a ConflictMode value  \n               // in call to SubmitChanges.  \n               db.SubmitChanges();  \n         }  \n        catch (ChangeConflictException e)  \n        {  \n            // Handle potential change conflict in whatever way  \n            // is appropriate for your application.  \n            // For more information, see the MSDN article  \n            // How to: Manage Change Conflicts (LINQ to SQL)/  \n        }   \n    }  \n}  \n```  \n  \n To update a collection, call <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.AttachAll%2A> instead of `Attach`.  \n  \n### Expected Entity Members  \n As stated previously, only certain members of the entity object are required to be set before you call the `Attach` methods. Entity members that are required to be set must fulfill the following criteria:  \n  \n-   Be part of the entity’s identity.  \n  \n-   Be expected to be modified.  \n  \n-   Be a timestamp or have its <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A> attribute set to something besides `Never`.  \n  \n If a table uses a timestamp or version number for an optimistic concurrency check, you must set those members before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A>. A member is dedicated for optimistic concurrency checking when the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.IsVersion%2A> property is set to true on that Column attribute. Any requested updates will be submitted only if the version number or timestamp values are the same on the database.  \n  \n A member is also used in the optimistic concurrency check as long as the member does not have <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A> set to `Never`. The default value is `Always` if no other value is specified.  \n  \n If any one of these required members is missing, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException> is thrown during <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A> (\"Row not found or changed\").  \n  \n### State  \n After an entity object is attached to the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> instance, the object is considered to be in the `PossiblyModified` state. There are three ways to force an attached object to be considered `Modified`.  \n  \n1.  Attach it as unmodified, and then directly modify the fields.  \n  \n2.  Attach it with the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A> overload that takes current and original object instances. This supplies the change tracker with old and new values so that it will automatically know which fields have changed.  \n  \n3.  Attach it with the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A> overload that takes a second Boolean parameter (set to true). This will tell the change tracker to consider the object modified without having to supply any original values. In this approach, the object must have a version/timestamp field.  \n  \n For more information, see [Object States and Change-Tracking](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/object-states-and-change-tracking.md).  \n  \n If an entity object already occurs in the ID Cache with the same identity as the object being attached, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException> is thrown.  \n  \n When you attach with an `IEnumerable` set of objects, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException> is thrown when an already existing key is present. Remaining objects are not attached.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [N-Tier and Remote Applications with LINQ to SQL](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/n-tier-and-remote-applications-with-linq-to-sql.md)   \n [Background Information](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/background-information.md)","nodes":[{"pos":[4,401],"nodes":[{"content":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL) | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"pos":[0,87],"content":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL) | Microsoft Docs","nodes":[{"content":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL) | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,87]}]}],"pos":[6,96],"yaml":true}],"content":"title: \"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL) | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nms.prod: \".net-framework\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"dotnet-ado\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nms.assetid: c3133d53-83ed-4a4d-af8b-82edcf3831db\ncaps.latest.revision: 2\nauthor: \"JennieHubbard\"\nms.author: \"jhubbard\"\nmanager: \"jhubbard\"","yamlblock":true},{"pos":[408,478],"content":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL)","linkify":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL)","nodes":[{"content":"Data Retrieval and CUD Operations in N-Tier Applications (LINQ to SQL)","pos":[0,70]}]},{"content":"When you serialize entity objects such as Customers or Orders to a client over a network, those entities are detached from their data context.","pos":[479,621]},{"content":"The data context no longer tracks their changes or their associations with other objects.","pos":[622,711]},{"content":"This is not an issue as long as the clients are only reading the data.","pos":[712,782]},{"content":"It is also relatively simple to enable clients to add new rows to a database.","pos":[783,860]},{"content":"However, if your application requires that clients be able to update or delete data, then you must attach the entities to a new data context before you call <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>.","pos":[861,1096],"source":" However, if your application requires that clients be able to update or delete data, then you must attach the entities to a new data context before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A?displayProperty=fullName>."},{"content":"In addition, if you are using an optimistic concurrency check with original values, then you will also need a way to provide the database both the original entity and the entity as modified.","pos":[1097,1287]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Attach`</ph> methods are provided to enable you to put entities into a new data context after they have been detached.","pos":[1288,1406],"source":" The `Attach` methods are provided to enable you to put entities into a new data context after they have been detached."},{"pos":[1413,1748],"content":"Even if you are serializing proxy objects in place of the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)]</ph> entities, you still have to construct an entity on the data access layer (DAL), and attach it to a new <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph>, in order to submit the data to the database.","source":"Even if you are serializing proxy objects in place of the [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] entities, you still have to construct an entity on the data access layer (DAL), and attach it to a new <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext?displayProperty=fullName>, in order to submit the data to the database."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)]</ph> is completely indifferent about how entities are serialized.","pos":[1755,1883],"source":"[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] is completely indifferent about how entities are serialized."},{"content":"For more information about how to use the <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vs_ordesigner_long](../../../../../../includes/vs-ordesigner-long-md.md)]</ph> and SQLMetal tools to generate classes that are serializable by using Windows Communication Foundation (WCF), see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Make Entities Serializable<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-make-entities-serializable.md)</ept>.","pos":[1884,2253],"source":" For more information about how to use the [!INCLUDE[vs_ordesigner_long](../../../../../../includes/vs-ordesigner-long-md.md)] and SQLMetal tools to generate classes that are serializable by using Windows Communication Foundation (WCF), see [How to: Make Entities Serializable](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-make-entities-serializable.md)."},{"pos":[2261,3013],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Only call the `Attach` methods on new or deserialized entities. The only way for an entity to be detached from its original data context is for it to be serialized. If you try to attach an undetached entity to a new data context, and that entity still has deferred loaders from its previous data context, [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] will thrown an exception. An entity with deferred loaders from two different data contexts could cause unwanted results when you perform insert, update, and delete operations on that entity. For more information about deferred loaders, see [Deferred versus Immediate Loading](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/deferred-versus-immediate-loading.md).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Only call the `Attach` methods on new or deserialized entities. The only way for an entity to be detached from its original data context is for it to be serialized. If you try to attach an undetached entity to a new data context, and that entity still has deferred loaders from its previous data context, [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] will thrown an exception. An entity with deferred loaders from two different data contexts could cause unwanted results when you perform insert, update, and delete operations on that entity. For more information about deferred loaders, see [Deferred versus Immediate Loading](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/deferred-versus-immediate-loading.md).","pos":[9,750],"nodes":[{"content":"Only call the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Attach`</ph> methods on new or deserialized entities.","pos":[0,63],"source":"Only call the `Attach` methods on new or deserialized entities."},{"content":"The only way for an entity to be detached from its original data context is for it to be serialized.","pos":[64,164]},{"content":"If you try to attach an undetached entity to a new data context, and that entity still has deferred loaders from its previous data context, <ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)]</ph> will thrown an exception.","pos":[165,398],"source":" If you try to attach an undetached entity to a new data context, and that entity still has deferred loaders from its previous data context, [!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] will thrown an exception."},{"content":"An entity with deferred loaders from two different data contexts could cause unwanted results when you perform insert, update, and delete operations on that entity.","pos":[399,563]},{"content":"For more information about deferred loaders, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deferred versus Immediate Loading<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/deferred-versus-immediate-loading.md)</ept>.","pos":[564,741],"source":" For more information about deferred loaders, see [Deferred versus Immediate Loading](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/deferred-versus-immediate-loading.md)."}]}]},{"pos":[3022,3037],"content":"Retrieving Data","linkify":"Retrieving Data","nodes":[{"content":"Retrieving Data","pos":[0,15]}]},{"pos":[3047,3065],"content":"Client Method Call","linkify":"Client Method Call","nodes":[{"content":"Client Method Call","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"The following examples show a sample method call to the DAL from a Windows Forms client.","pos":[3069,3157]},{"content":"In this example, the DAL is implemented as a Windows Service Library:","pos":[3158,3227]},{"pos":[5263,5289],"content":"Middle Tier Implementation","linkify":"Middle Tier Implementation","nodes":[{"content":"Middle Tier Implementation","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"The following example shows an implementation of the interface method on the middle tier.","pos":[5293,5382]},{"content":"The following are the two main points to note:","pos":[5383,5429]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext&gt;</ph> is declared at method scope.","pos":[5439,5507],"source":"The <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> is declared at method scope."},{"content":"The method returns an <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.IEnumerable&gt;</ph> collection of the actual results.","pos":[5517,5610],"source":"The method returns an <xref:System.Collections.IEnumerable> collection of the actual results."},{"content":"The serializer will execute the query to send the results back to the client/presentation tier.","pos":[5611,5706]},{"content":"To access the query results locally on the middle tier, you can force execution by calling <ph id=\"ph1\">`ToList`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`ToArray`</ph> on the query variable.","pos":[5707,5842],"source":" To access the query results locally on the middle tier, you can force execution by calling `ToList` or `ToArray` on the query variable."},{"content":"You can then return that list or array as an <ph id=\"ph1\">`IEnumerable`</ph>.","pos":[5843,5902],"source":" You can then return that list or array as an `IEnumerable`."},{"content":"An instance of a data context should have a lifetime of one \"unit of work.\"","pos":[6662,6737]},{"content":"In a loosely-coupled environment, a unit of work is typically small, perhaps one optimistic transaction, including a single call to <ph id=\"ph1\">`SubmitChanges`</ph>.","pos":[6738,6886],"source":" In a loosely-coupled environment, a unit of work is typically small, perhaps one optimistic transaction, including a single call to `SubmitChanges`."},{"content":"Therefore, the data context is created and disposed at method scope.","pos":[6887,6955]},{"content":"If the unit of work includes calls to business rules logic, then generally you will want to keep the <ph id=\"ph1\">`DataContext`</ph> instance for that whole operation.","pos":[6956,7105],"source":" If the unit of work includes calls to business rules logic, then generally you will want to keep the `DataContext` instance for that whole operation."},{"content":"In any case, <ph id=\"ph1\">`DataContext`</ph> instances are not intended to be kept alive for long periods of time across arbitrary numbers of transactions.","pos":[7106,7243],"source":" In any case, `DataContext` instances are not intended to be kept alive for long periods of time across arbitrary numbers of transactions."},{"content":"This method will return Product objects but not the collection of Order_Detail objects that are associated with each Product.","pos":[7250,7375]},{"content":"Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataLoadOptions&gt;</ph> object to change this default behavior.","pos":[7376,7463],"source":" Use the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataLoadOptions> object to change this default behavior."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Control How Much Related Data Is Retrieved<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-control-how-much-related-data-is-retrieved.md)</ept>.","pos":[7464,7651],"source":" For more information, see [How to: Control How Much Related Data Is Retrieved](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-control-how-much-related-data-is-retrieved.md)."},{"pos":[7660,7674],"content":"Inserting Data","linkify":"Inserting Data","nodes":[{"content":"Inserting Data","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"To insert a new object, the presentation tier just calls the relevant method on the middle tier interface, and passes in the new object to insert.","pos":[7678,7824]},{"content":"In some cases, it may be more efficient for the client to pass in only some values and have the middle tier construct the full object.","pos":[7825,7959]},{"pos":[7969,7995],"content":"Middle Tier Implementation","linkify":"Middle Tier Implementation","nodes":[{"content":"Middle Tier Implementation","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"On the middle tier, a new <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext&gt;</ph> is created, the object is attached to the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext&gt;</ph> by using the <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A&gt;</ph> method, and the object is inserted when <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A&gt;</ph> is called.","pos":[7999,8307],"source":"On the middle tier, a new <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> is created, the object is attached to the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> by using the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A> method, and the object is inserted when <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A> is called."},{"content":"Exceptions, callbacks, and error conditions can be handled just as in any other Web service scenario.","pos":[8308,8409]},{"pos":[9045,9058],"content":"Deleting Data","linkify":"Deleting Data","nodes":[{"content":"Deleting Data","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"To delete an existing object from the database, the presentation tier calls the relevant method on the middle tier interface, and passes in its copy that includes original values of the object to be deleted.","pos":[9062,9269]},{"content":"Delete operations involve optimistic concurrency checks, and the object to be deleted must first be attached to the new data context.","pos":[9276,9409]},{"content":"In this example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Boolean`</ph> parameter is set to <ph id=\"ph2\">`false`</ph> to indicate that the object does not have a timestamp (RowVersion).","pos":[9410,9536],"source":" In this example, the `Boolean` parameter is set to `false` to indicate that the object does not have a timestamp (RowVersion)."},{"content":"If your database table does generate timestamps for each record, then concurrency checks are much simpler, especially for the client.","pos":[9537,9670]},{"content":"Just pass in either the original or modified object and set the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Boolean`</ph> parameter to <ph id=\"ph2\">`true`</ph>.","pos":[9671,9765],"source":" Just pass in either the original or modified object and set the `Boolean` parameter to `true`."},{"content":"In any case, on the middle tier it is typically necessary to catch the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException&gt;</ph>.","pos":[9766,9885],"source":" In any case, on the middle tier it is typically necessary to catch the <xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException>."},{"content":"For more information about how to handle optimistic concurrency conflicts, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optimistic Concurrency: Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[9886,10090],"source":" For more information about how to handle optimistic concurrency conflicts, see [Optimistic Concurrency: Overview](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md)."},{"content":"When deleting entities that have foreign key constraints on associated tables, you must first delete all the objects in its <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601&gt;</ph> collections.","pos":[10097,10271],"source":"When deleting entities that have foreign key constraints on associated tables, you must first delete all the objects in its <xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601> collections."},{"pos":[11719,11732],"content":"Updating Data","linkify":"Updating Data","nodes":[{"content":"Updating Data","pos":[0,13]}]},{"pos":[11736,11873],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)]</ph> supports updates in these scenarios involving optimistic concurrency:","source":"[!INCLUDE[vbtecdlinq](../../../../../../includes/vbtecdlinq-md.md)] supports updates in these scenarios involving optimistic concurrency:"},{"content":"Optimistic concurrency based on timestamps or RowVersion numbers.","pos":[11883,11948]},{"content":"Optimistic concurrency based on original values of a subset of entity properties.","pos":[11958,12039]},{"content":"Optimistic concurrency based on the complete original and modified entities.","pos":[12049,12125]},{"content":"You can also perform updates or deletes on an entity together with its relations, for example a Customer and a collection of its associated Order objects.","pos":[12132,12286]},{"content":"When you make modifications on the client to a graph of entity objects and their child (<ph id=\"ph1\">`EntitySet`</ph>) collections, and the optimistic concurrency checks require original values, the client must provide those original values for each entity and <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601&gt;</ph> object.","pos":[12287,12575],"source":" When you make modifications on the client to a graph of entity objects and their child (`EntitySet`) collections, and the optimistic concurrency checks require original values, the client must provide those original values for each entity and <xref:System.Data.Linq.EntitySet%601> object."},{"content":"If you want to enable clients to make a set of related updates, deletes, and insertions in a single method call, you must provide the client a way to indicate what type of operation to perform on each entity.","pos":[12576,12784]},{"content":"On the middle tier, you then must call the appropriate <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A&gt;</ph> method and then <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.InsertOnSubmit%2A&gt;</ph>, <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.DeleteAllOnSubmit%2A&gt;</ph>, or <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A&gt;</ph> (without <ph id=\"ph5\">`Attach`</ph>, for insertions) for each entity before you call <ph id=\"ph6\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[12785,13175],"source":" On the middle tier, you then must call the appropriate <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A> method and then <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.InsertOnSubmit%2A>, <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.DeleteAllOnSubmit%2A>, or <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.InsertOnSubmit%2A> (without `Attach`, for insertions) for each entity before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A>."},{"content":"Do not retrieve data from the database as a way to obtain original values before you try updates.","pos":[13176,13273]},{"content":"For more information about optimistic concurrency, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optimistic Concurrency: Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[13280,13460],"source":"For more information about optimistic concurrency, see [Optimistic Concurrency: Overview](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/optimistic-concurrency-overview.md)."},{"content":"For detailed information about resolving optimistic concurrency change conflicts, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Manage Change Conflicts<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-manage-change-conflicts.md)</ept>.","pos":[13461,13670],"source":" For detailed information about resolving optimistic concurrency change conflicts, see [How to: Manage Change Conflicts](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/how-to-manage-change-conflicts.md)."},{"content":"The following examples demonstrate each scenario:","pos":[13677,13726]},{"pos":[13736,13774],"content":"Optimistic concurrency with timestamps","linkify":"Optimistic concurrency with timestamps","nodes":[{"content":"Optimistic concurrency with timestamps","pos":[0,38]}]},{"pos":[14965,14995],"content":"With Subset of Original Values","linkify":"With Subset of Original Values","nodes":[{"content":"With Subset of Original Values","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"In this approach, the client returns the complete serialized object, together with the values to be modified.","pos":[14999,15108]},{"pos":[17087,17109],"content":"With Complete Entities","linkify":"With Complete Entities","nodes":[{"content":"With Complete Entities","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[18618,18711],"content":"To update a collection, call <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.AttachAll%2A&gt;</ph> instead of <ph id=\"ph2\">`Attach`</ph>.","source":"To update a collection, call <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.AttachAll%2A> instead of `Attach`."},{"pos":[18721,18744],"content":"Expected Entity Members","linkify":"Expected Entity Members","nodes":[{"content":"Expected Entity Members","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"As stated previously, only certain members of the entity object are required to be set before you call the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Attach`</ph> methods.","pos":[18748,18872],"source":"As stated previously, only certain members of the entity object are required to be set before you call the `Attach` methods."},{"content":"Entity members that are required to be set must fulfill the following criteria:","pos":[18873,18952]},{"content":"Be part of the entity’s identity.","pos":[18962,18995]},{"content":"Be expected to be modified.","pos":[19005,19032]},{"pos":[19042,19175],"content":"Be a timestamp or have its <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A&gt;</ph> attribute set to something besides <ph id=\"ph2\">`Never`</ph>.","source":"Be a timestamp or have its <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A> attribute set to something besides `Never`."},{"content":"If a table uses a timestamp or version number for an optimistic concurrency check, you must set those members before you call <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[19182,19349],"source":"If a table uses a timestamp or version number for an optimistic concurrency check, you must set those members before you call <xref:System.Data.Linq.ITable.Attach%2A>."},{"content":"A member is dedicated for optimistic concurrency checking when the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.IsVersion%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to true on that Column attribute.","pos":[19350,19527],"source":" A member is dedicated for optimistic concurrency checking when the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.IsVersion%2A> property is set to true on that Column attribute."},{"content":"Any requested updates will be submitted only if the version number or timestamp values are the same on the database.","pos":[19528,19644]},{"content":"A member is also used in the optimistic concurrency check as long as the member does not have <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A&gt;</ph> set to <ph id=\"ph2\">`Never`</ph>.","pos":[19651,19823],"source":"A member is also used in the optimistic concurrency check as long as the member does not have <xref:System.Data.Linq.Mapping.ColumnAttribute.UpdateCheck%2A> set to `Never`."},{"content":"The default value is <ph id=\"ph1\">`Always`</ph> if no other value is specified.","pos":[19824,19885],"source":" The default value is `Always` if no other value is specified."},{"content":"If any one of these required members is missing, a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException&gt;</ph> is thrown during <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A&gt;</ph> (\"Row not found or changed\").","pos":[19892,20090],"source":"If any one of these required members is missing, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.ChangeConflictException> is thrown during <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext.SubmitChanges%2A> (\"Row not found or changed\")."},{"pos":[20100,20105],"content":"State","linkify":"State","nodes":[{"content":"State","pos":[0,5]}]},{"content":"After an entity object is attached to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext&gt;</ph> instance, the object is considered to be in the <ph id=\"ph2\">`PossiblyModified`</ph> state.","pos":[20109,20260],"source":"After an entity object is attached to the <xref:System.Data.Linq.DataContext> instance, the object is considered to be in the `PossiblyModified` state."},{"content":"There are three ways to force an attached object to be considered <ph id=\"ph1\">`Modified`</ph>.","pos":[20261,20338],"source":" There are three ways to force an attached object to be considered `Modified`."},{"content":"Attach it as unmodified, and then directly modify the fields.","pos":[20348,20409]},{"content":"Attach it with the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A&gt;</ph> overload that takes current and original object instances.","pos":[20419,20540],"source":"Attach it with the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A> overload that takes current and original object instances."},{"content":"This supplies the change tracker with old and new values so that it will automatically know which fields have changed.","pos":[20541,20659]},{"content":"Attach it with the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A&gt;</ph> overload that takes a second Boolean parameter (set to true).","pos":[20669,20793],"source":"Attach it with the <xref:System.Data.Linq.Table%601.Attach%2A> overload that takes a second Boolean parameter (set to true)."},{"content":"This will tell the change tracker to consider the object modified without having to supply any original values.","pos":[20794,20905]},{"content":"In this approach, the object must have a version/timestamp field.","pos":[20906,20971]},{"pos":[20978,21132],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Object States and Change-Tracking<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/object-states-and-change-tracking.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Object States and Change-Tracking](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/object-states-and-change-tracking.md)."},{"content":"If an entity object already occurs in the ID Cache with the same identity as the object being attached, a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException&gt;</ph> is thrown.","pos":[21139,21301],"source":"If an entity object already occurs in the ID Cache with the same identity as the object being attached, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException> is thrown."},{"content":"When you attach with an <ph id=\"ph1\">`IEnumerable`</ph> set of objects, a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException&gt;</ph> is thrown when an already existing key is present.","pos":[21308,21460],"source":"When you attach with an `IEnumerable` set of objects, a <xref:System.Data.Linq.DuplicateKeyException> is thrown when an already existing key is present."},{"content":"Remaining objects are not attached.","pos":[21461,21496]},{"pos":[21505,21513],"content":"See Also","linkify":"See Also","nodes":[{"content":"See Also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>N-Tier and Remote Applications with LINQ to SQL<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/n-tier-and-remote-applications-with-linq-to-sql.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> </ph>","pos":[21517,21673],"source":"[N-Tier and Remote Applications with LINQ to SQL](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/n-tier-and-remote-applications-with-linq-to-sql.md) "},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Background Information<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/background-information.md)</ept>","pos":[21677,21782],"source":"[Background Information](../../../../../../docs/framework/data/adonet/sql/linq/background-information.md)"}]}