{"content":"---\ntitle: \"How to animate in a style (WPF)\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"animation [WPF], properties [WPF], within styles\"\n  - \"styles [WPF], animating properties within\"\nms.assetid: 6a791f3d-6b1f-4972-a2f9-35880bcfd954\n---\n# How to animate in a style\n\nThis example shows how to animate properties within a style. When animating within a style, only the framework element for which the style is defined can be targeted directly. To target a freezable object, you must \"dot down\" from a property of the styled element.\n\nIn the following example, several animations are defined within a style and applied to a <xref:System.Windows.Controls.Button>. When the user moves the mouse over the button, it fades from opaque to partially translucent and back again, repeatedly. When the user moves the mouse off the button, it becomes completely opaque. When the button is clicked, its background color changes from orange to white and back again. Because the <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> used to paint the button can't be targeted directly, it is accessed by dotting down from the button's <xref:System.Windows.Controls.Control.Background%2A> property.\n\n## Example\n\n[!code-xaml[timingbehaviors_snip#21](~/samples/snippets/csharp/VS_Snippets_Wpf/timingbehaviors_snip/CSharp/StyleStoryboardsExample.xaml#21)]\n\nNote that when animating within a style, it's possible to target objects that don't exist. For example, suppose your style uses a <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> to set a Button's background property, but at some point the style is overridden and the button's background is set with a <xref:System.Windows.Media.LinearGradientBrush>.  Trying to animate the <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> won't throw an exception; the animation will simply fail silently.\n\nFor more information about storyboard targeting syntax, see the [Storyboards Overview](storyboards-overview.md). For more information about animation, see the [Animation Overview](animation-overview.md). For more information about styles, see the [Styling and Templating](../controls/styling-and-templating.md).\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,240],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"How to animate in a style (WPF)\"\nms.date: \"03/30/2017\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"animation [WPF], properties [WPF], within styles\"\n  - \"styles [WPF], animating properties within\"\nms.assetid: 6a791f3d-6b1f-4972-a2f9-35880bcfd954","nodes":[{"content":"How to animate in a style (WPF)","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"How to animate in a style (WPF)","nodes":[{"content":"How to animate in a style (WPF)","pos":[0,31]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[247,272],"content":"How to animate in a style","linkify":"How to animate in a style","nodes":[{"content":"How to animate in a style","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This example shows how to animate properties within a style.","pos":[274,334]},{"content":"When animating within a style, only the framework element for which the style is defined can be targeted directly.","pos":[335,449]},{"content":"To target a freezable object, you must \"dot down\" from a property of the styled element.","pos":[450,538]},{"content":"In the following example, several animations are defined within a style and applied to a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Controls.Button&gt;</ph>.","pos":[540,667],"source":"In the following example, several animations are defined within a style and applied to a <xref:System.Windows.Controls.Button>."},{"content":"When the user moves the mouse over the button, it fades from opaque to partially translucent and back again, repeatedly.","pos":[668,788]},{"content":"When the user moves the mouse off the button, it becomes completely opaque.","pos":[789,864]},{"content":"When the button is clicked, its background color changes from orange to white and back again.","pos":[865,958]},{"content":"Because the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush&gt;</ph> used to paint the button can't be targeted directly, it is accessed by dotting down from the button's <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Controls.Control.Background%2A&gt;</ph> property.","pos":[959,1179],"source":" Because the <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> used to paint the button can't be targeted directly, it is accessed by dotting down from the button's <xref:System.Windows.Controls.Control.Background%2A> property."},{"pos":[1184,1191],"content":"Example","linkify":"Example","nodes":[{"content":"Example","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"Note that when animating within a style, it's possible to target objects that don't exist.","pos":[1335,1425]},{"content":"For example, suppose your style uses a <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush&gt;</ph> to set a Button's background property, but at some point the style is overridden and the button's background is set with a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Media.LinearGradientBrush&gt;</ph>.","pos":[1426,1680],"source":" For example, suppose your style uses a <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> to set a Button's background property, but at some point the style is overridden and the button's background is set with a <xref:System.Windows.Media.LinearGradientBrush>."},{"content":"Trying to animate the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush&gt;</ph> won't throw an exception; the animation will simply fail silently.","pos":[1682,1814],"source":"  Trying to animate the <xref:System.Windows.Media.SolidColorBrush> won't throw an exception; the animation will simply fail silently."},{"content":"For more information about storyboard targeting syntax, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Storyboards Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](storyboards-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[1816,1928],"source":"For more information about storyboard targeting syntax, see the [Storyboards Overview](storyboards-overview.md)."},{"content":"For more information about animation, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Animation Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](animation-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[1929,2019],"source":" For more information about animation, see the [Animation Overview](animation-overview.md)."},{"content":"For more information about styles, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Styling and Templating<ept id=\"p1\">](../controls/styling-and-templating.md)</ept>.","pos":[2020,2127],"source":" For more information about styles, see the [Styling and Templating](../controls/styling-and-templating.md)."}]}