{"content":"---\ntitle: Methods | C# Guide\ndescription: Overview of methods, method parameters, and method return values\nkeywords: .NET, .NET Core, C#\nauthor: rpetrusha\nms.author: ronpet\nms.date: 10/26/2016\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: .net\nms.technology: devlang-csharp\nms.devlang: csharp\nms.assetid: 577a8527-1081-4b36-9b9e-0685b6553c6e\n---\n# Methods #\n\nA method is a code block that contains a series of statements. A program causes the statements to be executed by calling the method and specifying any required method arguments. In C#, every executed instruction is performed in the context of a method. The `Main` method is the entry point for every C# application and it is called by the common language runtime (CLR) when the program is started.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> This topic discusses named methods. For information about anonymous functions, see [Anonymous Functions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb882516.aspx).\n\nThis topic contains the following sections:\n\n- [Method signatures](#signatures)\n- [Method invocation](#invocation)\n- [Inherited and overridden methods](#inherited)\n- [Passing parameters](#passing)\n  - [Passing parameters by value](#byval)\n  - [Passing parameters by reference](#byref)\n  - [Parameter arrays](#paramarray)\n- [Optional parameters and arguments](#optional)\n- [Return values](#return)\n- [Extension methods](#extension)\n- [Async Methods](#async)\n- [Expression-bodied members](#expr)\n- [Iterators](#iterators)\n\n<a name=\"signatures\"></a>\n## Method signatures ##\n\nMethods are declared in a `class` or `struct` by specifying:\n\n- An optional access level, such as `public` or `private`. The default is `private`.\n- Optional modifiers such as `abstract` or `sealed`.\n- The return value, or `void` if the method has none.\n- The method name.\n- Any method parameters. Method parameters are enclosed in parentheses and are separated by commas. Empty parentheses indicate that the method requires no parameters.\n\nThese parts together form the method signature.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> A return type of a method is not part of the signature of the method for the purposes of method overloading. However, it is part of the signature of the method when determining the compatibility between a delegate and the method that it points to.\n\nThe following example defines a class named `Motorcycle` that contains five methods:\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#40](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#40)]\n\nNote that the `Motorcycle` class includes an overloaded method, `Drive`. Two methods have the same name, but must be differentiated by their parameter types.\n\n<a name=\"invocation\"></a>\n## Method invocation ##\n\nMethods can be either *instance* or *static*. Invoking an instance method requires that you instantiate an object and call the method on that object; an instance method operates on that instance and its data. You invoke a static method by referencing the name of the type to which the method belongs; static methods operate do not operate on instance data. Attempting to call a static method through an object instance generates a compiler error.\n\nCalling a method is like accessing a field. After the object name (if you are calling an instance method) or the type name (if you are calling a `static` method), add a period, the name of the method, and parentheses. Arguments are listed within the parentheses, and are separated by commas.\n\nThe method definition specifies the names and types of any parameters that are required. When a caller invokes the method, it provides concrete values, called arguments, for each parameter. The arguments must be compatible with the parameter type, but the argument name, if one is used in the calling code, does not have to be the same as the parameter named defined in the method. In the following example, the `Square` method includes a single parameter of type `int` named *i*. The first method call passes the `Square` method a variable of type `int` named *num*; the second, a numeric constant; and the third, an expression.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#74](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/params74.cs#74)]\n\nThe most common form of method invocation used positional arguments; it supplies arguments in the same order as method parameters. The methods of the `Motorcycle` class can therefore be called as in the following example. The call to the `Drive` method, for example, includes two arguments that correspond to the two parameters in the method's syntax. The first becomes the value of the `miles` parameter, the second the value of the `speed` parameter.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#41](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#41)]\n\nYou can also used *named arguments* instead of positional arguments when invoking a method. When using named arguments, you specify the parameter name followed by a colon (\":\") and the argument. Arguments to the method can appear in any order, as long as all required arguments are present. The following example uses named arguments to invoke the `TestMotorcycle.Drive` method. In this example, the named arguments are passed in the opposite order from the method's parameter list.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#45](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named1.cs#45)]\n\nYou can invoke a method using both positional arguments and named arguments. However, a positional argument cannot follow a named argument. The following example invokes the `TestMotorcycle.Drive` method from the previous example using one positional argument and one named argument.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#46](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named2.cs#46)]\n\n <a name=\"inherited\"></a>\n ##Inherited and overridden methods ##\n\nIn addition to the members that are explicitly defined in a type, a type inherits members defined in its base classes. Since all types in the managed type system inherit directly or indirectly from the @System.Object class, all types inherit its members, such as @System.Object.Equals(System.Object), @System.Object.GetType, and @System.Object.ToString. The following example defines a `Person` class, instantiates two `Person` objects, and calls the `Person.Equals` method to determine whether the two objects are equal. The `Equals` method, however, is not defined in the `Person` class; it is inherited from @System.Object.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#104](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/inherited1.cs#104)]\n\nTypes can override inherited members by using the `override` keyword and providing an implementation for the overridden method. The method signature must be the same as that of the overriden method. The following example is like the previous one, except that it overrides the @Object.Equals(System.Object) method. (It also overrides the @Object.GetHashCode method, since the two methods are intended to provide consistent results.)\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#105](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/overridden1.cs#105)]\n\n<a name=\"passing\"></a>\n## Passing parameters ##\n\nTypes in C# are either *value types* or *reference types*. For a list of built-in value types, see [Types and variables](./tour-of-csharp/types-and-variables.md). By default, both value types and reference types are passed to a method by value.\n\n<a name=\"byval\"></a>\n### Passing parameters by value ###\n\nWhen a value type is passed to a method by value, a copy of the object instead of the object itself is passed to the method. Therefore, changes to the object in the called method have no effect on the original object when control returns to the caller.\n\nThe following example passes a value type to a method by value, and the called method attempts to change the value type's value. It defines a variable of type `int`, which is a value type, initializes its value to 20, and passes it to a method named `ModifyValue` that changes the variable's value to 30. When the method returns, however, the variable's value remains unchanged.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#10](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue10.cs#10)]\n\nWhen an object of a reference type is passed to a method by value, a reference to the object is passed by value. That is, the method receives not the object itself, but an argument that indicates the location of the object. If you change a member of the object by using this reference, the change is reflected in the object when control returns to the calling method. However, replacing the object passed to the method has no effect on the original object when control returns to the caller.\n\nThe following example defines a class (which is a reference type) named `SampleRefType`. It instantiates a `SampleRefType` object, assigns 44 to its `value` field, and passes the object to the `ModifyObject` method. This example does essentially the same thing as the previous example -- it passes an argument by value to a method. But because a reference type is used, the result is different. The modification that is made in `ModifyObject` to the `obj.value` field also changes the `value` field of the argument, `rt`, in the `Main` method to 33, as the output from the example shows.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#42](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue42.cs#42)]\n\n<a name=\"byref\"></a>\n### Passing parameters by reference ###\n\nYou pass a parameter by reference when you want to change the value of an argument in a method and want to refect that change when control returns to the calling method. To pass a parameter by reference, you use the `ref` or `out` keyword.\n\nThe following example is identical to the previous one, except the value is passed by reference to the `ModifyValue` method. When the value of the parameter is modified in the `ModifyValue` method, the change in value is reflected when control returns to the caller.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref106.cs#106)]\n\nA common pattern that uses by ref parameters involves swapping the values of variables. You pass two variables to a method by reference, and the method swaps their contents. The following example swaps integer values.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/swap107.cs#107)]\n\nPassing a reference-type parameter allows you to change the value of the reference itself, rather than the value of its individual elements or fields.\n\n<a name=\"paramarray\"></a>\n### Parameter arrays ###\n\nSometimes, the requirement that you specify the exact number of arguments to your method is restrictive. By using the `params` keyword to indicate that a parameter is a parameter array, you allow your method to be called with a variable number of arguments. The parameter tagged with the `params` keyword must must be an array type, and it must be the last parameter in the method's parameter list.\n\nA caller can then invoke the method in either of three ways:\n\n- By passing an array of the appropriate type that contains the desired number of elements.\n- By passing a comma-separated list of individual arguments of the appropriate type to the method.\n- By not providing an argument to the parameter array.\n\nThe following example defines a method named `DoStringOperation` that performs the string operation specified by its first parameter, a `StringOperation` enumeration member. The strings upon which it is to perform the operation are defined by a parameter array. The `Main` method illustrates all three ways of invoking the method. Note that the method tagged with the `params` keyword must be prepared to handle the case in which no argument is supplied for the parameter array, so that its value is `null`.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref108.cs#108)]\n\n<a name=\"optional\"></a>\n## Optional parameters and arguments ##\n\nA method definition can specify that its parameters are required or that they are optional. By default, parameters are required. Optional parameters are specified by including the parameter's default value in the method definition. When the method is called, if no argument is supplied for an optional parameter, the default value is used instead.\n\nThe parameter's default value must be assigned by one of the following kinds of expressions:\n\n- A constant, such as a literal string or number.\n- An expression of the form `new ValType`, where `ValType` is a value type. Note that this invokes the value type's implicit default constructor, which is not an actual member of the type.\n- An expression of the form `default(ValType)`, where `ValType` is a value type.\n\nIf a method includes both required and optional parameters, optional parameters are defined at the end of the parameter list, after all required parameters.\n\nThe following example defines a method, `ExampleMethod`, that has one required and two optional parameters.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#21](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#21)]\n\nIf a method with multiple optional arguments is invoked using positional arguments, the caller must supply an argument for all optional parameters from the first one to the last one for which an argument is supplied. In the case of the  `ExampleMethod` method, for example, if the caller supplies an argument for the `description` parameter, it must also supply one for the `optionalInt` parameter. `opt.ExampleMethod(2, 2, \"Addition of 2 and 2\");` is a valid method call; `opt.ExampleMethod(2, , \"Addition of 2 and 0);` generates an \"Argument missing\" compiler error.\n\nIf a method is called using named arguments or a combination of positional and named arguments, the caller can omit any arguments that follow the last positional argument in the method call.\n\nThe following example calls the `ExampleMethod` method three times.  The first two method calls use positional arguments. The first omits both optional arguments, while the second omits the last argument. The third method call supplies a positional argument for the required parameter, but uses a named argument to supply a value to the `description` parameter while omitting the `optionalInt` argument.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#22](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#22)]\n\nThe use of optional parameters affects *overload resolution*, or the way in which the C# compiler determines which particular overload should be invoked by a method call, as follows:\n\n- A method, indexer, or constructor is a candidate for execution if each of its parameters either is optional or corresponds, by name or by position, to a single argument in the calling statement, and that argument can be converted to the type of the parameter.\n- If more than one candidate is found, overload resolution rules for preferred conversions are applied to the arguments that are explicitly specified. Omitted arguments for optional parameters are ignored.\n- If two candidates are judged to be equally good, preference goes to a candidate that does not have optional parameters for which arguments were omitted in the call. This is a consequence of a general preference in overload resolution for candidates that have fewer parameters.\n\n <a name=\"return\"></a>\n ## Return values ##\n\nMethods can return a value to the caller. If the return type (the type listed before the method name) is not `void`, the method can return the value by using the `return` keyword. A statement with the `return` keyword followed by a variable, constant, or expression that matches the return type will return that value to the method caller. Methods with a non-void return type are required to use the `return` keyword to return a value. The `return` keyword also stops the execution of the method.\n\nIf the return type is `void`, a `return` statement without a value is still useful to stop the execution of the method. Without the `return` keyword, the method will stop executing when it reaches the end of the code block.\n\nFor example, these two methods use the `return` keyword to return integers:\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#44](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#44)]\n\nTo use a value returned from a method, the calling method can use the method call itself anywhere a value of the same type would be sufficient. You can also assign the return value to a variable. For example, the following two code examples accomplish the same goal:\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#45](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#45)]\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#46](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#46)]\n\nUsing a local variable, in this case, `result`, to store a value is optional. It may help the readability of the code, or it may be necessary if you need to store the original value of the argument for the entire scope of the method.\n\nSometimes, you want your method to return more than a single value. Starting with C# 7.0, you can do this easily by using *tuple types* and *tuple literals*. The tuple type defines the data types of the tuple's elements. Tuple literals provide the actual values of the returned tuple. In teh following example, `(string, string, string, int)` defines the tuple type that is returned by the `GetPersonalInfo` method. The expression `(per.FirstName, per.MiddleName, per.LastName, per.Age)` is the tuple literal; the method returns the first, middle, and last name, along with the age, of a `PersonInfo` object.\n\n```csharp\npublic (string, string, string, int) GetPersonalInfo(string id)\n{\n    PersonInfo per = PersonInfo.RetrieveInfoById(id);\n    if (per != null)\n       return (per.FirstName, per.MiddleName, per.LastName, per.Age);\n    else\n       return null;\n}\n```\n\nThe caller can then consume the returned tuple with code like the following:\n\n```csharp\nvar person = GetPersonalInfo(\"111111111\")\nif (person != null)\n   Console.WriteLine(\"{person.Item1} {person.Item3}: age = {person.Item4}\");\n```\n\nNames can also be assigned to the tuple elements in the tuple type definition. The following example shows an alternate version of the `GetPersonalInfo` method that uses named elements:\n\n```csharp\npublic (string FName, string MName, string LName, int Age) GetPersonalInfo(string id)\n{\n    PersonInfo per = PersonInfo.RetrieveInfoById(id);\n    if (per != null)\n       return (per.FirstName, per.MiddleName, per.LastName, per.Age);\n    else\n       return null;\n}\n```\n\nThe previous call to the `GetPersonInfo` method can then be modified as follows:\n\n```csharp\nvar person = GetPersonalInfo(\"111111111\");\nif (person != null)\n   Console.WriteLine(\"{person.FName} {person.LName}: age = {person.Age}\");\n```\n\nIf a method is passed an array as an argument and modifies the value of individual elements, it is not necessary for the method to return the array, although you may choose to do so for good style or functional flow of values.  This is because C# passes all reference types by value, and the value of an array reference is the pointer to the array. In the following example, changes to the contents of the `values` array that are made in the `DoubleValues` method are observable by any code that has a reference to the array.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#101](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/returnarray1.cs#101)]\n\n <a name=\"exten\"></a>\n ## Extension methods ##\n\nOrdinarily, there are two ways to add a method to an existing type:\n\n- Modify the source code for that type. You cannot do this, of course, if you do not own the type's source code. And this becomes a breaking change if you also add any private data fields to support the method.\n- Define the new method in a derived class. A method cannot be added in this way using inheritance for other types, such as structures and enumerations. Nor can it be used to \"add\" a method to a sealed class.\n\nExtension methods let you \"add\" a method to an existing type without modifying the type itself or implementing the new method in an inherited type. The extension method also does not have to reside in the same assembly as the type it extends. You call an extension method as if it were a defined member of a type.\n\nFor more information, see [Extension Methods](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb383977.aspx).\n\n<a name=\"async\"></a>\n## Async Methods ##\n\nBy using the async feature, you can invoke asynchronous methods without using explicit callbacks or manually splitting your code across multiple methods or lambda expressions.\n\nIf you mark a method with the [async](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156513.aspx) modifier, you can use the [await](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156528.aspx) operator in the method. When control reaches an `await` expression in the async method, control returns to the caller if the awaited task is not completed, and progress in the method with the `await` keyword is suspended until the awaited task completes. When the task is complete, execution can resume in the method.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> An async method returns to the caller when either it encounters the first awaited object that’s not yet complete or it gets to the end of the async method, whichever occurs first.\n\nAn async method can have a return type of @System.Threading.Tasks.Task<TResult>, @System.Threading.Tasks.Task, or `void`. The `void` return type is used primarily to define event handlers, where a `void` return type is required. An async method that returns `void` can't be awaited, and the caller of a void-returning method can't catch exceptions that the method throws. C# 7, when it is released, will ease this restriction to allow an async method [to return any task-like type](https://github.com/ljw1004/roslyn/blob/features/async-return/docs/specs/feature%20-%20arbitrary%20async%20returns.md).\n\nIn the following example, `DelayAsync` is an async method that has a return statement that returns an integer. Because it is an async method, its method declaration must have a return type of `Task<int>`. Because the return type is `Task<int>`, the evaluation of the `await` expression in `DoSomethingAsync` produces an integer, as the following `int result = await delayTask` statement demonstrates.\n\n[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#102](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/async1.cs#102)]\n\nAn async method can't declare any [ref](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx) or [out](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx) parameters, but it can call methods that have such parameters.\n\n For more information about async methods, see [Asynchronous Programming with Async and Await](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674882.aspx), [Control Flow in Async Programs](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674892.aspx), and [Async Return Types](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674893.aspx).\n\n<a name=\"expr\"></a>\n## Expression-bodied members ##\n\nIt is common to have method definitions that simply return immediately with the result of an expression, or that have a single statement as the body of the method.  There is a syntax shortcut for defining such methods using `=>`:\n\n```csharp\n\npublic Point Move(int dx, int dy) => new Point(x + dx, y + dy);\npublic void Print() => Console.WriteLine(First + \" \" + Last);\n// Works with operators, properties, and indexers too.\npublic static Complex operator +(Complex a, Complex b) => a.Add(b);\npublic string Name => First + \" \" + Last;\npublic Customer this[long id] => store.LookupCustomer(id);\n\n```\n\nIf the method returns `void` or is an async method, the body of the method must be a statement expression (same as with lambdas).  For properties and indexers, they must be read-only, and you do not use the `get` accessor keyword.\n\n<a name=\"iterators\"></a>\n## Iterators ##\n\nAn iterator performs a custom iteration over a collection, such as a list or an array. An iterator uses the [yield return](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/9k7k7cf0.aspx) statement to return each element one at a time. When a `yield return` statement is reached, the current location is remembered so that the caller can request the next element in the sequence.\n\nThe return type of an iterator can be @System.Collections.IEnumerable, @System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable%601, @System.Collections.IEnumerator, or @System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerator%601.\n\nFor more information, see [Iterators](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt639331.aspx).\n\n## See also ##\n\n[Access Modifiers](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/wxh6fsc7.aspx)\n[Static Classes and Static Class Members](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/79b3xss3.aspx)\n[Inheritance](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173149.aspx)\n[Abstract and Sealed Classes and Class Members](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173150.aspx)\n[params](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/w5zay9db.aspx)\n[out](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx)\n[ref](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx)\n[Passing Parameters](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/0f66670z.aspx)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[11,29],"content":"Methods | C# Guide","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Methods | C# Guide","pos":[0,18]}]},{"pos":[43,107],"content":"Overview of methods, method parameters, and method return values","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Overview of methods, method parameters, and method return values","pos":[0,64]}]},{"pos":[118,137],"content":".NET, .NET Core, C#","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":".NET, .NET Core, C#","pos":[0,19]}]},{"pos":[330,337],"content":"Methods","linkify":"Methods","nodes":[{"content":"Methods","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"A method is a code block that contains a series of statements.","pos":[341,403]},{"content":"A program causes the statements to be executed by calling the method and specifying any required method arguments.","pos":[404,518]},{"content":"In C#, every executed instruction is performed in the context of a method.","pos":[519,593]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Main`</ph> method is the entry point for every C# application and it is called by the common language runtime (CLR) when the program is started.","pos":[594,738],"source":" The `Main` method is the entry point for every C# application and it is called by the common language runtime (CLR) when the program is started."},{"pos":[742,907],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis topic discusses named methods. For information about anonymous functions, see [Anonymous Functions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb882516.aspx).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic discusses named methods. For information about anonymous functions, see [Anonymous Functions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb882516.aspx).","pos":[8,163],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic discusses named methods.","pos":[0,35]},{"content":"For information about anonymous functions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Anonymous Functions<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb882516.aspx)</ept>.","pos":[36,155],"source":" For information about anonymous functions, see [Anonymous Functions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb882516.aspx)."}]}]},{"content":"This topic contains the following sections:","pos":[909,952]},{"pos":[956,988],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Method signatures<ept id=\"p1\">](#signatures)</ept>","source":"[Method signatures](#signatures)"},{"pos":[991,1023],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Method invocation<ept id=\"p1\">](#invocation)</ept>","source":"[Method invocation](#invocation)"},{"pos":[1026,1072],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Inherited and overridden methods<ept id=\"p1\">](#inherited)</ept>","source":"[Inherited and overridden methods](#inherited)"},{"pos":[1075,1105],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Passing parameters<ept id=\"p1\">](#passing)</ept>","source":"[Passing parameters](#passing)"},{"pos":[1110,1147],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Passing parameters by value<ept id=\"p1\">](#byval)</ept>","source":"[Passing parameters by value](#byval)"},{"pos":[1152,1193],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Passing parameters by reference<ept id=\"p1\">](#byref)</ept>","source":"[Passing parameters by reference](#byref)"},{"pos":[1198,1229],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Parameter arrays<ept id=\"p1\">](#paramarray)</ept>","source":"[Parameter arrays](#paramarray)"},{"pos":[1232,1278],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optional parameters and arguments<ept id=\"p1\">](#optional)</ept>","source":"[Optional parameters and arguments](#optional)"},{"pos":[1281,1305],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Return values<ept id=\"p1\">](#return)</ept>","source":"[Return values](#return)"},{"pos":[1308,1339],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extension methods<ept id=\"p1\">](#extension)</ept>","source":"[Extension methods](#extension)"},{"pos":[1342,1365],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Async Methods<ept id=\"p1\">](#async)</ept>","source":"[Async Methods](#async)"},{"pos":[1368,1402],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Expression-bodied members<ept id=\"p1\">](#expr)</ept>","source":"[Expression-bodied members](#expr)"},{"pos":[1405,1428],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Iterators<ept id=\"p1\">](#iterators)</ept>","source":"[Iterators](#iterators)"},{"pos":[1459,1476],"content":"Method signatures","linkify":"Method signatures","nodes":[{"content":"Method signatures","pos":[0,17]}]},{"pos":[1481,1541],"content":"Methods are declared in a <ph id=\"ph1\">`class`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`struct`</ph> by specifying:","source":"Methods are declared in a `class` or `struct` by specifying:"},{"content":"An optional access level, such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`public`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`private`</ph>.","pos":[1545,1601],"source":"An optional access level, such as `public` or `private`."},{"content":"The default is <ph id=\"ph1\">`private`</ph>.","pos":[1602,1627],"source":" The default is `private`."},{"pos":[1630,1680],"content":"Optional modifiers such as <ph id=\"ph1\">`abstract`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`sealed`</ph>.","source":"Optional modifiers such as `abstract` or `sealed`."},{"pos":[1683,1734],"content":"The return value, or <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph> if the method has none.","source":"The return value, or `void` if the method has none."},{"content":"The method name.","pos":[1737,1753]},{"content":"Any method parameters.","pos":[1756,1778]},{"content":"Method parameters are enclosed in parentheses and are separated by commas.","pos":[1779,1853]},{"content":"Empty parentheses indicate that the method requires no parameters.","pos":[1854,1920]},{"content":"These parts together form the method signature.","pos":[1922,1969]},{"pos":[1973,2230],"content":"[!NOTE]\nA return type of a method is not part of the signature of the method for the purposes of method overloading. However, it is part of the signature of the method when determining the compatibility between a delegate and the method that it points to.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"A return type of a method is not part of the signature of the method for the purposes of method overloading. However, it is part of the signature of the method when determining the compatibility between a delegate and the method that it points to.","pos":[8,255],"nodes":[{"content":"A return type of a method is not part of the signature of the method for the purposes of method overloading.","pos":[0,108]},{"content":"However, it is part of the signature of the method when determining the compatibility between a delegate and the method that it points to.","pos":[109,247]}]}]},{"pos":[2232,2316],"content":"The following example defines a class named <ph id=\"ph1\">`Motorcycle`</ph> that contains five methods:","source":"The following example defines a class named `Motorcycle` that contains five methods:"},{"pos":[2318,2419],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#40<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#40)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#40](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#40)]"},{"content":"Note that the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Motorcycle`</ph> class includes an overloaded method, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Drive`</ph>.","pos":[2421,2493],"source":"Note that the `Motorcycle` class includes an overloaded method, `Drive`."},{"content":"Two methods have the same name, but must be differentiated by their parameter types.","pos":[2494,2578]},{"pos":[2609,2626],"content":"Method invocation","linkify":"Method invocation","nodes":[{"content":"Method invocation","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Methods can be either <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>instance<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>static<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.","pos":[2631,2676],"source":"Methods can be either *instance* or *static*."},{"content":"Invoking an instance method requires that you instantiate an object and call the method on that object; an instance method operates on that instance and its data.","pos":[2677,2839]},{"content":"You invoke a static method by referencing the name of the type to which the method belongs; static methods operate do not operate on instance data.","pos":[2840,2987]},{"content":"Attempting to call a static method through an object instance generates a compiler error.","pos":[2988,3077]},{"content":"Calling a method is like accessing a field.","pos":[3079,3122]},{"content":"After the object name (if you are calling an instance method) or the type name (if you are calling a <ph id=\"ph1\">`static`</ph> method), add a period, the name of the method, and parentheses.","pos":[3123,3296],"source":" After the object name (if you are calling an instance method) or the type name (if you are calling a `static` method), add a period, the name of the method, and parentheses."},{"content":"Arguments are listed within the parentheses, and are separated by commas.","pos":[3297,3370]},{"content":"The method definition specifies the names and types of any parameters that are required.","pos":[3372,3460]},{"content":"When a caller invokes the method, it provides concrete values, called arguments, for each parameter.","pos":[3461,3561]},{"content":"The arguments must be compatible with the parameter type, but the argument name, if one is used in the calling code, does not have to be the same as the parameter named defined in the method.","pos":[3562,3753]},{"content":"In the following example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Square`</ph> method includes a single parameter of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`int`</ph> named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>i<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[3754,3852],"source":" In the following example, the `Square` method includes a single parameter of type `int` named *i*."},{"content":"The first method call passes the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Square`</ph> method a variable of type <ph id=\"ph2\">`int`</ph> named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>num<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>; the second, a numeric constant; and the third, an expression.","pos":[3853,4001],"source":" The first method call passes the `Square` method a variable of type `int` named *num*; the second, a numeric constant; and the third, an expression."},{"pos":[4003,4103],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#74<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/params74.cs#74)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#74](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/params74.cs#74)]"},{"content":"The most common form of method invocation used positional arguments; it supplies arguments in the same order as method parameters.","pos":[4105,4235]},{"content":"The methods of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Motorcycle`</ph> class can therefore be called as in the following example.","pos":[4236,4326],"source":" The methods of the `Motorcycle` class can therefore be called as in the following example."},{"content":"The call to the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Drive`</ph> method, for example, includes two arguments that correspond to the two parameters in the method's syntax.","pos":[4327,4456],"source":" The call to the `Drive` method, for example, includes two arguments that correspond to the two parameters in the method's syntax."},{"content":"The first becomes the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`miles`</ph> parameter, the second the value of the <ph id=\"ph2\">`speed`</ph> parameter.","pos":[4457,4557],"source":" The first becomes the value of the `miles` parameter, the second the value of the `speed` parameter."},{"pos":[4559,4660],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#41<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#41)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#41](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/methods40.cs#41)]"},{"content":"You can also used <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>named arguments<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> instead of positional arguments when invoking a method.","pos":[4662,4753],"source":"You can also used *named arguments* instead of positional arguments when invoking a method."},{"content":"When using named arguments, you specify the parameter name followed by a colon (\":\") and the argument.","pos":[4754,4856]},{"content":"Arguments to the method can appear in any order, as long as all required arguments are present.","pos":[4857,4952]},{"content":"The following example uses named arguments to invoke the <ph id=\"ph1\">`TestMotorcycle.Drive`</ph> method.","pos":[4953,5040],"source":" The following example uses named arguments to invoke the `TestMotorcycle.Drive` method."},{"content":"In this example, the named arguments are passed in the opposite order from the method's parameter list.","pos":[5041,5144]},{"pos":[5146,5244],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#45<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named1.cs#45)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#45](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named1.cs#45)]"},{"content":"You can invoke a method using both positional arguments and named arguments.","pos":[5246,5322]},{"content":"However, a positional argument cannot follow a named argument.","pos":[5323,5385]},{"content":"The following example invokes the <ph id=\"ph1\">`TestMotorcycle.Drive`</ph> method from the previous example using one positional argument and one named argument.","pos":[5386,5529],"source":" The following example invokes the `TestMotorcycle.Drive` method from the previous example using one positional argument and one named argument."},{"pos":[5531,5629],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#46<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named2.cs#46)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#46](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/named2.cs#46)]"},{"pos":[5660,5692],"content":"Inherited and overridden methods","linkify":"Inherited and overridden methods","nodes":[{"content":"Inherited and overridden methods","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"In addition to the members that are explicitly defined in a type, a type inherits members defined in its base classes.","pos":[5697,5815]},{"content":"Since all types in the managed type system inherit directly or indirectly from the <ph id=\"ph1\">@System.Object</ph> class, all types inherit its members, such as <ph id=\"ph2\">@System.Object.Equals</ph>(System.Object), <ph id=\"ph3\">@System.Object.GetType</ph>, and <ph id=\"ph4\">@System.Object.ToString</ph>.","pos":[5816,6050],"source":" Since all types in the managed type system inherit directly or indirectly from the @System.Object class, all types inherit its members, such as @System.Object.Equals(System.Object), @System.Object.GetType, and @System.Object.ToString."},{"content":"The following example defines a <ph id=\"ph1\">`Person`</ph> class, instantiates two <ph id=\"ph2\">`Person`</ph> objects, and calls the <ph id=\"ph3\">`Person.Equals`</ph> method to determine whether the two objects are equal.","pos":[6051,6218],"source":" The following example defines a `Person` class, instantiates two `Person` objects, and calls the `Person.Equals` method to determine whether the two objects are equal."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Equals`</ph> method, however, is not defined in the <ph id=\"ph2\">`Person`</ph> class; it is inherited from <ph id=\"ph3\">@System.Object</ph>.","pos":[6219,6323],"source":" The `Equals` method, however, is not defined in the `Person` class; it is inherited from @System.Object."},{"pos":[6325,6429],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#104<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/inherited1.cs#104)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#104](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/inherited1.cs#104)]"},{"content":"Types can override inherited members by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`override`</ph> keyword and providing an implementation for the overridden method.","pos":[6431,6558],"source":"Types can override inherited members by using the `override` keyword and providing an implementation for the overridden method."},{"content":"The method signature must be the same as that of the overriden method.","pos":[6559,6629]},{"content":"The following example is like the previous one, except that it overrides the <ph id=\"ph1\">@Object.Equals</ph>(System.Object) method.","pos":[6630,6744],"source":" The following example is like the previous one, except that it overrides the @Object.Equals(System.Object) method."},{"content":"(It also overrides the <ph id=\"ph1\">@Object.GetHashCode</ph> method, since the two methods are intended to provide consistent results.)","pos":[6745,6862],"source":" (It also overrides the @Object.GetHashCode method, since the two methods are intended to provide consistent results.)"},{"pos":[6864,6969],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#105<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/overridden1.cs#105)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#105](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/overridden1.cs#105)]"},{"pos":[6997,7015],"content":"Passing parameters","linkify":"Passing parameters","nodes":[{"content":"Passing parameters","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Types in C# are either <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>value types<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>reference types<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.","pos":[7020,7078],"source":"Types in C# are either *value types* or *reference types*."},{"content":"For a list of built-in value types, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Types and variables<ept id=\"p1\">](./tour-of-csharp/types-and-variables.md)</ept>.","pos":[7079,7182],"source":" For a list of built-in value types, see [Types and variables](./tour-of-csharp/types-and-variables.md)."},{"content":"By default, both value types and reference types are passed to a method by value.","pos":[7183,7264]},{"pos":[7291,7318],"content":"Passing parameters by value","linkify":"Passing parameters by value","nodes":[{"content":"Passing parameters by value","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"When a value type is passed to a method by value, a copy of the object instead of the object itself is passed to the method.","pos":[7324,7448]},{"content":"Therefore, changes to the object in the called method have no effect on the original object when control returns to the caller.","pos":[7449,7576]},{"content":"The following example passes a value type to a method by value, and the called method attempts to change the value type's value.","pos":[7578,7706]},{"content":"It defines a variable of type <ph id=\"ph1\">`int`</ph>, which is a value type, initializes its value to 20, and passes it to a method named <ph id=\"ph2\">`ModifyValue`</ph> that changes the variable's value to 30.","pos":[7707,7882],"source":" It defines a variable of type `int`, which is a value type, initializes its value to 20, and passes it to a method named `ModifyValue` that changes the variable's value to 30."},{"content":"When the method returns, however, the variable's value remains unchanged.","pos":[7883,7956]},{"pos":[7958,8059],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#10<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue10.cs#10)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#10](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue10.cs#10)]"},{"content":"When an object of a reference type is passed to a method by value, a reference to the object is passed by value.","pos":[8061,8173]},{"content":"That is, the method receives not the object itself, but an argument that indicates the location of the object.","pos":[8174,8284]},{"content":"If you change a member of the object by using this reference, the change is reflected in the object when control returns to the calling method.","pos":[8285,8428]},{"content":"However, replacing the object passed to the method has no effect on the original object when control returns to the caller.","pos":[8429,8552]},{"content":"The following example defines a class (which is a reference type) named <ph id=\"ph1\">`SampleRefType`</ph>.","pos":[8554,8642],"source":"The following example defines a class (which is a reference type) named `SampleRefType`."},{"content":"It instantiates a <ph id=\"ph1\">`SampleRefType`</ph> object, assigns 44 to its <ph id=\"ph2\">`value`</ph> field, and passes the object to the <ph id=\"ph3\">`ModifyObject`</ph> method.","pos":[8643,8769],"source":" It instantiates a `SampleRefType` object, assigns 44 to its `value` field, and passes the object to the `ModifyObject` method."},{"content":"This example does essentially the same thing as the previous example -- it passes an argument by value to a method.","pos":[8770,8885]},{"content":"But because a reference type is used, the result is different.","pos":[8886,8948]},{"content":"The modification that is made in <ph id=\"ph1\">`ModifyObject`</ph> to the <ph id=\"ph2\">`obj.value`</ph> field also changes the <ph id=\"ph3\">`value`</ph> field of the argument, <ph id=\"ph4\">`rt`</ph>, in the <ph id=\"ph5\">`Main`</ph> method to 33, as the output from the example shows.","pos":[8949,9141],"source":" The modification that is made in `ModifyObject` to the `obj.value` field also changes the `value` field of the argument, `rt`, in the `Main` method to 33, as the output from the example shows."},{"pos":[9143,9244],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#42<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue42.cs#42)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#42](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byvalue42.cs#42)]"},{"pos":[9271,9302],"content":"Passing parameters by reference","linkify":"Passing parameters by reference","nodes":[{"content":"Passing parameters by reference","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"You pass a parameter by reference when you want to change the value of an argument in a method and want to refect that change when control returns to the calling method.","pos":[9308,9477]},{"content":"To pass a parameter by reference, you use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ref`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`out`</ph> keyword.","pos":[9478,9547],"source":" To pass a parameter by reference, you use the `ref` or `out` keyword."},{"content":"The following example is identical to the previous one, except the value is passed by reference to the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ModifyValue`</ph> method.","pos":[9549,9673],"source":"The following example is identical to the previous one, except the value is passed by reference to the `ModifyValue` method."},{"content":"When the value of the parameter is modified in the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ModifyValue`</ph> method, the change in value is reflected when control returns to the caller.","pos":[9674,9815],"source":" When the value of the parameter is modified in the `ModifyValue` method, the change in value is reflected when control returns to the caller."},{"pos":[9817,9919],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#106<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref106.cs#106)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref106.cs#106)]"},{"content":"A common pattern that uses by ref parameters involves swapping the values of variables.","pos":[9921,10008]},{"content":"You pass two variables to a method by reference, and the method swaps their contents.","pos":[10009,10094]},{"content":"The following example swaps integer values.","pos":[10095,10138]},{"pos":[10140,10241],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#106<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/swap107.cs#107)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/swap107.cs#107)]"},{"content":"Passing a reference-type parameter allows you to change the value of the reference itself, rather than the value of its individual elements or fields.","pos":[10243,10393]},{"pos":[10425,10441],"content":"Parameter arrays","linkify":"Parameter arrays","nodes":[{"content":"Parameter arrays","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"Sometimes, the requirement that you specify the exact number of arguments to your method is restrictive.","pos":[10447,10551]},{"content":"By using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`params`</ph> keyword to indicate that a parameter is a parameter array, you allow your method to be called with a variable number of arguments.","pos":[10552,10704],"source":" By using the `params` keyword to indicate that a parameter is a parameter array, you allow your method to be called with a variable number of arguments."},{"content":"The parameter tagged with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`params`</ph> keyword must must be an array type, and it must be the last parameter in the method's parameter list.","pos":[10705,10845],"source":" The parameter tagged with the `params` keyword must must be an array type, and it must be the last parameter in the method's parameter list."},{"content":"A caller can then invoke the method in either of three ways:","pos":[10847,10907]},{"content":"By passing an array of the appropriate type that contains the desired number of elements.","pos":[10911,11000]},{"content":"By passing a comma-separated list of individual arguments of the appropriate type to the method.","pos":[11003,11099]},{"content":"By not providing an argument to the parameter array.","pos":[11102,11154]},{"content":"The following example defines a method named <ph id=\"ph1\">`DoStringOperation`</ph> that performs the string operation specified by its first parameter, a <ph id=\"ph2\">`StringOperation`</ph> enumeration member.","pos":[11156,11329],"source":"The following example defines a method named `DoStringOperation` that performs the string operation specified by its first parameter, a `StringOperation` enumeration member."},{"content":"The strings upon which it is to perform the operation are defined by a parameter array.","pos":[11330,11417]},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Main`</ph> method illustrates all three ways of invoking the method.","pos":[11418,11486],"source":" The `Main` method illustrates all three ways of invoking the method."},{"content":"Note that the method tagged with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`params`</ph> keyword must be prepared to handle the case in which no argument is supplied for the parameter array, so that its value is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","pos":[11487,11663],"source":" Note that the method tagged with the `params` keyword must be prepared to handle the case in which no argument is supplied for the parameter array, so that its value is `null`."},{"pos":[11665,11767],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#106<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref108.cs#108)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#106](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/byref108.cs#108)]"},{"pos":[11796,11829],"content":"Optional parameters and arguments","linkify":"Optional parameters and arguments","nodes":[{"content":"Optional parameters and arguments","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"A method definition can specify that its parameters are required or that they are optional.","pos":[11834,11925]},{"content":"By default, parameters are required.","pos":[11926,11962]},{"content":"Optional parameters are specified by including the parameter's default value in the method definition.","pos":[11963,12065]},{"content":"When the method is called, if no argument is supplied for an optional parameter, the default value is used instead.","pos":[12066,12181]},{"content":"The parameter's default value must be assigned by one of the following kinds of expressions:","pos":[12183,12275]},{"content":"A constant, such as a literal string or number.","pos":[12279,12326]},{"content":"An expression of the form <ph id=\"ph1\">`new ValType`</ph>, where <ph id=\"ph2\">`ValType`</ph> is a value type.","pos":[12329,12402],"source":"An expression of the form `new ValType`, where `ValType` is a value type."},{"content":"Note that this invokes the value type's implicit default constructor, which is not an actual member of the type.","pos":[12403,12515]},{"pos":[12518,12596],"content":"An expression of the form <ph id=\"ph1\">`default(ValType)`</ph>, where <ph id=\"ph2\">`ValType`</ph> is a value type.","source":"An expression of the form `default(ValType)`, where `ValType` is a value type."},{"content":"If a method includes both required and optional parameters, optional parameters are defined at the end of the parameter list, after all required parameters.","pos":[12598,12754]},{"pos":[12756,12863],"content":"The following example defines a method, <ph id=\"ph1\">`ExampleMethod`</ph>, that has one required and two optional parameters.","source":"The following example defines a method, `ExampleMethod`, that has one required and two optional parameters."},{"pos":[12865,12966],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#21<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#21)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#21](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#21)]"},{"content":"If a method with multiple optional arguments is invoked using positional arguments, the caller must supply an argument for all optional parameters from the first one to the last one for which an argument is supplied.","pos":[12968,13184]},{"content":"In the case of the  <ph id=\"ph1\">`ExampleMethod`</ph> method, for example, if the caller supplies an argument for the <ph id=\"ph2\">`description`</ph> parameter, it must also supply one for the <ph id=\"ph3\">`optionalInt`</ph> parameter.","pos":[13185,13366],"source":" In the case of the  `ExampleMethod` method, for example, if the caller supplies an argument for the `description` parameter, it must also supply one for the `optionalInt` parameter."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`opt.ExampleMethod(2, 2, \"Addition of 2 and 2\");`</ph> is a valid method call; <ph id=\"ph2\">`opt.ExampleMethod(2, , \"Addition of 2 and 0);`</ph> generates an \"Argument missing\" compiler error.","pos":[13367,13536],"source":"`opt.ExampleMethod(2, 2, \"Addition of 2 and 2\");` is a valid method call; `opt.ExampleMethod(2, , \"Addition of 2 and 0);` generates an \"Argument missing\" compiler error."},{"content":"If a method is called using named arguments or a combination of positional and named arguments, the caller can omit any arguments that follow the last positional argument in the method call.","pos":[13538,13728]},{"content":"The following example calls the <ph id=\"ph1\">`ExampleMethod`</ph> method three times.","pos":[13730,13797],"source":"The following example calls the `ExampleMethod` method three times."},{"content":"The first two method calls use positional arguments.","pos":[13799,13851]},{"content":"The first omits both optional arguments, while the second omits the last argument.","pos":[13852,13934]},{"content":"The third method call supplies a positional argument for the required parameter, but uses a named argument to supply a value to the <ph id=\"ph1\">`description`</ph> parameter while omitting the <ph id=\"ph2\">`optionalInt`</ph> argument.","pos":[13935,14133],"source":" The third method call supplies a positional argument for the required parameter, but uses a named argument to supply a value to the `description` parameter while omitting the `optionalInt` argument."},{"pos":[14135,14236],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#22<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#22)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#22](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/optional1.cs#22)]"},{"pos":[14238,14420],"content":"The use of optional parameters affects <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>overload resolution<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, or the way in which the C# compiler determines which particular overload should be invoked by a method call, as follows:","source":"The use of optional parameters affects *overload resolution*, or the way in which the C# compiler determines which particular overload should be invoked by a method call, as follows:"},{"content":"A method, indexer, or constructor is a candidate for execution if each of its parameters either is optional or corresponds, by name or by position, to a single argument in the calling statement, and that argument can be converted to the type of the parameter.","pos":[14424,14683]},{"content":"If more than one candidate is found, overload resolution rules for preferred conversions are applied to the arguments that are explicitly specified.","pos":[14686,14834]},{"content":"Omitted arguments for optional parameters are ignored.","pos":[14835,14889]},{"content":"If two candidates are judged to be equally good, preference goes to a candidate that does not have optional parameters for which arguments were omitted in the call.","pos":[14892,15056]},{"content":"This is a consequence of a general preference in overload resolution for candidates that have fewer parameters.","pos":[15057,15168]},{"pos":[15197,15210],"content":"Return values","linkify":"Return values","nodes":[{"content":"Return values","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Methods can return a value to the caller.","pos":[15215,15256]},{"content":"If the return type (the type listed before the method name) is not <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph>, the method can return the value by using the <ph id=\"ph2\">`return`</ph> keyword.","pos":[15257,15394],"source":" If the return type (the type listed before the method name) is not `void`, the method can return the value by using the `return` keyword."},{"content":"A statement with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`return`</ph> keyword followed by a variable, constant, or expression that matches the return type will return that value to the method caller.","pos":[15395,15554],"source":" A statement with the `return` keyword followed by a variable, constant, or expression that matches the return type will return that value to the method caller."},{"content":"Methods with a non-void return type are required to use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`return`</ph> keyword to return a value.","pos":[15555,15650],"source":" Methods with a non-void return type are required to use the `return` keyword to return a value."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`return`</ph> keyword also stops the execution of the method.","pos":[15651,15711],"source":" The `return` keyword also stops the execution of the method."},{"content":"If the return type is <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph>, a <ph id=\"ph2\">`return`</ph> statement without a value is still useful to stop the execution of the method.","pos":[15713,15832],"source":"If the return type is `void`, a `return` statement without a value is still useful to stop the execution of the method."},{"content":"Without the <ph id=\"ph1\">`return`</ph> keyword, the method will stop executing when it reaches the end of the code block.","pos":[15833,15936],"source":" Without the `return` keyword, the method will stop executing when it reaches the end of the code block."},{"pos":[15938,16013],"content":"For example, these two methods use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`return`</ph> keyword to return integers:","source":"For example, these two methods use the `return` keyword to return integers:"},{"pos":[16015,16115],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#44<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#44)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#44](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#44)]"},{"content":"To use a value returned from a method, the calling method can use the method call itself anywhere a value of the same type would be sufficient.","pos":[16117,16260]},{"content":"You can also assign the return value to a variable.","pos":[16261,16312]},{"content":"For example, the following two code examples accomplish the same goal:","pos":[16313,16383]},{"pos":[16385,16485],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#45<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#45)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#45](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#45)]"},{"pos":[16487,16587],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#46<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#46)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#46](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/return44.cs#46)]"},{"content":"Using a local variable, in this case, <ph id=\"ph1\">`result`</ph>, to store a value is optional.","pos":[16589,16666],"source":"Using a local variable, in this case, `result`, to store a value is optional."},{"content":"It may help the readability of the code, or it may be necessary if you need to store the original value of the argument for the entire scope of the method.","pos":[16667,16822]},{"content":"Sometimes, you want your method to return more than a single value.","pos":[16824,16891]},{"content":"Starting with C# 7.0, you can do this easily by using <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>tuple types<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>tuple literals<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.","pos":[16892,16981],"source":" Starting with C# 7.0, you can do this easily by using *tuple types* and *tuple literals*."},{"content":"The tuple type defines the data types of the tuple's elements.","pos":[16982,17044]},{"content":"Tuple literals provide the actual values of the returned tuple.","pos":[17045,17108]},{"content":"In teh following example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`(string, string, string, int)`</ph> defines the tuple type that is returned by the <ph id=\"ph2\">`GetPersonalInfo`</ph> method.","pos":[17109,17239],"source":" In teh following example, `(string, string, string, int)` defines the tuple type that is returned by the `GetPersonalInfo` method."},{"content":"The expression <ph id=\"ph1\">`(per.FirstName, per.MiddleName, per.LastName, per.Age)`</ph> is the tuple literal; the method returns the first, middle, and last name, along with the age, of a <ph id=\"ph2\">`PersonInfo`</ph> object.","pos":[17240,17432],"source":" The expression `(per.FirstName, per.MiddleName, per.LastName, per.Age)` is the tuple literal; the method returns the first, middle, and last name, along with the age, of a `PersonInfo` object."},{"content":"The caller can then consume the returned tuple with code like the following:","pos":[17691,17767]},{"content":"Names can also be assigned to the tuple elements in the tuple type definition.","pos":[17923,18001]},{"content":"The following example shows an alternate version of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetPersonalInfo`</ph> method that uses named elements:","pos":[18002,18108],"source":" The following example shows an alternate version of the `GetPersonalInfo` method that uses named elements:"},{"pos":[18389,18469],"content":"The previous call to the <ph id=\"ph1\">`GetPersonInfo`</ph> method can then be modified as follows:","source":"The previous call to the `GetPersonInfo` method can then be modified as follows:"},{"content":"If a method is passed an array as an argument and modifies the value of individual elements, it is not necessary for the method to return the array, although you may choose to do so for good style or functional flow of values.","pos":[18624,18850]},{"content":"This is because C# passes all reference types by value, and the value of an array reference is the pointer to the array.","pos":[18852,18972]},{"content":"In the following example, changes to the contents of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`values`</ph> array that are made in the <ph id=\"ph2\">`DoubleValues`</ph> method are observable by any code that has a reference to the array.","pos":[18973,19149],"source":" In the following example, changes to the contents of the `values` array that are made in the `DoubleValues` method are observable by any code that has a reference to the array."},{"pos":[19151,19257],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#101<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/returnarray1.cs#101)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#101](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/returnarray1.cs#101)]"},{"pos":[19285,19302],"content":"Extension methods","linkify":"Extension methods","nodes":[{"content":"Extension methods","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Ordinarily, there are two ways to add a method to an existing type:","pos":[19307,19374]},{"content":"Modify the source code for that type.","pos":[19378,19415]},{"content":"You cannot do this, of course, if you do not own the type's source code.","pos":[19416,19488]},{"content":"And this becomes a breaking change if you also add any private data fields to support the method.","pos":[19489,19586]},{"content":"Define the new method in a derived class.","pos":[19589,19630]},{"content":"A method cannot be added in this way using inheritance for other types, such as structures and enumerations.","pos":[19631,19739]},{"content":"Nor can it be used to \"add\" a method to a sealed class.","pos":[19740,19795]},{"content":"Extension methods let you \"add\" a method to an existing type without modifying the type itself or implementing the new method in an inherited type.","pos":[19797,19944]},{"content":"The extension method also does not have to reside in the same assembly as the type it extends.","pos":[19945,20039]},{"content":"You call an extension method as if it were a defined member of a type.","pos":[20040,20110]},{"pos":[20112,20208],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extension Methods<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb383977.aspx)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Extension Methods](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/bb383977.aspx)."},{"pos":[20234,20247],"content":"Async Methods","linkify":"Async Methods","nodes":[{"content":"Async Methods","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"By using the async feature, you can invoke asynchronous methods without using explicit callbacks or manually splitting your code across multiple methods or lambda expressions.","pos":[20252,20427]},{"content":"If you mark a method with the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>async<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156513.aspx)</ept> modifier, you can use the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>await<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156528.aspx)</ept> operator in the method.","pos":[20429,20624],"source":"If you mark a method with the [async](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156513.aspx) modifier, you can use the [await](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh156528.aspx) operator in the method."},{"content":"When control reaches an <ph id=\"ph1\">`await`</ph> expression in the async method, control returns to the caller if the awaited task is not completed, and progress in the method with the <ph id=\"ph2\">`await`</ph> keyword is suspended until the awaited task completes.","pos":[20625,20855],"source":" When control reaches an `await` expression in the async method, control returns to the caller if the awaited task is not completed, and progress in the method with the `await` keyword is suspended until the awaited task completes."},{"content":"When the task is complete, execution can resume in the method.","pos":[20856,20918]},{"pos":[20922,21111],"content":"[!NOTE]\nAn async method returns to the caller when either it encounters the first awaited object that’s not yet complete or it gets to the end of the async method, whichever occurs first.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"An async method returns to the caller when either it encounters the first awaited object that’s not yet complete or it gets to the end of the async method, whichever occurs first.","pos":[8,187]}]},{"content":"An async method can have a return type of <ph id=\"ph1\">@System.Threading.Tasks.Task</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;TResult&gt;</ph>, <ph id=\"ph3\">@System.Threading.Tasks.Task</ph>, or <ph id=\"ph4\">`void`</ph>.","pos":[21113,21234],"source":"An async method can have a return type of @System.Threading.Tasks.Task<TResult>, @System.Threading.Tasks.Task, or `void`."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph> return type is used primarily to define event handlers, where a <ph id=\"ph2\">`void`</ph> return type is required.","pos":[21235,21341],"source":" The `void` return type is used primarily to define event handlers, where a `void` return type is required."},{"content":"An async method that returns <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph> can't be awaited, and the caller of a void-returning method can't catch exceptions that the method throws.","pos":[21342,21484],"source":" An async method that returns `void` can't be awaited, and the caller of a void-returning method can't catch exceptions that the method throws."},{"content":"C# 7, when it is released, will ease this restriction to allow an async method <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>to return any task-like type<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/ljw1004/roslyn/blob/features/async-return/docs/specs/feature%20-%20arbitrary%20async%20returns.md)</ept>.","pos":[21485,21713],"source":" C# 7, when it is released, will ease this restriction to allow an async method [to return any task-like type](https://github.com/ljw1004/roslyn/blob/features/async-return/docs/specs/feature%20-%20arbitrary%20async%20returns.md)."},{"content":"In the following example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`DelayAsync`</ph> is an async method that has a return statement that returns an integer.","pos":[21715,21825],"source":"In the following example, `DelayAsync` is an async method that has a return statement that returns an integer."},{"content":"Because it is an async method, its method declaration must have a return type of <ph id=\"ph1\">`Task&lt;int&gt;`</ph>.","pos":[21826,21919],"source":" Because it is an async method, its method declaration must have a return type of `Task<int>`."},{"content":"Because the return type is <ph id=\"ph1\">`Task&lt;int&gt;`</ph>, the evaluation of the <ph id=\"ph2\">`await`</ph> expression in <ph id=\"ph3\">`DoSomethingAsync`</ph> produces an integer, as the following <ph id=\"ph4\">`int result = await delayTask`</ph> statement demonstrates.","pos":[21920,22115],"source":" Because the return type is `Task<int>`, the evaluation of the `await` expression in `DoSomethingAsync` produces an integer, as the following `int result = await delayTask` statement demonstrates."},{"pos":[22117,22217],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[!code-csharp</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>csSnippets.Methods#102<ept id=\"p2\">](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/async1.cs#102)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">]</ept>","source":"[!code-csharp[csSnippets.Methods#102](../../samples/snippets/csharp/concepts/methods/async1.cs#102)]"},{"pos":[22219,22430],"content":"An async method can't declare any <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ref<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>out<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx)</ept> parameters, but it can call methods that have such parameters.","source":"An async method can't declare any [ref](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx) or [out](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx) parameters, but it can call methods that have such parameters."},{"pos":[22433,22737],"content":"For more information about async methods, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Asynchronous Programming with Async and Await<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674882.aspx)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Control Flow in Async Programs<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674892.aspx)</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Async Return Types<ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674893.aspx)</ept>.","source":"For more information about async methods, see [Asynchronous Programming with Async and Await](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674882.aspx), [Control Flow in Async Programs](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674892.aspx), and [Async Return Types](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt674893.aspx)."},{"pos":[22762,22787],"content":"Expression-bodied members","linkify":"Expression-bodied members","nodes":[{"content":"Expression-bodied members","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"It is common to have method definitions that simply return immediately with the result of an expression, or that have a single statement as the body of the method.","pos":[22792,22955]},{"content":"There is a syntax shortcut for defining such methods using <ph id=\"ph1\">`=&gt;`</ph>:","pos":[22957,23021],"source":"  There is a syntax shortcut for defining such methods using `=>`:"},{"content":"If the method returns <ph id=\"ph1\">`void`</ph> or is an async method, the body of the method must be a statement expression (same as with lambdas).","pos":[23390,23519],"source":"If the method returns `void` or is an async method, the body of the method must be a statement expression (same as with lambdas)."},{"content":"For properties and indexers, they must be read-only, and you do not use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`get`</ph> accessor keyword.","pos":[23521,23620],"source":"  For properties and indexers, they must be read-only, and you do not use the `get` accessor keyword."},{"pos":[23650,23659],"content":"Iterators","linkify":"Iterators","nodes":[{"content":"Iterators","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"An iterator performs a custom iteration over a collection, such as a list or an array.","pos":[23664,23750]},{"content":"An iterator uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>yield return<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/9k7k7cf0.aspx)</ept> statement to return each element one at a time.","pos":[23751,23884],"source":" An iterator uses the [yield return](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/9k7k7cf0.aspx) statement to return each element one at a time."},{"content":"When a <ph id=\"ph1\">`yield return`</ph> statement is reached, the current location is remembered so that the caller can request the next element in the sequence.","pos":[23885,24028],"source":" When a `yield return` statement is reached, the current location is remembered so that the caller can request the next element in the sequence."},{"content":"The return type of an iterator can be <ph id=\"ph1\">@System.Collections.IEnumerable</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">@System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable</ph>%601, <ph id=\"ph3\">@System.Collections.IEnumerator</ph>, or <ph id=\"ph4\">@System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerator</ph>%601.","pos":[24030,24226],"source":"The return type of an iterator can be @System.Collections.IEnumerable, @System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerable%601, @System.Collections.IEnumerator, or @System.Collections.Generic.IEnumerator%601."},{"pos":[24228,24316],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Iterators<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt639331.aspx)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Iterators](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt639331.aspx)."},{"pos":[24321,24329],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[24334,24898],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Access Modifiers<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/wxh6fsc7.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Static Classes and Static Class Members<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/79b3xss3.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph2\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Inheritance<ept id=\"p3\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173149.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph3\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Abstract and Sealed Classes and Class Members<ept id=\"p4\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173150.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph4\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p5\">[</bpt>params<ept id=\"p5\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/w5zay9db.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph5\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p6\">[</bpt>out<ept id=\"p6\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph6\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p7\">[</bpt>ref<ept id=\"p7\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx)</ept><ph id=\"ph7\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p8\">[</bpt>Passing Parameters<ept id=\"p8\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/0f66670z.aspx)</ept>","source":"[Access Modifiers](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/wxh6fsc7.aspx)\n[Static Classes and Static Class Members](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/79b3xss3.aspx)\n[Inheritance](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173149.aspx)\n[Abstract and Sealed Classes and Class Members](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms173150.aspx)\n[params](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/w5zay9db.aspx)\n[out](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/t3c3bfhx.aspx)\n[ref](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/14akc2c7.aspx)\n[Passing Parameters](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/0f66670z.aspx)"}]}