{"content":"---\ntitle: \"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions\"\nms.date: \"10/22/2008\"\nms.technology: dotnet-standard\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"abstractions [.NET Framework]\"\n  - \"base classes, abstractions\"\nms.assetid: 37a2d9a4-9721-482a-a40f-eee2c1d97875\nauthor: \"KrzysztofCwalina\"\n---\n# Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions\nStrictly speaking, a class becomes a base class when another class is derived from it. For the purpose of this section, however, a base class is a class designed mainly to provide a common abstraction or for other classes to reuse some default implementation though inheritance. Base classes usually sit in the middle of inheritance hierarchies, between an abstraction at the root of a hierarchy and several custom implementations at the bottom.  \n  \n They serve as implementation helpers for implementing abstractions. For example, one of the Framework’s abstractions for ordered collections of items is the <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601> interface. Implementing <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601> is not trivial, and therefore the Framework provides several base classes, such as <xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.Collection%601> and <xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.KeyedCollection%602>, which serve as helpers for implementing custom collections.  \n  \n Base classes are usually not suited to serve as abstractions by themselves, because they tend to contain too much implementation. For example, the `Collection<T>` base class contains lots of implementation related to the fact that it implements the nongeneric `IList` interface (to integrate better with nongeneric collections) and to the fact that it is a collection of items stored in memory in one of its fields.  \n  \n As previously discussed, base classes can provide invaluable help for users who need to implement abstractions, but at the same time they can be a significant liability. They add surface area and increase the depth of inheritance hierarchies and so conceptually complicate the framework. Therefore, base classes should be used only if they provide significant value to the users of the framework. They should be avoided if they provide value only to the implementers of the framework, in which case delegation to an internal implementation instead of inheritance from a base class should be strongly considered.  \n  \n **✓ CONSIDER** making base classes abstract even if they don’t contain any abstract members. This clearly communicates to the users that the class is designed solely to be inherited from.  \n  \n **✓ CONSIDER** placing base classes in a separate namespace from the mainline scenario types. By definition, base classes are intended for advanced extensibility scenarios and therefore are not interesting to the majority of users.  \n  \n **X AVOID** naming base classes with a \"Base\" suffix if the class is intended for use in public APIs.  \n  \n *Portions © 2005, 2009 Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.*  \n  \n *Reprinted by permission of Pearson Education, Inc. from [Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries, 2nd Edition](https://www.informit.com/store/framework-design-guidelines-conventions-idioms-and-9780321545619) by Krzysztof Cwalina and Brad Abrams, published Oct 22, 2008 by Addison-Wesley Professional as part of the Microsoft Windows Development Series.*  \n  \n## See also\n\n- [Framework Design Guidelines](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/index.md)\n- [Designing for Extensibility](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/designing-for-extensibility.md)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,275],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"title: \"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions\"\nms.date: \"10/22/2008\"\nms.technology: dotnet-standard\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"abstractions [.NET Framework]\"\n  - \"base classes, abstractions\"\nms.assetid: 37a2d9a4-9721-482a-a40f-eee2c1d97875\nauthor: \"KrzysztofCwalina\"","nodes":[{"content":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","nodes":[{"pos":[0,42],"content":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","nodes":[{"content":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","pos":[0,42]}]}],"path":["title"],"nosxs":false}],"yml":true},{"pos":[282,324],"content":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","linkify":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","nodes":[{"content":"Base Classes for Implementing Abstractions","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Strictly speaking, a class becomes a base class when another class is derived from it.","pos":[325,411]},{"content":"For the purpose of this section, however, a base class is a class designed mainly to provide a common abstraction or for other classes to reuse some default implementation though inheritance.","pos":[412,603]},{"content":"Base classes usually sit in the middle of inheritance hierarchies, between an abstraction at the root of a hierarchy and several custom implementations at the bottom.","pos":[604,770]},{"content":"They serve as implementation helpers for implementing abstractions.","pos":[777,844]},{"content":"For example, one of the Framework’s abstractions for ordered collections of items is the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601&gt;</ph> interface.","pos":[845,988],"source":" For example, one of the Framework’s abstractions for ordered collections of items is the <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601> interface."},{"content":"Implementing <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601&gt;</ph> is not trivial, and therefore the Framework provides several base classes, such as <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.Collection%601&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.KeyedCollection%602&gt;</ph>, which serve as helpers for implementing custom collections.","pos":[989,1304],"source":" Implementing <xref:System.Collections.Generic.IList%601> is not trivial, and therefore the Framework provides several base classes, such as <xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.Collection%601> and <xref:System.Collections.ObjectModel.KeyedCollection%602>, which serve as helpers for implementing custom collections."},{"content":"Base classes are usually not suited to serve as abstractions by themselves, because they tend to contain too much implementation.","pos":[1311,1440]},{"content":"For example, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Collection&lt;T&gt;`</ph> base class contains lots of implementation related to the fact that it implements the nongeneric <ph id=\"ph2\">`IList`</ph> interface (to integrate better with nongeneric collections) and to the fact that it is a collection of items stored in memory in one of its fields.","pos":[1441,1726],"source":" For example, the `Collection<T>` base class contains lots of implementation related to the fact that it implements the nongeneric `IList` interface (to integrate better with nongeneric collections) and to the fact that it is a collection of items stored in memory in one of its fields."},{"content":"As previously discussed, base classes can provide invaluable help for users who need to implement abstractions, but at the same time they can be a significant liability.","pos":[1733,1902]},{"content":"They add surface area and increase the depth of inheritance hierarchies and so conceptually complicate the framework.","pos":[1903,2020]},{"content":"Therefore, base classes should be used only if they provide significant value to the users of the framework.","pos":[2021,2129]},{"content":"They should be avoided if they provide value only to the implementers of the framework, in which case delegation to an internal implementation instead of inheritance from a base class should be strongly considered.","pos":[2130,2344]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓ CONSIDER<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> making base classes abstract even if they don’t contain any abstract members.","pos":[2351,2443],"source":"**✓ CONSIDER** making base classes abstract even if they don’t contain any abstract members."},{"content":"This clearly communicates to the users that the class is designed solely to be inherited from.","pos":[2444,2538]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓ CONSIDER<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> placing base classes in a separate namespace from the mainline scenario types.","pos":[2545,2638],"source":"**✓ CONSIDER** placing base classes in a separate namespace from the mainline scenario types."},{"content":"By definition, base classes are intended for advanced extensibility scenarios and therefore are not interesting to the majority of users.","pos":[2639,2776]},{"pos":[2783,2884],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>X AVOID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> naming base classes with a \"Base\" suffix if the class is intended for use in public APIs.","source":"**X AVOID** naming base classes with a \"Base\" suffix if the class is intended for use in public APIs."},{"pos":[2891,2958],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Portions © 2005, 2009 Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>","source":"*Portions © 2005, 2009 Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.*"},{"pos":[2965,3370],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Reprinted by permission of Pearson Education, Inc. from <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries, 2nd Edition<ept id=\"p2\">](https://www.informit.com/store/framework-design-guidelines-conventions-idioms-and-9780321545619)</ept> by Krzysztof Cwalina and Brad Abrams, published Oct 22, 2008 by Addison-Wesley Professional as part of the Microsoft Windows Development Series.<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>","source":"*Reprinted by permission of Pearson Education, Inc. from [Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries, 2nd Edition](https://www.informit.com/store/framework-design-guidelines-conventions-idioms-and-9780321545619) by Krzysztof Cwalina and Brad Abrams, published Oct 22, 2008 by Addison-Wesley Professional as part of the Microsoft Windows Development Series.*"},{"pos":[3379,3387],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[3391,3471],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Framework Design Guidelines<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/index.md)</ept>","source":"[Framework Design Guidelines](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/index.md)"},{"pos":[3474,3576],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Designing for Extensibility<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/designing-for-extensibility.md)</ept>","source":"[Designing for Extensibility](../../../docs/standard/design-guidelines/designing-for-extensibility.md)"}]}